[
{"id": "44464", "question": "How can you use your vehicle’s engine as a brake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-use-your-vehicles-engine-as-a-brake-3/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["By selecting reverse gear", "By changing to a higher gear", "By selecting neutral gear", "By changing to a lower gear"], "answer": "By changing to a lower gear"},
{"id": "44460", "question": "How can you reduce the risk of your vehicle being broken into at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-reduce-the-risk-of-your-vehicle-being-broken-into-at-night/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Leave it in a well-lit area", "Park in a quiet side road", "Park in a poorly lit area", "Don't engage the steering lock"], "answer": "Leave it in a well-lit area"},
{"id": "44087", "question": "How can you reduce the environmental harm caused by your motor vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-reduce-the-environmental-harm-caused-by-your-motor-vehicle-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Drive faster than normal", "Keep engine revs low", "Only use it for short journeys", "Don't service it"], "answer": "Keep engine revs low"},
{"id": "44396", "question": "How can you reduce the damage your vehicle causes to the environment?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-reduce-the-damage-your-vehicle-causes-to-the-environment-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Anticipate well ahead", "Use busy routes", "Brake heavily", "Use narrow side streets"], "answer": "Anticipate well ahead"},
{"id": "44457", "question": "How can you reduce the chances of your car being broken into when leaving it unattended?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-reduce-the-chances-of-your-car-being-broken-into-when-leaving-it-unattended-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Take all valuables with you", "Park near a fire station", "Place any valuables on the floor", "Park near a taxi rank"], "answer": "Take all valuables with you"},
{"id": "44148", "question": "How can you plan your route before starting a long journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-plan-your-route-before-starting-a-long-journey-4/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Consult a travel agent", "Use a route planner on the internet", "Check your vehicle handbook", "Ask your local garage"], "answer": "Use a route planner on the internet"},
{"id": "44506", "question": "How can you make sure that a satellite navigation (satnav) system doesn’t distract you when you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-make-sure-that-a-satellite-navigation-satnav-system-doesnt-distract-you-when-youre-driving/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Choose a voice that you find calming", "Set it before starting your journey", "Turn it off while you're driving in built-up areas", "Only set the destination when you're lost"], "answer": "Set it before starting your journey"},
{"id": "43738", "question": "How can you identify traffic signs that give orders?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-identify-traffic-signs-that-give-orders-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["They're triangular with a blue border", "They're rectangular with a yellow border", "They're square with a brown border", "They're circular with a red border"], "answer": "They're circular with a red border"},
{"id": "44458", "question": "How can you help to prevent your car radio being stolen?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-help-to-prevent-your-car-radio-being-stolen-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Leave the radio turned on", "Park in an unlit area", "Park near a busy junction", "Install a security-coded radio"], "answer": "Install a security-coded radio"},
{"id": "44258", "question": "How can you avoid wheelspin when you’re driving on an icy road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-avoid-wheelspin-when-youre-driving-on-an-icy-road-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Drive in a low gear at all times", "Brake gently and repeatedly", "Use the parking brake if the wheels start to slip", "Drive at a slow speed in the highest gear possible"], "answer": "Drive at a slow speed in the highest gear possible"},
{"id": "44343", "question": "How can you avoid wasting fuel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-avoid-wasting-fuel-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["By revving the engine in the lower gears", "By having your vehicle serviced regularly", "By keeping an empty roof rack on your vehicle", "By driving at higher speeds where possible"], "answer": "By having your vehicle serviced regularly"},
{"id": "44503", "question": "How can driving in a fuel-efficient manner help protect the environment?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-driving-in-a-fuel-efficient-manner-help-protect-the-environment/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Through increased fuel bills", "Through the legal enforcement of speed regulations", "By increasing the number of cars on the road", "By reducing exhaust emissions"], "answer": "By reducing exhaust emissions"},
{"id": "44342", "question": "How can drivers help the environment?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-drivers-help-the-environment-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["By accelerating harshly", "By using leaded fuel", "By driving faster", "By accelerating gently"], "answer": "By accelerating gently"},
{"id": "44208", "question": "How can drinking alcohol affect your ability to drive?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-drinking-alcohol-affect-your-ability-to-drive/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Your ability to judge speed will be reduced", "Your reactions will be faster", "Your confidence will be reduced", "Your awareness of danger will be improved"], "answer": "Your ability to judge speed will be reduced"},
{"id": "43998", "question": "For how long is an MOT certificate normally valid?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/for-how-long-is-an-mot-certificate-normally-valid-4/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["30,000 miles", "10,000 miles", "Three years after the date it was issued", "One year after the date it was issued"], "answer": "One year after the date it was issued"},
{"id": "44141", "question": "For how long is a Statutory Off-Road Notification (SORN) valid?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/for-how-long-is-a-statutory-off-road-notification-sorn-valid-5/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Until the vehicle is repaired or modified", "Until the vehicle is taxed, sold or scrapped", "Until the vehicle is insured and MOT'd", "Until the vehicle is used on the road"], "answer": "Until the vehicle is taxed, sold or scrapped"},
{"id": "43732", "question": "When may you enter a box junction?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2281.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-enter-a-box-junction/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When signalled by another road user", "When there are fewer than two vehicles ahead", "When traffic signs direct you", "When your exit road is clear"], "answer": "When your exit road is clear"},
{"id": "44320", "question": "When may you drive without wearing your seat belt?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-drive-without-wearing-your-seat-belt-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When you're driving slowly in queuing traffic", "When you're testing your brakes", "When you're carrying out a manoeuvre that includes reversing", "When you're moving off on a hill"], "answer": "When you're carrying out a manoeuvre that includes reversing"},
{"id": "44311", "question": "When may you drive over a pavement?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-drive-over-a-pavement/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["To gain access to a property", "To overtake slow-moving traffic", "When the pavement is very wide", "If there are no pedestrians nearby"], "answer": "To gain access to a property"},
{"id": "44426", "question": "When may you drive a car in this bus lane?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1581.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-drive-a-car-in-this-bus-lane/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Outside its hours of operation", "To overtake slow-moving traffic", "You may not use it at any time", "To get to the front of a traffic queue"], "answer": "Outside its hours of operation"},
{"id": "43978", "question": "When may you cross a double solid white line in the middle of the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2396.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-cross-a-double-solid-white-line-in-the-middle-of-the-road-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["To pass a road maintenance vehicle travelling at 10 mph or less", "To pass a car signalling to turn left ahead", "To pass traffic that's queuing back at a junction", "To pass a vehicle that's towing a trailer"], "answer": "To pass a road maintenance vehicle travelling at 10 mph or less"},
{"id": "44537", "question": "When may front fog lights be used?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BB1325.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-front-fog-lights-be-used-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["When visibility is seriously reduced", "When they aren't as bright as the headlights", "When they're fitted above the bumper", "When an audible warning device is used"], "answer": "When visibility is seriously reduced"},
{"id": "44518", "question": "When may a passenger travel in a car without wearing a seat belt?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-a-passenger-travel-in-a-car-without-wearing-a-seat-belt/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["When they're under 1.5 metres (5 feet) in height", "When they're sitting in the rear seat", "When they're under 14 years old", "When they're exempt for medical reasons"], "answer": "When they're exempt for medical reasons"},
{"id": "44510", "question": "When is fuel consumption at its highest?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-is-fuel-consumption-at-its-highest/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["When you're accelerating", "When you're coasting", "When you're turning sharply", "When you're braking"], "answer": "When you're accelerating"},
{"id": "44420", "question": "When do windscreen pillars cause a serious obstruction to your view?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-do-windscreen-pillars-cause-a-serious-obstruction-to-your-view-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["When you're approaching bends and junctions", "When you're driving on a dual carriageway", "When you're driving on a motorway", "When you're approaching a one-way street"], "answer": "When you're approaching bends and junctions"},
{"id": "44434", "question": "When could the cost of your insurance be reduced?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-could-the-cost-of-your-insurance-be-reduced/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When you don't wear glasses", "When you're under 25 years old", "When you pass the driving test first time", "When you complete the Pass Plus scheme"], "answer": "When you complete the Pass Plus scheme"},
{"id": "43654", "question": "When are you not allowed to sound your vehicle’s horn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-are-you-not-allowed-to-sound-your-vehicles-horn/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Between 11.30 pm and 7.00 am in a built-up area", "Between 11.30 pm and 6.00 am on any road", "Between 10.00 pm and 6.00 am in a built-up area", "At any time in a built-up area"], "answer": "Between 11.30 pm and 7.00 am in a built-up area"},
{"id": "44044", "question": "When are you allowed to use hazard warning lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-are-you-allowed-to-use-hazard-warning-lights-4/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["When stopped and temporarily obstructing traffic", "When travelling slowly because you're lost", "When travelling during darkness without headlights", "When parked on double yellow lines to visit a shop"], "answer": "When stopped and temporarily obstructing traffic"},
{"id": "44121", "question": "When are you allowed to stop on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-are-you-allowed-to-stop-on-a-motorway-4/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When you need to walk and get fresh air", "When you need to use a mobile telephone", "When you're signalled to do so by traffic signals", "When you wish to pick up hitchhikers"], "answer": "When you're signalled to do so by traffic signals"},
{"id": "44529", "question": "When are you allowed to park in a parking bay for disabled drivers?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-are-you-allowed-to-park-in-a-parking-bay-for-disabled-drivers/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When you have an adapted vehicle", "When you have a wheelchair", "When you have a Blue Badge", "When you have an advanced driver certificate"], "answer": "When you have a Blue Badge"},
{"id": "44306", "question": "What’s the speed limit for a car towing a trailer on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-speed-limit-for-a-car-towing-a-trailer-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["60 mph", "70 mph", "40 mph", "50 mph"], "answer": "60 mph"},
{"id": "44313", "question": "What’s the speed limit for a car towing a caravan on a dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-speed-limit-for-a-car-towing-a-caravan-on-a-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["70 mph", "60 mph", "40 mph", "50 mph"], "answer": "60 mph"},
{"id": "44140", "question": "You’ve stopped at a railway level crossing. What should you do if the red lights continue to flash after a train has gone by?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-stopped-at-a-railway-level-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-the-red-lights-continue-to-flash-after-a-train-has-gone-by/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Wait", "Phone the signal operator", "Proceed with caution", "Alert drivers behind you"], "answer": "Wait"},
{"id": "44293", "question": "You’ve stopped at a pelican crossing. What should you do if a disabled person is crossing slowly in front of you and the lights change to green?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-stopped-at-a-pelican-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-a-disabled-person-is-crossing-slowly-in-front-of-you-and-the-lights-change-to-green/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Drive in front of them", "Wait for them to finish crossing", "Sound your horn", "Edge forward slowly"], "answer": "Wait for them to finish crossing"},
{"id": "44074", "question": "You’ve just passed your first practical driving test. What will you have to do if you get six penalty points on your licence in the next two years?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-just-passed-your-first-practical-driving-test-what-will-you-have-to-do-if-you-get-six-penalty-points-on-your-licence-in-the-next-two-years/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Retake your theory and practical tests", "Retake only your theory test", "Retake only your practical test", "Reapply for your full licence immediately"], "answer": "Retake your theory and practical tests"},
{"id": "47578", "question": "You’ve just passed your driving test. What’s the maximum authorised mass (MAM) of any trailer that you can tow?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-just-passed-your-driving-test-whats-the-maximum-authorised-mass-mam-of-any-trailer-that-you-can-tow/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["5,500 kg", "6,500 kg", "4,500 kg", "3,500 kg"], "answer": "3,500 kg"},
{"id": "44233", "question": "You’ve just passed your driving test. How can you reduce your risk of being involved in a collision?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-just-passed-your-driving-test-how-can-you-reduce-your-risk-of-being-involved-in-a-collision/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["By always staying close to the vehicle in front", "By taking further training", "By staying in the left-hand lane on all roads", "By never going over 40 mph"], "answer": "By taking further training"},
{"id": "44056", "question": "You’ve just gone through flood water. What should you do to make sure your brakes are working properly?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-just-gone-through-flood-water-what-should-you-do-to-make-sure-your-brakes-are-working-properly/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Stop for at least an hour to allow them time to dry", "Avoid using the brakes at all for a few miles", "Accelerate and keep to a high speed for a short time", "Go slowly while gently applying the brakes"], "answer": "Go slowly while gently applying the brakes"},
{"id": "44384", "question": "You’ve just been overtaken by this motorcyclist. What should you do if the rider cuts in sharply?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1455.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-just-been-overtaken-by-this-motorcyclist-what-should-you-do-if-the-rider-cuts-in-sharply/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Flash your lights", "Keep a safe gap", "Brake firmly", "Sound the horn"], "answer": "Keep a safe gap"},
{"id": "44292", "question": "You’ve driven up to a pelican crossing. What must you do while the amber light is flashing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-driven-up-to-a-pelican-crossing-what-must-you-do-while-the-amber-light-is-flashing/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Signal the pedestrian to cross", "Always wait for the green light before proceeding", "Wait for the red-and-amber light before proceeding", "Give way to any pedestrians on the crossing"], "answer": "Give way to any pedestrians on the crossing"},
{"id": "44331", "question": "You’ve broken down on a two-way road. You have a warning triangle. At least how far from your vehicle should you place the warning triangle?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1252.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-broken-down-on-a-two-way-road-you-have-a-warning-triangle-at-least-how-far-from-your-vehicle-should-you-place-the-warning-triangle-2/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["45 metres (147 feet)", "25 metres (82 feet)", "100 metres (328 feet)", "5 metres (16 feet)"], "answer": "45 metres (147 feet)"},
{"id": "44360", "question": "You’ve been involved in an argument that’s made you feel angry. What should you do before starting your journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-been-involved-in-an-argument-thats-made-you-feel-angry-what-should-you-do-before-starting-your-journey/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Calm down", "Open a window", "Have an alcoholic drink", "Turn on your radio"], "answer": "Calm down"},
{"id": "44477", "question": "You’ve been driving in fog. What must you do when the visibility improves?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youve-been-driving-in-fog-what-must-you-do-when-the-visibility-improves/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Leave your fog lights switched on in case the fog returns", "Switch off your fog lights", "Keep your rear fog lights switched on", "Keep your front fog lights switched on"], "answer": "Switch off your fog lights"},
{"id": "43694", "question": "You’re waiting to turn right out of a minor road. It’s clear to the left but a lorry is coming from the right. Why should you wait, even if you have enough time to turn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-to-turn-right-out-of-a-minor-road-its-clear-to-the-left-but-a-lorry-is-coming-from-the-right-why-should-you-wait-even-if-you-have-enough-time-to-turn/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["The lorry could suddenly speed up", "The lorry might be slowing down", "The load on the lorry might be unstable", "Anything overtaking the lorry will be hidden from view"], "answer": "Anything overtaking the lorry will be hidden from view"},
{"id": "44161", "question": "You’re waiting to turn right at the end of a road. What should you do if your view is obstructed by parked vehicles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-to-turn-right-at-the-end-of-a-road-what-should-you-do-if-your-view-is-obstructed-by-parked-vehicles/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Move quickly to where you can see so you only block traffic from one direction", "Wait for a pedestrian to let you know when it's safe for you to emerge", "Turn your vehicle around immediately and find another junction to use", "Stop and then move forward slowly and carefully for a clear view"], "answer": "Stop and then move forward slowly and carefully for a clear view"},
{"id": "44448", "question": "You’re waiting to emerge from a junction. The windscreen pillar is restricting your view. What should you be particularly aware of?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1633.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-to-emerge-from-a-junction-the-windscreen-pillar-is-restricting-your-view-what-should-you-be-particularly-aware-of-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Coaches", "Lorries", "Buses", "Motorcyclists"], "answer": "Motorcyclists"},
{"id": "44507", "question": "You’re waiting to emerge at a junction. Your view is restricted by parked vehicles. What can help you to see traffic on the road you’re joining?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-to-emerge-at-a-junction-your-view-is-restricted-by-parked-vehicles-what-can-help-you-to-see-traffic-on-the-road-youre-joining-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Reflections of traffic in windows", "Making eye contact with other road users", "Looking for traffic behind you", "Checking for traffic in your interior mirror"], "answer": "Reflections of traffic in windows"},
{"id": "43687", "question": "You’re waiting to come out of a side road. Why should you look carefully for motorcycles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-to-come-out-of-a-side-road-why-should-you-look-carefully-for-motorcycles-4/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Motorcycles have right of way", "Motorcycles can easily be hidden behind obstructions", "Motorcycles are usually faster than cars", "Police patrols often use motorcycles"], "answer": "Motorcycles can easily be hidden behind obstructions"},
{"id": "44247", "question": "You’re waiting in a traffic queue at night. How can you avoid dazzling drivers behind you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-in-a-traffic-queue-at-night-how-can-you-avoid-dazzling-drivers-behind-you-2/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Keep your foot on the footbrake", "Use the parking brake and footbrake together", "Balance the clutch with the accelerator", "Use the parking brake and release the footbrake"], "answer": "Use the parking brake and release the footbrake"},
{"id": "44327", "question": "You’re waiting at a T-junction. What should you do if a vehicle is coming from the right, with its left indicator flashing?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1239.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-at-a-t-junction-what-should-you-do-if-a-vehicle-is-coming-from-the-right-with-its-left-indicator-flashing/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Move out slowly", "Wait until the vehicle starts to turn in", "Move out and accelerate hard", "Pull out before the vehicle reaches the junction"], "answer": "Wait until the vehicle starts to turn in"},
{"id": "43737", "question": "You’re waiting at a pelican crossing. What does it mean when the red light changes to flashing amber?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-at-a-pelican-crossing-what-does-it-mean-when-the-red-light-changes-to-flashing-amber-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Get ready and go when the continuous amber light shows", "Wait for the green light before moving off", "Give way to pedestrians on the crossing", "Move off immediately without any hesitation"], "answer": "Give way to pedestrians on the crossing"},
{"id": "44317", "question": "You’re waiting at a level crossing. What should you do if the red warning lights continue to flash after a train has passed by?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1226.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-at-a-level-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-the-red-warning-lights-continue-to-flash-after-a-train-has-passed-by/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Get out and investigate", "Drive across carefully", "Continue to wait", "Telephone the signal operator"], "answer": "Continue to wait"},
{"id": "44050", "question": "You’re waiting at a level crossing. What must you do if a train passes but the lights keep flashing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-waiting-at-a-level-crossing-what-must-you-do-if-a-train-passes-but-the-lights-keep-flashing/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Carry on waiting", "Park and investigate", "Phone the signal operator", "Edge over the stop line and look for trains"], "answer": "Carry on waiting"},
{"id": "44126", "question": "You’re turning right onto a dual carriageway. What should you do if the central reservation is too narrow to contain your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-turning-right-onto-a-dual-carriageway-what-should-you-do-if-the-central-reservation-is-too-narrow-to-contain-your-vehicle/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Stop in the first lane so that other vehicles give way", "Emerge slightly to show your intentions", "Proceed to the central reservation and wait", "Wait until the road is clear in both directions"], "answer": "Wait until the road is clear in both directions"},
{"id": "44447", "question": "You’re turning right onto a dual carriageway. What should you do before emerging?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BB1632.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-turning-right-onto-a-dual-carriageway-what-should-you-do-before-emerging-4/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Stop, apply the parking brake and then select a low gear", "Check that the central reservation is wide enough for your vehicle", "Make sure that you leave enough room for a vehicle behind", "Position your vehicle well to the left of the side road"], "answer": "Check that the central reservation is wide enough for your vehicle"},
{"id": "47542", "question": "You’re turning right from a main road into a side road. There’s no oncoming traffic. What should you do if pedestrians are standing on the pavement waiting to cross the side road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-turning-right-from-a-main-road-into-a-side-road-theres-no-oncoming-traffic-what-should-you-do-if-pedestrians-are-standing-on-the-pavement-waiting-to-cross-the-side-road/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Turn in because the pedestrians are safe on the pavement", "Wait and give way to the pedestrians", "Wave at the pedestrians, inviting them to cross the road", "Sound your horn to alert the pedestrians to your presence"], "answer": "Wait and give way to the pedestrians"},
{"id": "44026", "question": "You’re turning right at a crossroads. An oncoming driver is also turning right. What’s the advantage of turning behind the oncoming vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-turning-right-at-a-crossroads-an-oncoming-driver-is-also-turning-right-whats-the-advantage-of-turning-behind-the-oncoming-vehicle/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["You'll have more time to turn", "You'll have a clearer view of any approaching traffic", "You'll use less fuel because you can stay in a higher gear", "You'll be able to turn without stopping"], "answer": "You'll have a clearer view of any approaching traffic"},
{"id": "47545", "question": "You’re turning left from a main road into a side road. What should you do if there’s a pedestrian on the pavement waiting to cross the side road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-turning-left-from-a-main-road-into-a-side-road-what-should-you-do-if-theres-a-pedestrian-on-the-pavement-waiting-to-cross-the-side-road/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Carry on turning into the side road", "Flash your lights to encourage the pedestrian to cross", "Sound your horn to let the pedestrian know you're there", "Wait and give way to the pedestrian"], "answer": "Wait and give way to the pedestrian"},
{"id": "44057", "question": "You’re travelling on a road that has road humps. What should you do when the driver in front is travelling more slowly than you?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2640.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-on-a-road-that-has-road-humps-what-should-you-do-when-the-driver-in-front-is-travelling-more-slowly-than-you/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Flash your headlights", "Overtake as soon as you can", "Sound your horn", "Slow down and stay behind"], "answer": "Slow down and stay behind"},
{"id": "47543", "question": "You’re travelling on a narrow section of road. What should you do if a horse rider ahead is riding in the centre of the lane?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-on-a-narrow-section-of-road-what-should-you-do-if-a-horse-rider-ahead-is-riding-in-the-centre-of-the-lane/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Stay behind and allow them to ride in this position", "Move across to the right and try to ease past them", "Get up close behind to encourage them to move aside", "Sound your horn to alert them to your presence"], "answer": "Stay behind and allow them to ride in this position"},
{"id": "44163", "question": "You’re travelling on a motorway in England. When must you stop your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-on-a-motorway-in-england-when-must-you-stop-your-vehicle/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When signalled to stop by a pedestrian on the hard shoulder", "When signalled to stop by a driver who has broken down", "When signalled to stop by a traffic officer", "When signalled to stop by a roadworks supervisor"], "answer": "When signalled to stop by a traffic officer"},
{"id": "43702", "question": "You’re travelling in very heavy rain. How is this likely to affect your overall stopping distance?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-in-very-heavy-rain-how-is-this-likely-to-affect-your-overall-stopping-distance-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["It will be doubled", "It will be no different", "It will be halved", "It will be ten times greater"], "answer": "It will be doubled"},
{"id": "44122", "question": "You’re travelling in the left-hand lane of a three-lane motorway. How should you react to traffic joining from a slip road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-in-the-left-hand-lane-of-a-three-lane-motorway-how-should-you-react-to-traffic-joining-from-a-slip-road-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Maintain a steady speed", "Adjust your speed or change lane if you can do so safely", "Increase your speed to ensure they join behind you", "Switch on your hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Adjust your speed or change lane if you can do so safely"},
{"id": "44016", "question": "You’re travelling behind a moped. What should you do if you want to turn left a short distance ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-behind-a-moped-what-should-you-do-if-you-want-to-turn-left-a-short-distance-ahead-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Sound your horn as a warning and pull in front of the moped", "Stay behind until the moped has passed the junction", "Overtake the moped before the junction", "Pull alongside the moped and stay level until just before the junction"], "answer": "Stay behind until the moped has passed the junction"},
{"id": "43699", "question": "You’re travelling behind a bus. What should you do if it pulls up at a bus stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-behind-a-bus-what-should-you-do-if-it-pulls-up-at-a-bus-stop/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Sound your horn", "Accelerate past the bus", "Pull in closely behind the bus", "Look for pedestrians"], "answer": "Look for pedestrians"},
{"id": "44379", "question": "You’re travelling along this road. How should you pass the cyclist?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1439.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-along-this-road-how-should-you-pass-the-cyclist/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Sound your horn as you pass", "Keep close to them as you pass", "Change down one gear before you pass", "Leave them plenty of room as you pass"], "answer": "Leave them plenty of room as you pass"},
{"id": "44040", "question": "You’re travelling along a residential street. There are parked vehicles on the left-hand side. Why should you keep your speed down?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-along-a-residential-street-there-are-parked-vehicles-on-the-left-hand-side-why-should-you-keep-your-speed-down/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["You may set off car alarms", "So that oncoming traffic can see you more clearly", "There may be delivery lorries on the street", "Children may run out from between the vehicles"], "answer": "Children may run out from between the vehicles"},
{"id": "43712", "question": "You’re travelling along a motorway. Where would you find a crawler or climbing lane?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2237.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-along-a-motorway-where-would-you-find-a-crawler-or-climbing-lane-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Before a junction", "Along the hard shoulder", "Before a service area", "On a steep gradient"], "answer": "On a steep gradient"},
{"id": "44124", "question": "You’re travelling along a motorway. When are you allowed to overtake on the left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-travelling-along-a-motorway-when-are-you-allowed-to-overtake-on-the-left-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When you can see well ahead that the hard shoulder is clear", "When you warn drivers behind by signalling left", "When in queues and traffic to your right is moving more slowly than you are", "When the traffic in the right-hand lane is signalling right"], "answer": "When in queues and traffic to your right is moving more slowly than you are"},
{"id": "44481", "question": "You’re towing a trailer along a three-lane motorway. When may you use the right-hand lane?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-towing-a-trailer-along-a-three-lane-motorway-when-may-you-use-the-right-hand-lane-2/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When there are lane closures", "When you can maintain a high speed", "When there's slow-moving traffic", "When large vehicles are in the left and centre lanes"], "answer": "When there are lane closures"},
{"id": "44473", "question": "You’re towing a caravan. Which is the safest type of rear-view mirror to use?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-towing-a-caravan-which-is-the-safest-type-of-rear-view-mirror-to-use-2/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Extended-arm side mirrors", "Interior wide-angle mirror", "Ordinary interior mirror", "Ordinary door mirrors"], "answer": "Extended-arm side mirrors"},
{"id": "44214", "question": "You’re the first person to arrive at an incident where people are badly injured. You’ve switched on your hazard warning lights and checked all engines are stopped. What else should you do?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-the-first-person-to-arrive-at-an-incident-where-people-are-badly-injured-youve-switched-on-your-hazard-warning-lights-and-checked-all-engines-are-stopped-what-else-should-you-do-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Try and get people who are injured to drink something", "Move the people who are injured clear of their vehicles", "Make sure that an ambulance has been called", "Stop other cars and ask the drivers for help"], "answer": "Make sure that an ambulance has been called"},
{"id": "44524", "question": "You’re stopped at the side of the road. What must you do if you’ll be waiting there for some time?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-stopped-at-the-side-of-the-road-what-must-you-do-if-youll-be-waiting-there-for-some-time/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Apply the steering lock", "Switch off the engine", "Switch off the radio", "Use your headlights"], "answer": "Switch off the engine"},
{"id": "44362", "question": "You’re reversing into a side road. When would your vehicle be the greatest hazard to passing traffic?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-reversing-into-a-side-road-when-would-your-vehicle-be-the-greatest-hazard-to-passing-traffic/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When the front of your vehicle swings out", "After you've completed the manoeuvre", "Just before you begin to manoeuvre", "After you've entered the side road"], "answer": "When the front of your vehicle swings out"},
{"id": "44491", "question": "You’re planning to tow a caravan. What will help the handling of the combination?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-planning-to-tow-a-caravan-what-will-help-the-handling-of-the-combination/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Anti-lock brakes fitted to the towing vehicle", "A stabiliser fitted to the tow bar", "Power steering fitted to the towing vehicle", "A jockey wheel fitted to the tow bar"], "answer": "A stabiliser fitted to the tow bar"},
{"id": "44076", "question": "You’re parked on the road at night. When must you use parking lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-parked-on-the-road-at-night-when-must-you-use-parking-lights/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["When the speed limit exceeds 30 mph", "When you're facing oncoming traffic", "When you're near a bus stop", "When there are continuous white lines in the middle of the road"], "answer": "When the speed limit exceeds 30 mph"},
{"id": "44483", "question": "You’re parked in a busy high street. What’s the safest way to turn your vehicle around so you can drive in the opposite direction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-parked-in-a-busy-high-street-whats-the-safest-way-to-turn-your-vehicle-around-so-you-can-drive-in-the-opposite-direction/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Carry out a U-turn", "Turn around in a quiet side road", "Ask someone to stop the traffic", "Drive into a side road and reverse out into the main road"], "answer": "Turn around in a quiet side road"},
{"id": "44039", "question": "You’re on a three-lane motorway. Which lane are you in if there are red reflective studs on your left and white ones to your right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-three-lane-motorway-which-lane-are-you-in-if-there-are-red-reflective-studs-on-your-left-and-white-ones-to-your-right/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["On the hard shoulder", "In the middle lane", "In the right-hand lane", "In the left-hand lane"], "answer": "In the left-hand lane"},
{"id": "44145", "question": "You’re on a smart motorway. What does it mean when a red cross is displayed above the hard shoulder?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2789.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-smart-motorway-what-does-it-mean-when-a-red-cross-is-displayed-above-the-hard-shoulder/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Use this lane as a running lane", "You shouldn't travel in this lane", "Pull up in this lane to answer your mobile phone", "This lane can be used if you need a rest"], "answer": "You shouldn't travel in this lane"},
{"id": "44146", "question": "You’re on a smart motorway. What does it mean when a mandatory speed limit is displayed above the hard shoulder?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2790.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-smart-motorway-what-does-it-mean-when-a-mandatory-speed-limit-is-displayed-above-the-hard-shoulder-2/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["The hard shoulder can be used as a running lane", "You can pull up in this lane to answer a mobile phone", "You can park on the hard shoulder if you feel tired", "You shouldn't travel in this lane"], "answer": "The hard shoulder can be used as a running lane"},
{"id": "44180", "question": "You’re on a smart motorway. What does it mean if a red cross is showing above the hard shoulder and mandatory speed limits above all other lanes?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2856.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-smart-motorway-what-does-it-mean-if-a-red-cross-is-showing-above-the-hard-shoulder-and-mandatory-speed-limits-above-all-other-lanes/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["The hard shoulder is for emergency or breakdown use only", "The hard shoulder can be used as a rest area if you feel tired", "The hard shoulder can be used as a normal running lane", "The hard shoulder has a speed limit of 50 mph"], "answer": "The hard shoulder is for emergency or breakdown use only"},
{"id": "44412", "question": "You’re on a road that’s only wide enough for one vehicle. What should you do if a car is coming towards you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-road-thats-only-wide-enough-for-one-vehicle-what-should-you-do-if-a-car-is-coming-towards-you/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Pull into a passing place on your right", "Pull into a passing place on your left", "Pull into a passing place if your vehicle is wider", "Force the other driver to reverse"], "answer": "Pull into a passing place on your left"},
{"id": "44240", "question": "You’re on a motorway. When can you use hazard warning lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-motorway-when-can-you-use-hazard-warning-lights-2/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["When you slow down quickly because of danger ahead", "When you're being towed by another vehicle", "When you're riding on the hard shoulder", "When a vehicle is following too closely"], "answer": "When you slow down quickly because of danger ahead"},
{"id": "44046", "question": "You’re on a motorway. What should you do if there’s a red cross showing on the signs above your lane only?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-motorway-what-should-you-do-if-theres-a-red-cross-showing-on-the-signs-above-your-lane-only/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Continue in that lane and look for further information", "Pull onto the hard shoulder", "Don't continue in that lane", "Stop and wait for an instruction to proceed"], "answer": "Don't continue in that lane"},
{"id": "44177", "question": "You’re on a motorway. What must you do if there’s a red cross showing above every lane?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2852.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-motorway-what-must-you-do-if-theres-a-red-cross-showing-above-every-lane/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Leave at the next exit", "Slow down and watch for further signals", "Stop and wait", "Pull onto the hard shoulder"], "answer": "Stop and wait"},
{"id": "44119", "question": "You’re on a motorway that isn’t subject to smart motorway regulations. When should you use the hard shoulder?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-motorway-that-isnt-subject-to-smart-motorway-regulations-when-should-you-use-the-hard-shoulder/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When you're stopping in an emergency", "When you're leaving the motorway", "When you're stopping for a rest", "When you're joining the motorway"], "answer": "When you're stopping in an emergency"},
{"id": "44031", "question": "You’re on a motorway. A lorry has stopped in the right-hand lane. What should you do when you see this sign on the lorry?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2592.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-motorway-a-lorry-has-stopped-in-the-right-hand-lane-what-should-you-do-when-you-see-this-sign-on-the-lorry-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Move into the right-hand lane", "Stop behind the flashing lights", "Leave the motorway at the next exit", "Pass the lorry on the left"], "answer": "Pass the lorry on the left"},
{"id": "44242", "question": "You’re on a long motorway journey. What should you do if you start to feel sleepy?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-on-a-long-motorway-journey-what-should-you-do-if-you-start-to-feel-sleepy-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Drive faster to complete your journey sooner", "Stop on the hard shoulder for a rest", "Leave the motorway and stop in a safe place", "Play some loud music"], "answer": "Leave the motorway and stop in a safe place"},
{"id": "44049", "question": "You’re looking for somewhere to safely park your vehicle. Where would you choose to park?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-looking-for-somewhere-to-safely-park-your-vehicle-where-would-you-choose-to-park/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["At or near a bus stop", "Near the brow of a hill", "On the approach to a level crossing", "In a designated parking space"], "answer": "In a designated parking space"},
{"id": "44404", "question": "You’re looking for somewhere to park your vehicle. What should you do if the only free spaces are marked for disabled drivers?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-looking-for-somewhere-to-park-your-vehicle-what-should-you-do-if-the-only-free-spaces-are-marked-for-disabled-drivers/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Wait for a regular parking space to become free", "Park in one of these spaces but stay with your vehicle", "Use one of the spaces as long as one is kept free", "Use one of these spaces"], "answer": "Wait for a regular parking space to become free"},
{"id": "44527", "question": "You’re leaving your vehicle parked on a road and unattended. When may you leave the engine running?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-leaving-your-vehicle-parked-on-a-road-and-unattended-when-may-you-leave-the-engine-running-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["If you'll be parking for less than five minutes", "When parked in a 20 mph zone", "If the battery keeps going flat", "Never if you're away from the vehicle"], "answer": "Never if you're away from the vehicle"},
{"id": "44020", "question": "You’re leaving a safe gap as you follow a large vehicle. What should you do if a car moves into this gap?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-leaving-a-safe-gap-as-you-follow-a-large-vehicle-what-should-you-do-if-a-car-moves-into-this-gap/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Sound your horn", "Start to overtake", "Flash your headlights", "Drop back further"], "answer": "Drop back further"},
{"id": "43706", "question": "You’re joining a motorway from a slip road. How should you deal with traffic already on the motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-joining-a-motorway-from-a-slip-road-how-should-you-deal-with-traffic-already-on-the-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Carry on along the hard shoulder until you see a safe gap", "Stop at the end of the slip road and look for a safe gap", "Match your speed to traffic in the left-hand lane and filter into a safe gap", "Use the slip road to accelerate until you're moving much faster than the motorway traffic"], "answer": "Match your speed to traffic in the left-hand lane and filter into a safe gap"},
{"id": "44276", "question": "You’re invited to a pub lunch. What should you do if you know that you’ll have to drive in the evening?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-invited-to-a-pub-lunch-what-should-you-do-if-you-know-that-youll-have-to-drive-in-the-evening/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Eat a hot meal with your alcoholic drinks", "Have some milk before drinking alcohol", "Don't drink any alcohol at all", "Avoid mixing your alcoholic drinks"], "answer": "Don't drink any alcohol at all"},
{"id": "44120", "question": "You’re in the right-hand lane of a three-lane motorway. What do these overhead signs mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2748.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-three-lane-motorway-what-do-these-overhead-signs-mean-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Leave the motorway at the next exit", "Use the hard shoulder until you've passed the hazard", "Move to the left and reduce your speed to 50 mph", "There are roadworks 50 metres (55 yards) ahead"], "answer": "Move to the left and reduce your speed to 50 mph"},
{"id": "43973", "question": "You’re in the left-hand lane at traffic lights, waiting to turn left. Which signal means you must wait?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-the-left-hand-lane-at-traffic-lights-waiting-to-turn-left-which-signal-means-you-must-wait/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2389b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2389a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2389d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2389c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2389a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44167", "question": "You’re in a tunnel and you see this sign. What does it mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2841.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-a-tunnel-and-you-see-this-sign-what-does-it-mean-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Beware of pedestrians: no footpath ahead", "No access for pedestrians", "Beware of pedestrians crossing ahead", "Direction to an emergency pedestrian exit"], "answer": "Direction to an emergency pedestrian exit"},
{"id": "43651", "question": "You’re in a one-way street and want to turn right. Where should you position your vehicle when there are two lanes?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-a-one-way-street-and-want-to-turn-right-where-should-you-position-your-vehicle-when-there-are-two-lanes/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["In either lane, depending on the traffic", "In the left-hand lane", "Just left of the centre line", "In the right-hand lane"], "answer": "In the right-hand lane"},
{"id": "44086", "question": "You’re in a line of traffic. What action should you take if the driver behind is following very closely?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-a-line-of-traffic-what-action-should-you-take-if-the-driver-behind-is-following-very-closely/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Slow down, gradually increasing the gap between you and the vehicle in front", "Move over to a position just left of the centre line of the road", "Signal left and wave the driver behind to come past", "Ignore the driver behind and continue to travel within the speed limit"], "answer": "Slow down, gradually increasing the gap between you and the vehicle in front"},
{"id": "44125", "question": "You’re in a built-up area at night and the road is well lit. Why should you use dipped headlights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-in-a-built-up-area-at-night-and-the-road-is-well-lit-why-should-you-use-dipped-headlights/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["So that you can see further along the road", "So that you can go at a much faster speed", "So that you can switch to main beam quickly", "So that you can be easily seen by others"], "answer": "So that you can be easily seen by others"},
{"id": "44436", "question": "You’re having difficulty finding a parking space in a busy town. Can you park on the zigzag lines of a zebra crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-having-difficulty-finding-a-parking-space-in-a-busy-town-can-you-park-on-the-zigzag-lines-of-a-zebra-crossing/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Yes, if you don't block people from crossing", "No, not unless you stay with your car", "No, not under any circumstances", "Yes, in order to drop off a passenger"], "answer": "No, not under any circumstances"},
{"id": "44316", "question": "You’re going to turn left from a main road into a minor road. What should you do as you approach the junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-going-to-turn-left-from-a-main-road-into-a-minor-road-what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-the-junction/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Keep in the middle of the road", "Keep just left of the middle of the road", "Swing out to the right just before turning", "Keep well to the left of the road"], "answer": "Keep well to the left of the road"},
{"id": "47580", "question": "You’re going to tow a trailer that’s wider than your car. What must you fit to your car before you start towing it?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-going-to-tow-a-trailer-thats-wider-than-your-car-what-must-you-fit-to-your-car-before-you-start-towing-it/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Exterior towing mirrors", "Parking sensors", "Rear-view camera", "Projection markers"], "answer": "Exterior towing mirrors"},
{"id": "44206", "question": "You’re going through a long tunnel. What will warn you of congestion or an incident ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-going-through-a-long-tunnel-what-will-warn-you-of-congestion-or-an-incident-ahead-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Variable message signs", "Other drivers flashing their lights", "Hazard warning lines", "Areas with hatch markings"], "answer": "Variable message signs"},
{"id": "44015", "question": "You’re following two cyclists as they approach a roundabout in the left-hand lane. Where would you expect the cyclists to go?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-two-cyclists-as-they-approach-a-roundabout-in-the-left-hand-lane-where-would-you-expect-the-cyclists-to-go/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Any direction", "Straight ahead", "Left", "Right"], "answer": "Any direction"},
{"id": "44232", "question": "You’re following other vehicles in fog. You have your headlights on dipped beam. What else can you do to reduce the chances of being in a collision?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-other-vehicles-in-fog-you-have-your-headlights-on-dipped-beam-what-else-can-you-do-to-reduce-the-chances-of-being-in-a-collision/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Keep a safe distance from the vehicle in front", "Use main beam instead of dipped headlights", "Keep up with the faster vehicles", "Keep close to the vehicle in front"], "answer": "Keep a safe distance from the vehicle in front"},
{"id": "44113", "question": "You’re following a vehicle on a wet road. You stay a safe distance behind it. What should you do if a driver overtakes you and pulls into the gap you’ve left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-vehicle-on-a-wet-road-you-stay-a-safe-distance-behind-it-what-should-you-do-if-a-driver-overtakes-you-and-pulls-into-the-gap-youve-left/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Stay close to the other vehicle until it moves on", "Try to overtake safely as soon as you can", "Drop back to regain a safe distance", "Flash your headlights as a warning"], "answer": "Drop back to regain a safe distance"},
{"id": "44064", "question": "You’re following a slower-moving vehicle. What should you do if there’s a junction just ahead on the right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-slower-moving-vehicle-what-should-you-do-if-theres-a-junction-just-ahead-on-the-right/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Slow down and prepare to overtake on the left", "Only consider overtaking when you're past the junction", "Overtake after checking your mirrors and signalling", "Accelerate quickly to overtake before reaching the junction"], "answer": "Only consider overtaking when you're past the junction"},
{"id": "43700", "question": "You’re following a lorry on a wet road. What should you do when spray makes it difficult to see the road ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2193.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-lorry-on-a-wet-road-what-should-you-do-when-spray-makes-it-difficult-to-see-the-road-ahead-3/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Speed up and overtake quickly", "Drop back until you can see better", "Put your headlights on full beam", "Keep close to the lorry, away from the spray"], "answer": "Drop back until you can see better"},
{"id": "43695", "question": "You’re following a long vehicle as it approaches a crossroads. What should you do if it signals left but moves out to the right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-long-vehicle-as-it-approaches-a-crossroads-what-should-you-do-if-it-signals-left-but-moves-out-to-the-right/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Assume the signal is wrong and that it's turning right", "Overtake it as it starts to slow down", "Stay well back and give it room", "Get closer in order to pass it quickly"], "answer": "Stay well back and give it room"},
{"id": "43696", "question": "You’re following a long vehicle approaching a crossroads. What should you do if the driver signals right but moves close to the left-hand kerb?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-long-vehicle-approaching-a-crossroads-what-should-you-do-if-the-driver-signals-right-but-moves-close-to-the-left-hand-kerb-2/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Overtake on the right-hand side", "Wait behind the long vehicle", "Warn the driver about the wrong signal", "Report the driver to the police"], "answer": "Wait behind the long vehicle"},
{"id": "44084", "question": "You’re following a large vehicle. Why should you stay a safe distance behind it?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-large-vehicle-why-should-you-stay-a-safe-distance-behind-it-3/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["You'll help the large vehicle to stop more easily", "You'll be able to corner more quickly", "You'll give the driver a chance to see you in their mirrors", "You'll keep out of the wind better"], "answer": "You'll give the driver a chance to see you in their mirrors"},
{"id": "44112", "question": "You’re following a large vehicle as it approaches a crossroads. What should you do if the driver signals to turn left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-large-vehicle-as-it-approaches-a-crossroads-what-should-you-do-if-the-driver-signals-to-turn-left/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Overtake if there are no oncoming vehicles", "Overtake if you can leave plenty of room", "Wait for the driver to cancel his signal", "Wait for the vehicle to finish turning"], "answer": "Wait for the vehicle to finish turning"},
{"id": "44033", "question": "You’re following a cyclist. What should you do when you wish to turn left a short distance ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2601.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-following-a-cyclist-what-should-you-do-when-you-wish-to-turn-left-a-short-distance-ahead/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Hold back until the cyclist has passed the junction", "Pull alongside the cyclist and stay level until after the junction", "Go around the cyclist on the junction", "Overtake the cyclist before you reach the junction"], "answer": "Hold back until the cyclist has passed the junction"},
{"id": "44341", "question": "You’re driving your car. When may you use a hand-held mobile phone?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-your-car-when-may-you-use-a-hand-held-mobile-phone/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["When you've parked safely", "When you're receiving a call", "When your car has automatic transmission", "When you're driving at less than 30 mph"], "answer": "When you've parked safely"},
{"id": "44538", "question": "You’re driving with your front fog lights switched on. What should you do if the fog has cleared?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-with-your-front-fog-lights-switched-on-what-should-you-do-if-the-fog-has-cleared/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Switch them off as long as visibility remains good", "Leave them on if other drivers have their lights on", "Flash them to warn oncoming traffic that it's foggy", "Drive with them on instead of your headlights"], "answer": "Switch them off as long as visibility remains good"},
{"id": "44270", "question": "You’re driving towards this level crossing. What would be the first warning of an approaching train?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1085.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-towards-this-level-crossing-what-would-be-the-first-warning-of-an-approaching-train-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["One half-barrier down", "Twin flashing red lights", "A steady amber light", "Both half-barriers down"], "answer": "A steady amber light"},
{"id": "44467", "question": "You’re driving towards this left-hand bend. What danger should you be anticipating?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1665.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-towards-this-left-hand-bend-what-danger-should-you-be-anticipating/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Mud on the road", "A vehicle overtaking you", "The road getting narrower", "Pedestrians walking towards you"], "answer": "Pedestrians walking towards you"},
{"id": "44472", "question": "You’re driving towards a zebra crossing. What should you do if a person in a wheelchair is waiting to cross?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-towards-a-zebra-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-a-person-in-a-wheelchair-is-waiting-to-cross/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Continue on your way", "Wave to the person to cross", "Be prepared to stop", "Wave to the person to wait"], "answer": "Be prepared to stop"},
{"id": "44470", "question": "You’re driving past parked cars. What should you do if you see a bicycle wheel sticking out between the cars?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-past-parked-cars-what-should-you-do-if-you-see-a-bicycle-wheel-sticking-out-between-the-cars/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Slow down and wave the cyclist across", "Slow down and be prepared to stop for a cyclist", "Accelerate past quickly and sound your horn", "Brake sharply and flash your headlights"], "answer": "Slow down and be prepared to stop for a cyclist"},
{"id": "44294", "question": "You’re driving past a line of parked cars. What should you do if a ball bounces out into the road ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1142.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-past-a-line-of-parked-cars-what-should-you-do-if-a-ball-bounces-out-into-the-road-ahead/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Continue driving at the same speed and flash your headlights", "Stop and wave the children across to fetch their ball", "Continue driving at the same speed and sound your horn", "Slow down and be prepared to stop for children"], "answer": "Slow down and be prepared to stop for children"},
{"id": "44383", "question": "You’re driving on this dual carriageway. Why may you need to slow down?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1454.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-this-dual-carriageway-why-may-you-need-to-slow-down-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["There's a broken white line in the centre", "There are solid white lines on either side", "There are roadworks ahead of you", "There are no footpaths"], "answer": "There are roadworks ahead of you"},
{"id": "44402", "question": "You’re driving on the motorway. Which lane should you get into well before you reach your exit?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-the-motorway-which-lane-should-you-get-into-well-before-you-reach-your-exit/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["The hard shoulder", "The middle lane", "The right-hand lane", "The left-hand lane"], "answer": "The left-hand lane"},
{"id": "44459", "question": "You’re driving on the motorway. What should you do if luggage falls from your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-the-motorway-what-should-you-do-if-luggage-falls-from-your-vehicle/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Pull up on the hard shoulder and wave traffic down", "Stop at the next emergency telephone and report the incident", "Stop on the motorway and switch on hazard warning lights while you pick it up", "Walk back up the motorway to pick it up"], "answer": "Stop at the next emergency telephone and report the incident"},
{"id": "44302", "question": "You’re driving on the motorway in windy conditions. What should you do as you overtake a high-sided vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-the-motorway-in-windy-conditions-what-should-you-do-as-you-overtake-a-high-sided-vehicle/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Increase your speed", "Drive alongside very closely", "Expect normal conditions", "Be wary of a sudden gust"], "answer": "Be wary of a sudden gust"},
{"id": "44212", "question": "You’re driving on the motorway. How can you lower the risk of a collision when the vehicle behind is following too closely?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-the-motorway-how-can-you-lower-the-risk-of-a-collision-when-the-vehicle-behind-is-following-too-closely/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Increase your distance from the vehicle in front", "Brake sharply", "Switch on your hazard warning lights", "Move onto the hard shoulder and stop"], "answer": "Increase your distance from the vehicle in front"},
{"id": "44463", "question": "You’re driving on an open road in dry weather. What distance should you keep from the vehicle in front?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-an-open-road-in-dry-weather-what-distance-should-you-keep-from-the-vehicle-in-front/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["One car length", "Two car lengths", "Two metres (6 feet 6 inches)", "A two-second time gap"], "answer": "A two-second time gap"},
{"id": "44388", "question": "You’re driving on an icy road. What distance from the car in front should you drive?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-an-icy-road-what-distance-from-the-car-in-front-should-you-drive-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Four times the normal distance", "Ten times the normal distance", "Six times the normal distance", "Eight times the normal distance"], "answer": "Ten times the normal distance"},
{"id": "44358", "question": "You’re driving on a wet road. What should you do if you have to stop your vehicle in an emergency?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-wet-road-what-should-you-do-if-you-have-to-stop-your-vehicle-in-an-emergency/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Keep both hands on the steering wheel", "Apply the parking brake and footbrake together", "Select reverse gear", "Give an arm signal"], "answer": "Keep both hands on the steering wheel"},
{"id": "44083", "question": "You’re driving on a three-lane motorway. How should you overtake a slow-moving lorry in the middle lane if it’s showing this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2701.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-three-lane-motorway-how-should-you-overtake-a-slow-moving-lorry-in-the-middle-lane-if-its-showing-this-sign/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Approach with care and overtake on the left of the lorry", "Follow the lorry until you can leave the motorway", "Cautiously approach the lorry, then overtake on either side", "Use the right-hand lane and overtake the lorry normally"], "answer": "Approach with care and overtake on the left of the lorry"},
{"id": "43698", "question": "You’re driving on a single carriageway road. Why should you keep well back while you’re following a large vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-single-carriageway-road-why-should-you-keep-well-back-while-youre-following-a-large-vehicle/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["To get the best view of the road ahead", "To give yourself acceleration space if you decide to overtake", "To leave a gap in case the vehicle stops and rolls back", "To offer other drivers a safe gap if they want to overtake you"], "answer": "To get the best view of the road ahead"},
{"id": "44275", "question": "You’re driving on a road with several lanes. What do these signs above the lanes mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1100.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-road-with-several-lanes-what-do-these-signs-above-the-lanes-mean/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The two left lanes are open", "The two right lanes are open", "Traffic in the left lanes should stop", "Traffic in the right lanes should stop"], "answer": "The two left lanes are open"},
{"id": "44515", "question": "You’re driving on a road that has a cycle lane. What does it mean if the lane is marked by a broken white line?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BB1747.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-road-that-has-a-cycle-lane-what-does-it-mean-if-the-lane-is-marked-by-a-broken-white-line/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["The lane must be used by motorcyclists in heavy traffic", "Cyclists can travel in both directions in that lane", "You shouldn't drive in the lane unless it's unavoidable", "There's a reduced speed limit for motor vehicles using the lane"], "answer": "You shouldn't drive in the lane unless it's unavoidable"},
{"id": "44353", "question": "You’re driving on a one-way street. What should you do if you realise you’ve taken the wrong route?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1353.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-one-way-street-what-should-you-do-if-you-realise-youve-taken-the-wrong-route/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Turn around in a side road", "Reverse into a driveway", "Reverse out of the road", "Continue and find another route"], "answer": "Continue and find another route"},
{"id": "44401", "question": "You’re driving on a motorway. What does it mean if the car in front shows its hazard warning lights for a short time?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-motorway-what-does-it-mean-if-the-car-in-front-shows-its-hazard-warning-lights-for-a-short-time/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["There's a police speed check ahead", "Traffic ahead is slowing or stopping suddenly", "The driver wants you to overtake", "The other car is going to change lanes"], "answer": "Traffic ahead is slowing or stopping suddenly"},
{"id": "44390", "question": "You’re driving on a motorway at night. Which lights should you have on if there are other vehicles just ahead of you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-motorway-at-night-which-lights-should-you-have-on-if-there-are-other-vehicles-just-ahead-of-you/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Sidelights only", "Front fog lights", "Main-beam headlights", "Dipped headlights"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44308", "question": "You’re driving on a motorway and have to slow down suddenly due to a hazard ahead. How can you warn drivers behind of the hazard?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-motorway-and-have-to-slow-down-suddenly-due-to-a-hazard-ahead-how-can-you-warn-drivers-behind-of-the-hazard/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Sound your horn", "Switch on your hazard warning lights", "Switch on your headlights", "Flash your headlights"], "answer": "Switch on your hazard warning lights"},
{"id": "44029", "question": "You’re driving on a country road that has no pavement. What should you anticipate finding on your side of the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-country-road-that-has-no-pavement-what-should-you-anticipate-finding-on-your-side-of-the-road/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Horse riders", "Bicycles", "Pedestrians", "Motorcycles"], "answer": "Pedestrians"},
{"id": "44244", "question": "You’re driving on a clear night. Which lights should you use if the national speed limit applies and there’s a steady stream of oncoming traffic?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-clear-night-which-lights-should-you-use-if-the-national-speed-limit-applies-and-theres-a-steady-stream-of-oncoming-traffic/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Full-beam headlights", "Dipped headlights", "Fog lights", "Sidelights"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44319", "question": "You’re driving on a busy main road. What should you do if you find that you’re driving in the wrong direction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-on-a-busy-main-road-what-should-you-do-if-you-find-that-youre-driving-in-the-wrong-direction/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Turn around in a side road", "Make a 'three-point' turn in the main road", "Make a U-turn in the main road", "Turn into a side road on the right and reverse into the main road"], "answer": "Turn around in a side road"},
{"id": "44248", "question": "You’re driving in traffic at the speed limit for the road. What should you do if the driver behind is trying to overtake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-traffic-at-the-speed-limit-for-the-road-what-should-you-do-if-the-driver-behind-is-trying-to-overtake-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Wave the driver behind to overtake when it's safe", "Keep a steady course and allow the driver behind to overtake", "Accelerate to get away from the driver behind", "Move closer to the car ahead, so the driver behind has no room to overtake"], "answer": "Keep a steady course and allow the driver behind to overtake"},
{"id": "44297", "question": "You’re driving in town. Why should you be careful if there’s a bus at a bus stop on the other side of the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-town-why-should-you-be-careful-if-theres-a-bus-at-a-bus-stop-on-the-other-side-of-the-road-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Pedestrians might come from behind the bus", "The bus might move off suddenly", "The bus might remain stationary", "The bus might have broken down"], "answer": "Pedestrians might come from behind the bus"},
{"id": "44485", "question": "You’re driving in the right-hand lane of a dual carriageway. What should you do if you see a sign showing that the right-hand lane is closed 800 yards ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1694.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-dual-carriageway-what-should-you-do-if-you-see-a-sign-showing-that-the-right-hand-lane-is-closed-800-yards-ahead/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Move to the left in good time", "Wait and see which lane is moving faster", "Keep in that lane until you reach the queue", "Move to the left immediately"], "answer": "Move to the left in good time"},
{"id": "44474", "question": "You’re driving in heavy traffic on a wet road. Which lights should you use if there’s a lot of surface spray?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-heavy-traffic-on-a-wet-road-which-lights-should-you-use-if-theres-a-lot-of-surface-spray/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Dipped headlights", "Rear fog lights if visibility is more than 100 metres (328 feet)", "Main-beam headlights", "Sidelights only"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44260", "question": "You’re driving in freezing conditions. What should you do as you approach a sharp bend?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-freezing-conditions-what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-a-sharp-bend/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Firmly use your footbrake", "Apply your parking brake", "Coast into the bend", "Slow down gently"], "answer": "Slow down gently"},
{"id": "44303", "question": "You’re driving in fog. Why should you keep well back from the vehicle in front?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-fog-why-should-you-keep-well-back-from-the-vehicle-in-front-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["In case it changes direction suddenly", "In case its fog lights dazzle you", "In case its brake lights dazzle you", "In case it stops suddenly"], "answer": "In case it stops suddenly"},
{"id": "44428", "question": "You’re driving in busy traffic. You want to pull up just after a junction on the left. When should you signal?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-busy-traffic-you-want-to-pull-up-just-after-a-junction-on-the-left-when-should-you-signal/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["As you're passing or just after the junction", "It would be better not to signal at all", "Well before you reach the junction", "Just before you reach the junction"], "answer": "As you're passing or just after the junction"},
{"id": "44296", "question": "You’re driving in a slow-moving queue of traffic. What should you do just before changing lane?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-a-slow-moving-queue-of-traffic-what-should-you-do-just-before-changing-lane/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Give a 'slowing down' arm signal", "Look for motorcyclists filtering through the traffic", "Change down to first gear", "Sound the horn and flash your lights"], "answer": "Look for motorcyclists filtering through the traffic"},
{"id": "44267", "question": "You’re driving in a built-up area that has traffic-calming measures. What should you do when you approach a road hump?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1076.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-in-a-built-up-area-that-has-traffic-calming-measures-what-should-you-do-when-you-approach-a-road-hump-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Move across to the left-hand side of the road", "Stop and check both pavements", "Check your mirror and slow down", "Wait for any pedestrians to cross"], "answer": "Check your mirror and slow down"},
{"id": "44245", "question": "You’re driving behind a large goods vehicle. What should you do if it signals left but steers to the right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-behind-a-large-goods-vehicle-what-should-you-do-if-it-signals-left-but-steers-to-the-right-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Hold your speed and sound your horn", "Drive on, keeping to the left", "Slow down and let the vehicle turn", "Overtake on the right of it"], "answer": "Slow down and let the vehicle turn"},
{"id": "44045", "question": "You’re driving at the legal speed limit. What should you do if the vehicle behind approaches quickly, flashing its headlights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-the-legal-speed-limit-what-should-you-do-if-the-vehicle-behind-approaches-quickly-flashing-its-headlights/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Allow the vehicle to overtake", "Maintain your speed to prevent the vehicle from overtaking", "Accelerate to make a gap behind you", "Touch the brakes sharply to show your brake lights"], "answer": "Allow the vehicle to overtake"},
{"id": "44418", "question": "You’re driving at night with your headlights on main beam. A vehicle is overtaking you. When should you dip your headlights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-night-with-your-headlights-on-main-beam-a-vehicle-is-overtaking-you-when-should-you-dip-your-headlights/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["As soon as the vehicle passes you", "Some time after the vehicle has passed you", "Only if the other driver dips their headlights", "Before the vehicle starts to pass you"], "answer": "As soon as the vehicle passes you"},
{"id": "44305", "question": "You’re driving at night. What should you do if you’re dazzled by headlights coming towards you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-night-what-should-you-do-if-youre-dazzled-by-headlights-coming-towards-you-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Shade your eyes with your hand", "Pull down your sun visor", "Slow down or stop", "Flash your main-beam headlights"], "answer": "Slow down or stop"},
{"id": "44471", "question": "You’re driving at night. What should you do if you’re dazzled by a vehicle behind you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-night-what-should-you-do-if-youre-dazzled-by-a-vehicle-behind-you/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Brake sharply to a stop", "Switch your rear lights on and off", "Set your mirror to the anti-dazzle position", "Set your mirror to dazzle the other driver"], "answer": "Set your mirror to the anti-dazzle position"},
{"id": "44450", "question": "You’re driving at night on an unlit road. What should you do if you’re following another vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-night-on-an-unlit-road-what-should-you-do-if-youre-following-another-vehicle/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Switch off your headlights", "Flash your headlights", "Use full-beam headlights", "Use dipped headlights"], "answer": "Use dipped headlights"},
{"id": "43726", "question": "You’re driving at night and looking for somewhere to park. When may you park on the right-hand side of the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-at-night-and-looking-for-somewhere-to-park-when-may-you-park-on-the-right-hand-side-of-the-road/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When you're in a one-way street", "When you have your sidelights on", "When you're more than 10 metres (32 feet) from a junction", "When you're under a lamppost"], "answer": "When you're in a one-way street"},
{"id": "44246", "question": "You’re driving along this road. What should you do if the red car cuts in close in front of you?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1013.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-along-this-road-what-should-you-do-if-the-red-car-cuts-in-close-in-front-of-you/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Flash your headlights several times", "Drop back to leave the correct separation distance", "Accelerate to get closer to the red car", "Give a long blast on the horn"], "answer": "Drop back to leave the correct separation distance"},
{"id": "44369", "question": "You’re driving along a wet road. How can you tell if your vehicle’s tyres are losing their grip on the surface?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-along-a-wet-road-how-can-you-tell-if-your-vehicles-tyres-are-losing-their-grip-on-the-surface-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["The engine noise will increase", "The steering will feel very light", "The engine will stall", "The steering will feel very heavy"], "answer": "The steering will feel very light"},
{"id": "44352", "question": "You’re driving along a country road. You see this sign. What should you do after dealing safely with the hazard?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1351.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-along-a-country-road-you-see-this-sign-what-should-you-do-after-dealing-safely-with-the-hazard-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Test your brakes", "Accelerate briskly", "Check your tyre pressures", "Switch on your hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Test your brakes"},
{"id": "44347", "question": "You’re driving a vehicle that has anti-lock brakes. How should you apply the footbrake when you need to stop in an emergency?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-a-vehicle-that-has-anti-lock-brakes-how-should-you-apply-the-footbrake-when-you-need-to-stop-in-an-emergency-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Slowly and gently", "Slowly but firmly", "Rapidly and gently", "Rapidly and firmly"], "answer": "Rapidly and firmly"},
{"id": "44520", "question": "You’re driving a friend’s children home from school. They’re both under 14 years old. Who’s responsible for making sure they wear a seat belt or approved child restraint where required?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-a-friends-children-home-from-school-theyre-both-under-14-years-old-whos-responsible-for-making-sure-they-wear-a-seat-belt-or-approved-child-restraint-where-required-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Your friend", "The children", "You, the driver", "An adult passenger"], "answer": "You, the driver"},
{"id": "44453", "question": "You’re driving a car that has a diesel engine. What can a loose filler cap on your fuel tank cause?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-a-car-that-has-a-diesel-engine-what-can-a-loose-filler-cap-on-your-fuel-tank-cause/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["It can make the engine difficult to start", "It can improve your vehicle's fuel consumption", "It can increase the level of exhaust emissions", "It can make the roads slippery for other road users"], "answer": "It can make the roads slippery for other road users"},
{"id": "44431", "question": "You’re driving a car fitted with automatic transmission. When would you use ‘kick down’?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-driving-a-car-fitted-with-automatic-transmission-when-would-you-use-kick-down/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["To brake progressively", "To accelerate quickly", "To improve fuel economy", "To engage cruise control"], "answer": "To accelerate quickly"},
{"id": "44338", "question": "You’re carrying two 13-year-old children and their parents in your car. Who’s responsible for seeing that the children wear seat belts?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-carrying-two-13-year-old-children-and-their-parents-in-your-car-whos-responsible-for-seeing-that-the-children-wear-seat-belts-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["You, the driver", "The children", "The children's parents", "The front-seat passenger"], "answer": "You, the driver"},
{"id": "44523", "question": "You’re carrying an 11-year-old child on the front seat of your car. They’re under 1.35 metres (4 feet 5 inches) tall. What seat belt security must be in place?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-carrying-an-11-year-old-child-on-the-front-seat-of-your-car-theyre-under-1-35-metres-4-feet-5-inches-tall-what-seat-belt-security-must-be-in-place/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["They must use an adult seat belt", "They must be able to see clearly out of the front window", "They must be able to fasten their own seat belt", "They must use a suitable child restraint"], "answer": "They must use a suitable child restraint"},
{"id": "44519", "question": "You’re carrying a child under three years old in your car. Which restraint is suitable for a child of this age?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-carrying-a-child-under-three-years-old-in-your-car-which-restraint-is-suitable-for-a-child-of-this-age/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["A child seat", "An adult seat belt", "An adult lap belt", "An adult holding a child"], "answer": "A child seat"},
{"id": "43644", "question": "You’re being overtaken by a long, heavily laden lorry. What should you do if it’s taking a long time for it to overtake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-being-overtaken-by-a-long-heavily-laden-lorry-what-should-you-do-if-its-taking-a-long-time-for-it-to-overtake/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Slow down", "Hold your speed", "Change direction", "Speed up"], "answer": "Slow down"},
{"id": "44271", "question": "You’re behind this cyclist. When the traffic lights change, what should you do?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1087.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-behind-this-cyclist-when-the-traffic-lights-change-what-should-you-do-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Turn right but give the cyclist room", "Tap your horn and drive through first", "Try to move off before the cyclist", "Allow the cyclist time and room"], "answer": "Allow the cyclist time and room"},
{"id": "44237", "question": "You’re at the scene of an incident. How could you help someone who’s suffering from shock?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-at-the-scene-of-an-incident-how-could-you-help-someone-whos-suffering-from-shock/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Reassure them confidently", "Offer them a cigarette", "Give them a warm drink", "Offer them some food"], "answer": "Reassure them confidently"},
{"id": "44291", "question": "You’re at the front of a queue of traffic waiting to turn right into a side road. Why is it important to check your right mirror just before turning?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-at-the-front-of-a-queue-of-traffic-waiting-to-turn-right-into-a-side-road-why-is-it-important-to-check-your-right-mirror-just-before-turning-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To check for emerging traffic", "To make sure the side road is clear", "To check for overtaking vehicles", "To look for pedestrians about to cross"], "answer": "To check for overtaking vehicles"},
{"id": "44183", "question": "You’re at an incident. What could you do to help an unconscious casualty?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-at-an-incident-what-could-you-do-to-help-an-unconscious-casualty/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Splash their face with cool water", "Take photographs of the scene", "Move them to somewhere more comfortable", "Check that they're breathing normally"], "answer": "Check that they're breathing normally"},
{"id": "43972", "question": "You’re at a junction controlled by traffic lights. When should you wait at a green light?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-at-a-junction-controlled-by-traffic-lights-when-should-you-wait-at-a-green-light/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["When pedestrians are waiting to cross", "When you intend to turn right", "When you think the lights may be about to change", "When your exit from the junction is blocked"], "answer": "When your exit from the junction is blocked"},
{"id": "44211", "question": "You’re approaching traffic lights and the red light is showing. What signal will show next?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-traffic-lights-and-the-red-light-is-showing-what-signal-will-show-next/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Green alone", "Green and amber", "Red and amber", "Amber alone"], "answer": "Red and amber"},
{"id": "44174", "question": "You’re approaching this roundabout. What should you do when a cyclist is keeping to the left while signalling to turn right?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2849.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-this-roundabout-what-should-you-do-when-a-cyclist-is-keeping-to-the-left-while-signalling-to-turn-right/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Sound your horn", "Overtake them", "Allow them space to turn", "Assume they're turning left"], "answer": "Allow them space to turn"},
{"id": "44060", "question": "You’re approaching an unmarked crossroads. How should you deal with the junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-an-unmarked-crossroads-how-should-you-deal-with-the-junction/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Slow down and keep to the right", "Accelerate and keep to the middle", "Slow down and look both ways", "Accelerate and look to the left"], "answer": "Slow down and look both ways"},
{"id": "44380", "question": "You’re approaching a zebra crossing. What should you do if pedestrians are waiting to cross?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-zebra-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-pedestrians-are-waiting-to-cross/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Use your headlights to indicate they can cross", "Wave at them to cross the road", "Give way to older and infirm people only", "Slow down and prepare to stop"], "answer": "Slow down and prepare to stop"},
{"id": "43692", "question": "You’re approaching a roundabout. What should you do if there are horses being ridden in front of you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-roundabout-what-should-you-do-if-there-are-horses-being-ridden-in-front-of-you/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Give them plenty of room", "Sound your horn as a warning", "Treat them like any other vehicle", "Accelerate past as quickly as possible"], "answer": "Give them plenty of room"},
{"id": "43684", "question": "You’re approaching a roundabout. What should you do if a cyclist ahead is signalling to turn right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-roundabout-what-should-you-do-if-a-cyclist-ahead-is-signalling-to-turn-right/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Signal the cyclist to move across", "Overtake on the right", "Give the cyclist plenty of room", "Give a warning with your horn"], "answer": "Give the cyclist plenty of room"},
{"id": "44413", "question": "You’re approaching a red light at a puffin crossing. Pedestrians are on the crossing. When will the red light change?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-red-light-at-a-puffin-crossing-pedestrians-are-on-the-crossing-when-will-the-red-light-change-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["When you start to edge forward onto the crossing", "When a driver from the opposite direction reaches the crossing", "When the pedestrians push the button on the far side of the crossing", "When the pedestrians have cleared the crossing"], "answer": "When the pedestrians have cleared the crossing"},
{"id": "43697", "question": "You’re approaching a mini-roundabout. What should you do if a long vehicle in front signals left but positions over to the right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-mini-roundabout-what-should-you-do-if-a-long-vehicle-in-front-signals-left-but-positions-over-to-the-right/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Sound your horn", "Follow the same course as the lorry", "Overtake on the left", "Keep well back"], "answer": "Keep well back"},
{"id": "43985", "question": "You’re approaching a junction where the traffic lights aren’t working. What should you do when a police officer gives this signal?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2407.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-junction-where-the-traffic-lights-arent-working-what-should-you-do-when-a-police-officer-gives-this-signal-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Turn left only", "Stop at the stop line", "Continue ahead only", "Turn right only"], "answer": "Stop at the stop line"},
{"id": "44062", "question": "You’re approaching a crossroads. What should you do if the traffic lights have failed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-crossroads-what-should-you-do-if-the-traffic-lights-have-failed/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Be prepared to stop for any traffic", "Brake sharply to a stop before looking", "Be prepared to brake sharply to a stop", "Brake and stop only for large vehicles"], "answer": "Be prepared to stop for any traffic"},
{"id": "43728", "question": "You’re approaching a busy junction. What should you do when, at the last moment, you realise you’re in the wrong lane?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-approaching-a-busy-junction-what-should-you-do-when-at-the-last-moment-you-realise-youre-in-the-wrong-lane-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Stop until the area has cleared", "Continue in that lane", "Force your way into the lane you need", "Use arm signals to help you change lane"], "answer": "Continue in that lane"},
{"id": "47583", "question": "You’re about to start a journey towing a trailer. What should you do if you notice that a light on your trailer is not working?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-start-a-journey-towing-a-trailer-what-should-you-do-if-you-notice-that-a-light-on-your-trailer-is-not-working/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Disconnect the trailer electrical coupling before continuing with your journey", "Book the trailer in for repair before continuing with your journey", "Continue with your journey because the lights on your car are working", "Repair the fault before continuing with your journey"], "answer": "Repair the fault before continuing with your journey"},
{"id": "44261", "question": "You’re about to start a journey in freezing weather. What part of your vehicle should you clear of ice and snow?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-start-a-journey-in-freezing-weather-what-part-of-your-vehicle-should-you-clear-of-ice-and-snow/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["The bumper", "The windows", "The aerial", "The boot"], "answer": "The windows"},
{"id": "44287", "question": "You’re about to reverse into a side road. What should you do if a pedestrian is waiting to cross behind your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-reverse-into-a-side-road-what-should-you-do-if-a-pedestrian-is-waiting-to-cross-behind-your-car/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Wave to the pedestrian to stop", "Sound your horn to warn the pedestrian", "Reverse before the pedestrian starts to cross", "Give way to the pedestrian"], "answer": "Give way to the pedestrian"},
{"id": "43959", "question": "You’re about to overtake. What should you do when you see this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2362.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-overtake-what-should-you-do-when-you-see-this-sign-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Move to the right to get a better view", "Overtake the other driver as quickly as possible", "Switch your headlights on before overtaking", "Hold back until you can see clearly ahead"], "answer": "Hold back until you can see clearly ahead"},
{"id": "43693", "question": "You’re about to overtake a slow-moving motorcyclist. Which sign would make you take special care?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-overtake-a-slow-moving-motorcyclist-which-sign-would-make-you-take-special-care/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2176d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2176c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2176b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2176a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2176a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44203", "question": "You’re about to overtake a cyclist. Why should you leave them as much room as you would give to a car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-overtake-a-cyclist-why-should-you-leave-them-as-much-room-as-you-would-give-to-a-car/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["The cyclist might get off their bicycle", "The cyclist might be unsettled if you pass too near them", "The cyclist might have to make a left turn", "The cyclist might speed up"], "answer": "The cyclist might be unsettled if you pass too near them"},
{"id": "47544", "question": "You’re about to overtake a cyclist on a road that has a 30 mph speed limit. How much room should you leave them as you overtake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-overtake-a-cyclist-on-a-road-that-has-a-30-mph-speed-limit-how-much-room-should-you-leave-them-as-you-overtake/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["At least a car's width", "At least as much room as you would if you were overtaking a car", "At least a car's length", "At least 2 car widths"], "answer": "At least as much room as you would if you were overtaking a car"},
{"id": "44265", "question": "You’re about to go down a steep hill. What should you do to control the speed of your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-go-down-a-steep-hill-what-should-you-do-to-control-the-speed-of-your-vehicle-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Select a high gear and use the brakes carefully", "Select a low gear and avoid using the brakes", "Select a high gear and use the brakes firmly", "Select a low gear and use the brakes carefully"], "answer": "Select a low gear and use the brakes carefully"},
{"id": "44385", "question": "You’re about to drive your car. What should you do if you can’t find the glasses you need to wear?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-drive-your-car-what-should-you-do-if-you-cant-find-the-glasses-you-need-to-wear/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Drive home slowly, keeping to quiet roads", "Find a way of getting home without driving", "Drive home at night, so that the lights will help you", "Borrow a friend's glasses and use those"], "answer": "Find a way of getting home without driving"},
{"id": "44284", "question": "You’re about to drive home. What should you do if you feel very tired and have a severe headache?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/youre-about-to-drive-home-what-should-you-do-if-you-feel-very-tired-and-have-a-severe-headache-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Wait until you're fit and well before driving", "Drive home if you can stay awake for the journey", "Wait for a short time, then drive home slowly", "Drive home, but take a tablet for headaches"], "answer": "Wait until you're fit and well before driving"},
{"id": "44052", "question": "Your vehicle is stationary. When may you use its horn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-is-stationary-when-may-you-use-its-horn-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["When the road is blocked by queuing traffic", "When signalling that you've just arrived", "When another road user poses a danger", "When it's used only briefly"], "answer": "When another road user poses a danger"},
{"id": "44355", "question": "Your vehicle has stalled in the middle of a level crossing. What should you do if the warning bells start to ring while you’re trying to restart the engine?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-has-stalled-in-the-middle-of-a-level-crossing-what-should-you-do-if-the-warning-bells-start-to-ring-while-youre-trying-to-restart-the-engine/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Run down the track to warn the signal operator", "Push the vehicle clear of the crossing", "Carry on trying to restart the engine", "Get out of the car and clear of the crossing"], "answer": "Get out of the car and clear of the crossing"},
{"id": "44391", "question": "Your vehicle has broken down on a motorway. What should you do if you aren’t able to get onto the hard shoulder?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-has-broken-down-on-a-motorway-what-should-you-do-if-you-arent-able-to-get-onto-the-hard-shoulder/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Attempt to repair your vehicle quickly", "Stand behind your vehicle to warn others", "Stop the traffic behind and ask for help", "Switch on your hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Switch on your hazard warning lights"},
{"id": "44006", "question": "Your vehicle has broken down on a motorway. In which direction should you walk to find the nearest emergency telephone?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-has-broken-down-on-a-motorway-in-which-direction-should-you-walk-to-find-the-nearest-emergency-telephone/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["In the direction shown on the marker posts", "In the direction of the nearest exit", "Facing oncoming traffic", "With the traffic flow"], "answer": "In the direction shown on the marker posts"},
{"id": "43711", "question": "Your vehicle broke down on the hard shoulder of a motorway, but has now been repaired. How should you rejoin the main carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-broke-down-on-the-hard-shoulder-of-a-motorway-but-has-now-been-repaired-how-should-you-rejoin-the-main-carriageway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Move out onto the carriageway, then build up your speed", "Wait on the hard shoulder until someone flashes their headlights at you", "Gain speed on the hard shoulder before moving out onto the carriageway", "Move out onto the carriageway using your hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Gain speed on the hard shoulder before moving out onto the carriageway"},
{"id": "43710", "question": "Your vehicle breaks down on a motorway and you need to call for help. Why might it be better to use an emergency roadside telephone rather than a mobile phone?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-breaks-down-on-a-motorway-and-you-need-to-call-for-help-why-might-it-be-better-to-use-an-emergency-roadside-telephone-rather-than-a-mobile-phone/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Using a mobile phone will distract other drivers", "It allows easy location by the emergency services", "It connects you to a local garage", "Mobile phones don't work on motorways"], "answer": "It allows easy location by the emergency services"},
{"id": "44480", "question": "Your vehicle breaks down on a motorway and you manage to stop on the hard shoulder. What should you do if you use your mobile phone to call for help?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-vehicle-breaks-down-on-a-motorway-and-you-manage-to-stop-on-the-hard-shoulder-what-should-you-do-if-you-use-your-mobile-phone-to-call-for-help/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Check your location from the nearest marker posts beside the hard shoulder", "Stand at the rear of the vehicle while making the call", "Phone a friend and ask them to come and collect you", "Wait in the car for the emergency services to arrive"], "answer": "Check your location from the nearest marker posts beside the hard shoulder"},
{"id": "44188", "question": "Your insurer will issue you with an insurance certificate. When must you produce this document for inspection?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-insurer-will-issue-you-with-an-insurance-certificate-when-must-you-produce-this-document-for-inspection/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When your vehicle is having an MOT test", "When making a SORN", "When a police officer asks you for it", "When buying or selling a vehicle"], "answer": "When a police officer asks you for it"},
{"id": "44487", "question": "Your car requires an MOT certificate. When is it legal to drive it without an MOT certificate?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-car-requires-an-mot-certificate-when-is-it-legal-to-drive-it-without-an-mot-certificate-3/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Up to seven days after the old certificate has run out", "When driving the car with the owner's permission", "When driving to an appointment at an MOT centre", "When driving to an MOT centre to arrange an appointment"], "answer": "When driving to an appointment at an MOT centre"},
{"id": "44330", "question": "Your car needs to pass an MOT test. What may be invalidated if you drive the car without a current MOT certificate?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-car-needs-to-pass-an-mot-test-what-may-be-invalidated-if-you-drive-the-car-without-a-current-mot-certificate-3/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["The vehicle insurance", "The vehicle tax", "The vehicle registration document", "The vehicle service record"], "answer": "The vehicle insurance"},
{"id": "44309", "question": "Your car gets a puncture while you’re driving on the motorway. What should you do when you’ve stopped on the hard shoulder?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-car-gets-a-puncture-while-youre-driving-on-the-motorway-what-should-you-do-when-youve-stopped-on-the-hard-shoulder/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Use an emergency telephone and call for help", "Carefully change the wheel yourself", "Try to wave down another vehicle for help", "Only change the wheel if you have a passenger to help you"], "answer": "Use an emergency telephone and call for help"},
{"id": "44332", "question": "Your car breaks down on a level crossing. What’s the first thing you should do?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/your-car-breaks-down-on-a-level-crossing-whats-the-first-thing-you-should-do/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Tell drivers behind what's happened", "Stay in your car until you're told to move", "Leave your vehicle and get everyone clear", "Walk down the track and signal the next train"], "answer": "Leave your vehicle and get everyone clear"},
{"id": "43652", "question": "You wish to turn right ahead. Why should you take up the correct position in good time?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-wish-to-turn-right-ahead-why-should-you-take-up-the-correct-position-in-good-time-4/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["To allow drivers to pass you on the right", "To give a better view into the road that you're joining", "To help other road users know what you intend to do", "To allow other drivers to pull out in front of you"], "answer": "To help other road users know what you intend to do"},
{"id": "44508", "question": "You wish to tow a trailer. Where would you find the maximum noseweight for your vehicle’s tow hitch?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-wish-to-tow-a-trailer-where-would-you-find-the-maximum-noseweight-for-your-vehicles-tow-hitch/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["In the vehicle handbook", "In your licence documents", "In your vehicle registration certificate", "In The Highway Code"], "answer": "In the vehicle handbook"},
{"id": "44295", "question": "You want to turn right from a main road into a side road. What should you do just before turning?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-turn-right-from-a-main-road-into-a-side-road-what-should-you-do-just-before-turning-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Select first gear", "Check for traffic overtaking on your right", "Cancel your right-turn signal", "Stop and set the parking brake"], "answer": "Check for traffic overtaking on your right"},
{"id": "44290", "question": "You want to turn right from a junction. What should you do if your view is restricted by parked vehicles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-turn-right-from-a-junction-what-should-you-do-if-your-view-is-restricted-by-parked-vehicles-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Sound your horn and pull out if there's no reply", "Move out quickly, but be prepared to stop", "Stop, then move forward slowly until you have a clear view", "Stop, get out and look along the main road to check"], "answer": "Stop, then move forward slowly until you have a clear view"},
{"id": "44354", "question": "You want to turn right at a box junction. What should you do if there’s oncoming traffic?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-turn-right-at-a-box-junction-what-should-you-do-if-theres-oncoming-traffic-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Wait in the box junction if your exit is clear", "Drive on; you can't turn right at a box junction", "Drive slowly into the box junction when signalled by oncoming traffic", "Wait before the junction until it's clear of all traffic"], "answer": "Wait in the box junction if your exit is clear"},
{"id": "44422", "question": "You want to turn left at this junction. What should you do if your view of the main road is restricted?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1576.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-turn-left-at-this-junction-what-should-you-do-if-your-view-of-the-main-road-is-restricted/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Stop and apply the parking brake even if the road is clear", "Approach slowly and edge out until you can see more clearly", "Stay well back and wait to see if anything comes", "Build up your speed so that you can emerge quickly"], "answer": "Approach slowly and edge out until you can see more clearly"},
{"id": "44286", "question": "You want to reverse into a side road. What should you do if you aren’t sure that the area behind your car is clear?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-reverse-into-a-side-road-what-should-you-do-if-you-arent-sure-that-the-area-behind-your-car-is-clear/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Get out and check", "Check the mirrors only", "Look through the rear window only", "Carry on, assuming it's clear"], "answer": "Get out and check"},
{"id": "44525", "question": "You want to put a rear-facing baby seat on the front passenger seat. What must you do if the passenger seat is protected by a frontal airbag?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-put-a-rear-facing-baby-seat-on-the-front-passenger-seat-what-must-you-do-if-the-passenger-seat-is-protected-by-a-frontal-airbag/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Put the child in an adult seat belt", "Ask a passenger to hold the baby", "Deactivate the airbag", "Turn the seat to face sideways"], "answer": "Deactivate the airbag"},
{"id": "44314", "question": "You want to park and you see this sign. What should you do on the days and times shown?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1213.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-want-to-park-and-you-see-this-sign-what-should-you-do-on-the-days-and-times-shown-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Park on yellow lines and pay", "Park in a bay and not pay", "Park in a bay and pay", "Park on yellow lines and not pay"], "answer": "Park in a bay and pay"},
{"id": "44339", "question": "You take some cough medicine given to you by a friend. What should you do before driving your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-take-some-cough-medicine-given-to-you-by-a-friend-what-should-you-do-before-driving-your-car/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Check the label to see if the medicine will affect your driving", "Ask your friend if taking the medicine affected their driving", "Drink some strong coffee one hour before driving", "Drive a short distance to see if the medicine is affecting your driving"], "answer": "Check the label to see if the medicine will affect your driving"},
{"id": "44171", "question": "You stop on the hard shoulder of a motorway and use the emergency telephone. Where’s the best place to wait for help to arrive?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-stop-on-the-hard-shoulder-of-a-motorway-and-use-the-emergency-telephone-wheres-the-best-place-to-wait-for-help-to-arrive-4/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["On the hard shoulder", "Well away from the carriageway", "Next to the phone", "With your vehicle"], "answer": "Well away from the carriageway"},
{"id": "44394", "question": "You service your own vehicle. How should you dispose of the old engine oil?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-service-your-own-vehicle-how-should-you-dispose-of-the-old-engine-oil/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Take it to a local-authority site", "Tip it into a hole in the ground", "Pour it down a drain", "Put it in your dustbin"], "answer": "Take it to a local-authority site"},
{"id": "44129", "question": "You see this amber traffic light ahead. Which light, or lights, will come on next?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2758.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-see-this-amber-traffic-light-ahead-which-light-or-lights-will-come-on-next-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Green and amber together", "Red alone", "Red and amber together", "Green alone"], "answer": "Red alone"},
{"id": "44007", "question": "You see these double white lines along the centre of the road. When may you park on the left?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2528.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-see-these-double-white-lines-along-the-centre-of-the-road-when-may-you-park-on-the-left/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["To pick up or set down passengers", "If the line nearest to you is broken", "During daylight hours only", "When there are no yellow lines"], "answer": "To pick up or set down passengers"},
{"id": "43681", "question": "You see a pedestrian carrying a white stick that also has a red band. What does this mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2136.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-see-a-pedestrian-carrying-a-white-stick-that-also-has-a-red-band-what-does-this-mean/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["They're deaf", "They have limited mobility", "They're deaf and blind", "They're blind"], "answer": "They're deaf and blind"},
{"id": "44017", "question": "You see a horse rider as you approach a roundabout. What should you do if they’re signalling right but keeping well to the left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-see-a-horse-rider-as-you-approach-a-roundabout-what-should-you-do-if-theyre-signalling-right-but-keeping-well-to-the-left-4/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Stay well back", "Cut in front of them", "Keep close to them", "Proceed as normal"], "answer": "Stay well back"},
{"id": "44151", "question": "You plan your route before starting a journey. Why should you also plan an alternative route?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-plan-your-route-before-starting-a-journey-why-should-you-also-plan-an-alternative-route/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Your original route may be blocked", "You may find you have to pay a congestion charge", "Your maps may have different scales", "You may get held up by a tractor"], "answer": "Your original route may be blocked"},
{"id": "44089", "question": "You need to top up your battery with distilled water. What level should you fill it to?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-need-to-top-up-your-battery-with-distilled-water-what-level-should-you-fill-it-to/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Just below the cell plates", "Halfway up the battery", "Just above the cell plates", "The top of the battery"], "answer": "Just above the cell plates"},
{"id": "44397", "question": "You need glasses to read a vehicle number plate at the required distance. When must you wear them?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-need-glasses-to-read-a-vehicle-number-plate-at-the-required-distance-when-must-you-wear-them/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Whenever you're driving", "When you think it's necessary", "Only in bad weather conditions", "Only at night time"], "answer": "Whenever you're driving"},
{"id": "44533", "question": "You lose control of your car and damage a garden wall. What must you do if the property owner isn’t available?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-lose-control-of-your-car-and-damage-a-garden-wall-what-must-you-do-if-the-property-owner-isnt-available/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Report the incident to your insurance company when you get home", "Go back to tell the house owner the next day", "Find someone in the area to tell them about it immediately", "Report the incident to the police within 24 hours"], "answer": "Report the incident to the police within 24 hours"},
{"id": "44272", "question": "You intend to turn left at the traffic lights. What should you do just before turning?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1095.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-intend-to-turn-left-at-the-traffic-lights-what-should-you-do-just-before-turning-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Move out to the right", "Check your right mirror", "Move up closer to the car ahead", "Check for bicycles on your left"], "answer": "Check for bicycles on your left"},
{"id": "44522", "question": "You have to make an unexpected journey. You’re carrying a five-year-old child on the back seat of your car. They’re under 1.35 metres (4 feet 5 inches) tall. How should you seat them if a correct child restraint isn’t available?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-have-to-make-an-unexpected-journey-youre-carrying-a-five-year-old-child-on-the-back-seat-of-your-car-theyre-under-1-35-metres-4-feet-5-inches-tall-how-should-you-seat-them-if-a-correct-chil/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Between two other children", "Using an adult seat belt", "Sharing a belt with an adult", "Behind the passenger seat"], "answer": "Using an adult seat belt"},
{"id": "44152", "question": "You have to arrive on time for an appointment. How should you plan for the journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-have-to-arrive-on-time-for-an-appointment-how-should-you-plan-for-the-journey/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Avoid roads with the national speed limit", "Prevent other drivers from overtaking", "Allow plenty of time for the trip", "Plan to travel at busy times"], "answer": "Allow plenty of time for the trip"},
{"id": "47547", "question": "You have stopped in an emergency area. What must you do before you rejoin the carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-have-stopped-in-an-emergency-area-what-must-you-do-before-you-rejoin-the-carriageway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Move away with your hazard lights on", "Use the emergency telephone", "Give an arm signal as you are moving off", "Switch on your vehicle's headlights"], "answer": "Use the emergency telephone"},
{"id": "44215", "question": "You arrive at the scene of a motorcycle crash. The rider is injured. When should their helmet be removed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-arrive-at-the-scene-of-a-motorcycle-crash-the-rider-is-injured-when-should-their-helmet-be-removed-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Only when the motorcyclist asks", "Always, unless they're in shock", "Always straight away", "Only when it's essential"], "answer": "Only when it's essential"},
{"id": "44220", "question": "You arrive at the scene of a motorcycle crash. No other vehicle is involved. The rider is unconscious and lying in the middle of the road. What’s the first thing you should do at the scene?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-arrive-at-the-scene-of-a-motorcycle-crash-no-other-vehicle-is-involved-the-rider-is-unconscious-and-lying-in-the-middle-of-the-road-whats-the-first-thing-you-should-do-at-the-scene-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Move the rider out of the road", "Warn other traffic", "Give the rider reassurance", "Clear the road of debris"], "answer": "Warn other traffic"},
{"id": "44179", "question": "You arrive at the scene of a crash where someone is bleeding heavily from a wound in their arm. Nothing is embedded in the wound. What could you do to help?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-arrive-at-the-scene-of-a-crash-where-someone-is-bleeding-heavily-from-a-wound-in-their-arm-nothing-is-embedded-in-the-wound-what-could-you-do-to-help/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Walk them around and keep them talking", "Get them a drink", "Apply pressure over the wound", "Dab the wound"], "answer": "Apply pressure over the wound"},
{"id": "44216", "question": "You arrive at an incident. There’s no danger from fire or further collisions and the emergency services have been called. What’s your first priority when attending to an unconscious motorcyclist?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-arrive-at-an-incident-theres-no-danger-from-fire-or-further-collisions-and-the-emergency-services-have-been-called-whats-your-first-priority-when-attending-to-an-unconscious-motorcyclist/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Check whether they're breathing normally", "Check whether they're bleeding", "Check whether they have any bruising", "Check whether they have any broken bones"], "answer": "Check whether they're breathing normally"},
{"id": "44224", "question": "You arrive at an incident. A pedestrian is bleeding heavily from a leg wound. The leg isn’t broken and there’s nothing in the wound. How could you help?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/you-arrive-at-an-incident-a-pedestrian-is-bleeding-heavily-from-a-leg-wound-the-leg-isnt-broken-and-theres-nothing-in-the-wound-how-could-you-help/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Give them a warm drink", "Keep the casualty's legs flat on the ground", "Dab the wound to stop the bleeding", "Apply firm pressure over the wound"], "answer": "Apply firm pressure over the wound"},
{"id": "44365", "question": "Why would you fit chains to your wheels?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-would-you-fit-chains-to-your-wheels-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To help prevent skidding in deep snow", "To help prevent the brakes locking", "To help prevent damage to the road surface", "To help prevent wear to the tyres"], "answer": "To help prevent skidding in deep snow"},
{"id": "44160", "question": "Why should you use your mirrors when you see a hazard ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-use-your-mirrors-when-you-see-a-hazard-ahead/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["To check what's happening on the road ahead", "Because you'll need to brake sharply and stop", "To assess how your actions will affect the traffic behind", "Because you'll need to accelerate out of danger"], "answer": "To assess how your actions will affect the traffic behind"},
{"id": "44438", "question": "Why should you try and park in a secure car park?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-try-and-park-in-a-secure-car-park/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["It doesn't cost anything to park here", "It stops the car being exposed to bad weather", "It makes it easy to find your car", "It helps deter thieves"], "answer": "It helps deter thieves"},
{"id": "44155", "question": "Why should you test your brakes after this hazard?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2821.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-test-your-brakes-after-this-hazard/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["You'll have just crossed a long bridge", "Your brakes will be wet", "You'll be on a slippery road", "You'll be going down a long hill"], "answer": "Your brakes will be wet"},
{"id": "44243", "question": "Why should you switch your headlights on when it first starts to get dark?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-switch-your-headlights-on-when-it-first-starts-to-get-dark/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Because the street lights are lit", "To make your dials easier to see", "So others can see you more easily", "So that you blend in with other drivers"], "answer": "So others can see you more easily"},
{"id": "44348", "question": "Why should you switch off your rear fog lights when the fog has cleared?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-switch-off-your-rear-fog-lights-when-the-fog-has-cleared-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To allow your headlights to work", "To prevent dazzling drivers behind", "To stop the engine losing power", "To stop draining the battery"], "answer": "To prevent dazzling drivers behind"},
{"id": "44099", "question": "Why should you slow down as you approach this hazard?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2724.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-slow-down-as-you-approach-this-hazard/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Because it's hard to see to the right", "Because of approaching traffic", "Because of animals crossing", "Because of the level crossing"], "answer": "Because of the level crossing"},
{"id": "44156", "question": "Why should you reduce your speed when you’re driving or riding in fog?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-reduce-your-speed-when-youre-driving-or-riding-in-fog/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["The engine will take longer to warm up", "You'll be dazzled by other headlights", "The brakes don't work as well", "It's more difficult to see what's ahead"], "answer": "It's more difficult to see what's ahead"},
{"id": "44273", "question": "Why should you reduce your speed here?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1096.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-reduce-your-speed-here/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["A staggered junction is ahead", "The road narrows ahead", "The road surface changes ahead", "A low bridge is ahead"], "answer": "A staggered junction is ahead"},
{"id": "43640", "question": "Why should you never wave people across at pedestrian crossings?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-never-wave-people-across-at-pedestrian-crossings-4/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["They may not be looking", "Another vehicle may be coming", "It's safer for you to carry on", "They may not be ready to cross"], "answer": "Another vehicle may be coming"},
{"id": "44427", "question": "Why should you make sure that your indicators are cancelled after turning at a junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-make-sure-that-your-indicators-are-cancelled-after-turning-at-a-junction/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["To avoid dazzling other road users", "To avoid misleading other road users", "To avoid damage to the indicator relay", "To avoid flattening the battery"], "answer": "To avoid misleading other road users"},
{"id": "43686", "question": "Why should you look carefully for motorcyclists and cyclists at junctions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-look-carefully-for-motorcyclists-and-cyclists-at-junctions/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["They may slow down to let you turn", "They may want to turn into the side road", "They might not see you turn", "They're harder to see"], "answer": "They're harder to see"},
{"id": "44047", "question": "Why should you keep well to the left as you approach a right-hand bend?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2624.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-keep-well-to-the-left-as-you-approach-a-right-hand-bend/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["To be positioned safely if you skid", "To improve your view of the road", "To let faster traffic from behind overtake", "To overcome the effect of the road's slope"], "answer": "To improve your view of the road"},
{"id": "44387", "question": "Why should you check the information leaflet before taking any medicine?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-check-the-information-leaflet-before-taking-any-medicine/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Some types of medicine can affect your ability to drive safely", "You may have to let your insurance company know about the medicine", "The medicine you take may affect your hearing", "Drug companies want customer feedback on their products"], "answer": "Some types of medicine can affect your ability to drive safely"},
{"id": "43676", "question": "Why should you check for motorcyclists just before turning right into a side road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-check-for-motorcyclists-just-before-turning-right-into-a-side-road-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["They may be overtaking on your left", "They may be emerging from the side road", "They may be following you closely", "They may be overtaking on your right"], "answer": "They may be overtaking on your right"},
{"id": "44173", "question": "Why should you be cautious when going past this bus waiting at a bus stop?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2848.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-be-cautious-when-going-past-this-bus-waiting-at-a-bus-stop/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["There's a zebra crossing ahead", "People may cross the road in front of it", "There are driveways on the left", "The road surface will be slippery"], "answer": "People may cross the road in front of it"},
{"id": "44398", "question": "Why should you allow extra room while overtaking a motorcyclist on a windy day?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-you-allow-extra-room-while-overtaking-a-motorcyclist-on-a-windy-day/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["The rider may stop suddenly", "The rider may turn off suddenly to get out of the wind", "The rider may be blown in front of you", "The rider may be travelling faster than normal"], "answer": "The rider may be blown in front of you"},
{"id": "44011", "question": "Why should these road markings be kept clear?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2545.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-these-road-markings-be-kept-clear/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To allow children to be dropped off at school", "To allow teachers to park", "To allow children to see and be seen when they're crossing the road", "To allow children to be picked up after school"], "answer": "To allow children to see and be seen when they're crossing the road"},
{"id": "44516", "question": "Why should the junction on the left be kept clear?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1748.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-the-junction-on-the-left-be-kept-clear-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["To allow vehicles to make a U-turn", "To allow vehicles to park", "To allow vehicles to enter and emerge", "To allow the bus to reverse"], "answer": "To allow vehicles to enter and emerge"},
{"id": "44424", "question": "Why should drivers be more careful on roads where trams also operate?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-should-drivers-be-more-careful-on-roads-where-trams-also-operate/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Because trams don't have lights", "Because trams can't steer to avoid obstructions", "Because trams can't stop for cars", "Because trams don't have a horn"], "answer": "Because trams can't steer to avoid obstructions"},
{"id": "43667", "question": "Why must you take great care when emerging from this junction?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2100.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-must-you-take-great-care-when-emerging-from-this-junction/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The kerbs are high", "The view is restricted", "The road surface is poor", "The footpath is narrow"], "answer": "The view is restricted"},
{"id": "44513", "question": "Why is travelling in neutral for long distances (known as coasting) bad driving technique?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-travelling-in-neutral-for-long-distances-known-as-coasting-bad-driving-technique/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["It will make the engine stall", "There won't be any engine braking", "It will cause the car to skid", "The engine will run faster"], "answer": "There won't be any engine braking"},
{"id": "44400", "question": "Why is it particularly important to check your vehicle before making a long motorway journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-particularly-important-to-check-your-vehicle-before-making-a-long-motorway-journey/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Continuous high speeds increase the risk of your vehicle breaking down", "Motorway services areas don't deal with breakdowns", "You'll have to do more harsh braking on motorways", "The road surface will wear down the tyres faster"], "answer": "Continuous high speeds increase the risk of your vehicle breaking down"},
{"id": "44193", "question": "Why is it more difficult to overtake a large vehicle than a car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-more-difficult-to-overtake-a-large-vehicle-than-a-car-4/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["It will take longer to overtake a large vehicle", "It will take longer for a large vehicle to accelerate", "A large vehicle will be fitted with a speed limiter", "A large vehicle will have air brakes"], "answer": "It will take longer to overtake a large vehicle"},
{"id": "44254", "question": "Why is it important to wear suitable shoes when you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-important-to-wear-suitable-shoes-when-youre-driving/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To enable you to walk for assistance if you break down", "To maintain control of the pedals", "To enable you to adjust your seat", "To prevent wear on the pedals"], "answer": "To maintain control of the pedals"},
{"id": "44023", "question": "Why is it important to make full use of the slip road as you join a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-important-to-make-full-use-of-the-slip-road-as-you-join-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Because you can continue on the hard shoulder", "To allow you direct access to the overtaking lanes", "To allow you to fit safely into the traffic flow in the left-hand lane", "Because there's space available to turn round if you need to"], "answer": "To allow you to fit safely into the traffic flow in the left-hand lane"},
{"id": "44478", "question": "Why is it dangerous to leave rear fog lights switched on after the fog has cleared?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-dangerous-to-leave-rear-fog-lights-switched-on-after-the-fog-has-cleared/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Electrical systems could be overloaded", "They may be confused with brake lights", "Direction indicators may not work properly", "The bulbs would fail"], "answer": "They may be confused with brake lights"},
{"id": "43641", "question": "Why is it dangerous to drive too close to the vehicle ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-dangerous-to-drive-too-close-to-the-vehicle-ahead/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Your engine will overheat", "Your view of the road ahead will be restricted", "Your satnav will be confused", "Your mirrors will need adjusting"], "answer": "Your view of the road ahead will be restricted"},
{"id": "44499", "question": "Why is it bad technique to coast when you’re driving downhill?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-bad-technique-to-coast-when-youre-driving-downhill/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["The tyres will wear more quickly", "The engine will overheat", "The fuel consumption will increase", "The vehicle will gain speed more quickly"], "answer": "The vehicle will gain speed more quickly"},
{"id": "44149", "question": "Why is it a good idea to plan your journey to avoid busy times?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-it-a-good-idea-to-plan-your-journey-to-avoid-busy-times-4/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["You'll have an easier journey", "Your journey time will be longer", "You'll have a more stressful journey", "It will cause more traffic congestion"], "answer": "You'll have an easier journey"},
{"id": "43677", "question": "Why is a toucan crossing different from other crossings?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-is-a-toucan-crossing-different-from-other-crossings-5/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Moped riders can use it", "Cyclists can use it", "It's controlled by a traffic warden", "It's controlled by two flashing lights"], "answer": "Cyclists can use it"},
{"id": "43656", "question": "Why have ‘red routes’ been introduced in major cities?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-have-red-routes-been-introduced-in-major-cities-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To raise the speed limits", "To allow lorries to load more freely", "To provide better parking", "To help the traffic flow"], "answer": "To help the traffic flow"},
{"id": "43982", "question": "Why does this junction have a ‘stop’ sign and a stop line on the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2402.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-does-this-junction-have-a-stop-sign-and-a-stop-line-on-the-road/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Speed on the major road is derestricted", "The junction is on a downhill gradient", "Visibility along the major road is restricted", "It's a busy junction"], "answer": "Visibility along the major road is restricted"},
{"id": "43689", "question": "Why do motorcyclists wear bright clothing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-do-motorcyclists-wear-bright-clothing/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To make them more visible", "It helps keep them cool in summer", "They must do so by law", "The colours are popular"], "answer": "To make them more visible"},
{"id": "43688", "question": "Why do motorcyclists use dipped headlights in daylight?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-do-motorcyclists-use-dipped-headlights-in-daylight/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["So that the rider can be seen more easily", "To improve the rider's vision", "The rider is inviting you to proceed", "To stop the battery overcharging"], "answer": "So that the rider can be seen more easily"},
{"id": "43690", "question": "Why do motorcyclists often look round over their right shoulder just before turning right?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-do-motorcyclists-often-look-round-over-their-right-shoulder-just-before-turning-right/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To check for traffic in their blind area", "It helps them balance as they turn", "To listen for traffic behind them", "Motorcycles don't have mirrors"], "answer": "To check for traffic in their blind area"},
{"id": "44395", "question": "Why do MOT tests include an exhaust emission test?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-do-mot-tests-include-an-exhaust-emission-test/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To make sure diesel and petrol engines emit the same fumes", "To help protect the environment against pollution", "To discover which fuel supplier is used the most", "To recover the cost of expensive garage equipment"], "answer": "To help protect the environment against pollution"},
{"id": "44323", "question": "Why could it be dangerous to reverse from a side road into a main road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-could-it-be-dangerous-to-reverse-from-a-side-road-into-a-main-road/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Your reverse sensors will beep", "Your reversing lights will be hidden", "Your mirrors will need adjusting", "Your view will be restricted"], "answer": "Your view will be restricted"},
{"id": "44377", "question": "Why could it be dangerous to keep the clutch down, or select neutral, for long periods of time while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-could-it-be-dangerous-to-keep-the-clutch-down-or-select-neutral-for-long-periods-of-time-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["You'll have less steering and braking control", "Engine damage may be caused", "It will wear tyres out more quickly", "Fuel spillage will occur"], "answer": "You'll have less steering and braking control"},
{"id": "44433", "question": "Why are vehicles fitted with rear fog lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-are-vehicles-fitted-with-rear-fog-lights-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To show when they've broken down in a dangerous position", "To make them more visible when driving at high speed", "To warn drivers following closely to drop back", "To make them more visible in thick fog"], "answer": "To make them more visible in thick fog"},
{"id": "44075", "question": "Why are vehicle mirrors often slightly curved (convex)?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-are-vehicle-mirrors-often-slightly-curved-convex/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["They make it easier to judge the speed of the traffic behind", "They totally cover blind spots", "They make the traffic behind look bigger", "They give a wider field of vision"], "answer": "They give a wider field of vision"},
{"id": "43638", "question": "Why are these yellow lines painted across the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2009.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-are-these-yellow-lines-painted-across-the-road-4/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["To make you aware of your speed", "To tell you the distance to the roundabout", "To help you choose the correct lane", "To help you keep the correct separation distance"], "answer": "To make you aware of your speed"},
{"id": "44100", "question": "Why are place names painted on the road surface?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/why-are-place-names-painted-on-the-road-surface-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["To prevent you from changing lanes", "To help you select the correct lane in good time", "To restrict the flow of traffic", "To warn of oncoming traffic"], "answer": "To help you select the correct lane in good time"},
{"id": "44405", "question": "Who’s responsible for paying the vehicle tax?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whos-responsible-for-paying-the-vehicle-tax/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["The registered keeper of the vehicle", "The driver of the vehicle", "The car dealer", "The Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency (DVLA)"], "answer": "The registered keeper of the vehicle"},
{"id": "44410", "question": "Who’s responsible for making sure that a vehicle isn’t overloaded?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whos-responsible-for-making-sure-that-a-vehicle-isnt-overloaded-3/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["The person who loaded the vehicle", "The owner of the items being carried", "The driver of the vehicle", "The licensing authority"], "answer": "The driver of the vehicle"},
{"id": "44164", "question": "Who’s legally responsible for ensuring that a vehicle registration certificate (V5C) is updated?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whos-legally-responsible-for-ensuring-that-a-vehicle-registration-certificate-v5c-is-updated-3/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["The vehicle manufacturer", "The registered vehicle keeper", "The licensing authority", "Your insurance company"], "answer": "The registered vehicle keeper"},
{"id": "43648", "question": "Who should obey diamond-shaped traffic signs?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2036.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/who-should-obey-diamond-shaped-traffic-signs-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Lorry drivers", "Tram drivers", "Bus drivers", "Taxi drivers"], "answer": "Tram drivers"},
{"id": "44178", "question": "Who may use toucan crossings?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/who-may-use-toucan-crossings-3/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Only cyclists", "Cyclists and pedestrians", "Motorcyclists and cyclists", "Motorcyclists and pedestrians"], "answer": "Cyclists and pedestrians"},
{"id": "43734", "question": "Who is authorised to signal you to stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/who-is-authorised-to-signal-you-to-stop/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["A pedestrian", "A police officer", "A motorcyclist", "A bus driver"], "answer": "A police officer"},
{"id": "43975", "question": "Who has priority when traffic lights are out of order?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/who-has-priority-when-traffic-lights-are-out-of-order-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Traffic turning left", "Traffic going straight on", "Traffic turning right", "Nobody"], "answer": "Nobody"},
{"id": "44043", "question": "Who has priority at an unmarked crossroads?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/who-has-priority-at-an-unmarked-crossroads-4/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["The smaller vehicle", "No-one has priority", "The faster vehicle", "The larger vehicle"], "answer": "No-one has priority"},
{"id": "43708", "question": "Which vehicles should use the left-hand lane on a three-lane motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicles-should-use-the-left-hand-lane-on-a-three-lane-motorway-4/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Emergency vehicles only", "Any vehicle that isn't overtaking", "Slow vehicles only", "Large vehicles only"], "answer": "Any vehicle that isn't overtaking"},
{"id": "43709", "question": "Which vehicles aren’t allowed to use the right-hand lane of a three-lane motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicles-arent-allowed-to-use-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-three-lane-motorway-2/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Motorcycle and sidecar outfits", "Small delivery vans", "Motorcycles", "Vehicles towing a trailer"], "answer": "Vehicles towing a trailer"},
{"id": "44115", "question": "Which vehicles are prohibited from using the motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicles-are-prohibited-from-using-the-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Motorcycles over 50 cc", "Cars with automatic transmission", "Powered mobility scooters", "Double-deck buses"], "answer": "Powered mobility scooters"},
{"id": "44108", "question": "Which vehicles are least likely to be affected by side wind?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicles-are-least-likely-to-be-affected-by-side-wind/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Motorcyclists", "Cars", "Cyclists", "High-sided vehicles"], "answer": "Cars"},
{"id": "43645", "question": "Which vehicle will use a blue flashing beacon?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicle-will-use-a-blue-flashing-beacon-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Snow plough", "Breakdown recovery", "Bomb disposal", "Motorway maintenance"], "answer": "Bomb disposal"},
{"id": "43685", "question": "Which vehicle should you allow extra room as you overtake them?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicle-should-you-allow-extra-room-as-you-overtake-them/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Lorry", "Tractor", "Road-sweeper", "Bicycle"], "answer": "Bicycle"},
{"id": "43731", "question": "Which vehicle might have to take a different course from normal at a roundabout?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicle-might-have-to-take-a-different-course-from-normal-at-a-roundabout/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Van", "Estate car", "Sports car", "Long vehicle"], "answer": "Long vehicle"},
{"id": "43723", "question": "Which vehicle is most likely to take an unusual course at a roundabout?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-vehicle-is-most-likely-to-take-an-unusual-course-at-a-roundabout-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Long vehicle", "Estate car", "Delivery van", "Milk float"], "answer": "Long vehicle"},
{"id": "43668", "question": "Which type of vehicle should you be ready to give way to as you approach this bridge?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2102.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-type-of-vehicle-should-you-be-ready-to-give-way-to-as-you-approach-this-bridge-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Buses", "Cars", "Bicycles", "Motorcycles"], "answer": "Buses"},
{"id": "43748", "question": "Which type of vehicle does this sign apply to?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2306.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-type-of-vehicle-does-this-sign-apply-to-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Long vehicles", "Wide vehicles", "High vehicles", "Heavy vehicles"], "answer": "High vehicles"},
{"id": "43740", "question": "Which type of sign tells you what you must not do?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-type-of-sign-tells-you-what-you-must-not-do/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2295c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2295b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2295a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2295d.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2295a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44411", "question": "Which type of glasses would make driving at night more difficult?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-type-of-glasses-would-make-driving-at-night-more-difficult/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Bifocal", "Half-moon", "Round", "Tinted"], "answer": "Tinted"},
{"id": "44002", "question": "Which type of crossing allows cyclists to ride across while pedestrians are also crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-type-of-crossing-allows-cyclists-to-ride-across-while-pedestrians-are-also-crossing/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Zebra", "Pelican", "Toucan", "Puffin"], "answer": "Toucan"},
{"id": "44196", "question": "Which sign shows that you’re entering a one-way system?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-shows-that-youre-entering-a-one-way-system/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2885d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2885c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2885a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2885b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2885b.gif'>"},
{"id": "44227", "question": "Which sign shows that a tanker is carrying dangerous goods?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-shows-that-a-tanker-is-carrying-dangerous-goods/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2935d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2935a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2935b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2935c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2935b.gif'>"},
{"id": "44071", "question": "Which sign means you have priority over oncoming vehicles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-you-have-priority-over-oncoming-vehicles-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2674a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2674b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2674d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2674c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2674c.gif'>"},
{"id": "44204", "question": "Which sign means turn left ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-turn-left-ahead/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2897d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2897c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2897a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2897b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2897b.gif'>"},
{"id": "43952", "question": "Which sign means there’s a double bend ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-theres-a-double-bend-ahead/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2351c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2351d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2351a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2351b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2351b.gif'>"},
{"id": "44200", "question": "Which sign means there will be two-way traffic crossing your route ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-there-will-be-two-way-traffic-crossing-your-route-ahead-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2890d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2890a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2890c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2890b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2890b.gif'>"},
{"id": "43955", "question": "Which sign means the end of a dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-the-end-of-a-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2357a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2357b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2357d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2357c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2357d.gif'>"},
{"id": "43673", "question": "Which sign means that there may be people walking along the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-that-there-may-be-people-walking-along-the-road-5/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2117a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2117c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2117d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2117b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2117d.gif'>"},
{"id": "43996", "question": "Which sign means that the national speed limit applies?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-that-the-national-speed-limit-applies/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2429b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2429c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2429d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2429a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2429d.gif'>"},
{"id": "43951", "question": "Which sign means that pedestrians may be walking along the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-that-pedestrians-may-be-walking-along-the-road-5/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2347a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2347d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2347b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2347c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2347a.gif'>"},
{"id": "43753", "question": "Which sign means ‘no stopping’?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-no-stopping-6/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2314d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2314c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2314a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2314b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2314b.gif'>"},
{"id": "43749", "question": "Which sign means no motor vehicles allowed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-no-motor-vehicles-allowed-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2307d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2307a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2307b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2307c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2307b.gif'>"},
{"id": "43746", "question": "Which sign means ‘no entry’?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-means-no-entry-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2304a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2304d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2304b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2304c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2304d.gif'>"},
{"id": "44137", "question": "Which sign informs you that you’re coming to a ‘no through road’?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-sign-informs-you-that-youre-coming-to-a-no-through-road-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2768a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2768c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2768b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2768d.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2768c.gif'>"},
{"id": "44132", "question": "Which shape is used for a ‘give way’ sign?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-shape-is-used-for-a-give-way-sign-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2763c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2763b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2763a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2763d.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2763d.gif'>"},
{"id": "43736", "question": "Which road users benefit from toucan crossings?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-road-users-benefit-from-toucan-crossings/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Tram and train drivers", "Car drivers and motorcyclists", "Bus and lorry drivers", "Cyclists and pedestrians"], "answer": "Cyclists and pedestrians"},
{"id": "44289", "question": "Which road users are most difficult to see when you’re reversing your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-road-users-are-most-difficult-to-see-when-youre-reversing-your-car/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Motorcyclists", "Cyclists", "Children", "Car drivers"], "answer": "Children"},
{"id": "43662", "question": "Which road user has caused a hazard?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2088.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-road-user-has-caused-a-hazard-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The parked car (arrowed A)", "The car turning (arrowed D)", "The pedestrian waiting to cross (arrowed B)", "The moving car (arrowed C)"], "answer": "The parked car (arrowed A)"},
{"id": "43705", "question": "Which plate may appear with this road sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2212.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-plate-may-appear-with-this-road-sign/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2212b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2212d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2212c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2212a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2212a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44198", "question": "Which of these signs warns you of a zebra crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-of-these-signs-warns-you-of-a-zebra-crossing-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2887a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2887d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2887c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2887b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2887a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44441", "question": "Which lights should you use when you’re driving in a tunnel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-lights-should-you-use-when-youre-driving-in-a-tunnel/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Dipped headlights", "Sidelights", "Front spotlights", "Rear fog lights"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44432", "question": "Which lights should you switch on when daytime visibility is poor but not seriously reduced?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-lights-should-you-switch-on-when-daytime-visibility-is-poor-but-not-seriously-reduced/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Front fog lights", "Rear fog lights", "Headlights and fog lights", "Dipped headlights"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44389", "question": "Which lights must you use if you’re driving on a well-lit motorway at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-lights-must-you-use-if-youre-driving-on-a-well-lit-motorway-at-night/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Use your headlights", "Use rear fog lights", "Use front fog lights", "Use only your sidelights"], "answer": "Use your headlights"},
{"id": "43966", "question": "Which is the sign for a ring road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-is-the-sign-for-a-ring-road-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2375d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2375c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2375b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2375a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2375c.gif'>"},
{"id": "43691", "question": "Which is the most vulnerable road user?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-is-the-most-vulnerable-road-user/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Car driver", "Lorry driver", "Tractor driver", "Motorcyclist"], "answer": "Motorcyclist"},
{"id": "44429", "question": "Which instrument-panel warning light would show that headlights are on main beam?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-instrument-panel-warning-light-would-show-that-headlights-are-on-main-beam/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1591c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1591b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1591d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1591a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1591a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44495", "question": "Which driving technique can help you save fuel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-driving-technique-can-help-you-save-fuel-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Using each gear in turn", "Accelerating sharply in each gear", "Using lower gears as often as possible", "Missing out some gears"], "answer": "Missing out some gears"},
{"id": "44228", "question": "Which document may the police ask you to produce after you’ve been involved in a collision?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-document-may-the-police-ask-you-to-produce-after-youve-been-involved-in-a-collision/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Your driving licence", "Your theory test certificate", "Your vehicle service record", "Your vehicle registration document"], "answer": "Your driving licence"},
{"id": "43981", "question": "Which diagram shows a hazard warning line?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-diagram-shows-a-hazard-warning-line/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2401a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2401b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2401d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2401c.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2401a.gif'>"},
{"id": "44085", "question": "Which colour follows the green signal at a puffin crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-colour-follows-the-green-signal-at-a-puffin-crossing/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Steady amber", "Flashing amber", "Steady red", "Flashing green"], "answer": "Steady amber"},
{"id": "44202", "question": "Which arm signal tells you that the car you’re following is going to pull up?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/which-arm-signal-tells-you-that-the-car-youre-following-is-going-to-pull-up-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2892a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2892d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2892c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2892b.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2892d.gif'>"},
{"id": "44378", "question": "Where’s the safest place to park your vehicle at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wheres-the-safest-place-to-park-your-vehicle-at-night-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["On a busy road", "In a garage", "In a quiet car park", "Near a red route"], "answer": "In a garage"},
{"id": "44014", "question": "Where would you see this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2559.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-see-this-sign-9/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Near a school crossing", "At a 'pedestrians only' area", "At a playground entrance", "On a school bus"], "answer": "On a school bus"},
{"id": "43679", "question": "Where would you see this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2129.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-see-this-sign-8/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["At playground areas", "At the side of the road", "On the rear of a school bus or coach", "In the window of a car taking children to school"], "answer": "On the rear of a school bus or coach"},
{"id": "43980", "question": "Where would you see this road marking?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2400.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-see-this-road-marking-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Near a level crossing", "At a box junction", "On road humps", "At traffic lights"], "answer": "On road humps"},
{"id": "43765", "question": "Where would you see a contraflow bus lane?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2335.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-see-a-contraflow-bus-lane/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["On a one-way street", "On an urban motorway", "On a dual carriageway", "On a roundabout"], "answer": "On a one-way street"},
{"id": "44127", "question": "Where would you find these road markings?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2756.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-find-these-road-markings-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["On a pedestrian crossing", "At a mini-roundabout", "At a railway crossing", "On a motorway"], "answer": "At a mini-roundabout"},
{"id": "43976", "question": "Where would you find these flashing red light signals?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2393.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-find-these-flashing-red-light-signals/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Motorway exits", "Zebra crossings", "Pelican crossings", "Level crossings"], "answer": "Level crossings"},
{"id": "43993", "question": "Where would you find green reflective studs on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-find-green-reflective-studs-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Separating driving lanes", "At slip-road entrances and exits", "Between the carriageway and the central reservation", "Between the hard shoulder and the carriageway"], "answer": "At slip-road entrances and exits"},
{"id": "43660", "question": "Where would you expect to see these markers?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2085.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-you-expect-to-see-these-markers-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["On a diversion sign", "On a motorway sign", "On a railway bridge", "On a large goods vehicle"], "answer": "On a large goods vehicle"},
{"id": "44439", "question": "Where would parking your vehicle cause an obstruction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-parking-your-vehicle-cause-an-obstruction-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["On your driveway", "Alongside a parking meter", "In a marked parking space", "In front of a property entrance"], "answer": "In front of a property entrance"},
{"id": "44187", "question": "Where would it be unsafe to overtake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-would-it-be-unsafe-to-overtake/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["On a one-way street", "Approaching a junction", "Travelling up a long hill", "On a single carriageway"], "answer": "Approaching a junction"},
{"id": "44159", "question": "Where will you see these red and white markers?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2826.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-will-you-see-these-red-and-white-markers-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Approaching a concealed speed-limit sign", "Approaching the end of a dual carriageway", "Approaching a concealed level crossing", "Approaching the end of a motorway"], "answer": "Approaching a concealed level crossing"},
{"id": "44416", "question": "Where should you take particular care to look for motorcyclists and cyclists?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-should-you-take-particular-care-to-look-for-motorcyclists-and-cyclists-4/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["On one-way streets", "At junctions", "At zebra crossings", "On dual carriageways"], "answer": "At junctions"},
{"id": "44194", "question": "Where should you stop to rest if you feel tired while you’re travelling along a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-should-you-stop-to-rest-if-you-feel-tired-while-youre-travelling-along-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["On the central reservation", "On the hard shoulder", "On a slip road", "At the nearest service area"], "answer": "At the nearest service area"},
{"id": "44484", "question": "Where should you park your vehicle at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-should-you-park-your-vehicle-at-night/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["In a well-lit area", "In a quiet road", "Near a police station", "On a red route"], "answer": "In a well-lit area"},
{"id": "43635", "question": "Where should you avoid overtaking?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-should-you-avoid-overtaking-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["In a one-way street", "Approaching a dip in the road", "On a 30 mph road", "Just after a bend"], "answer": "Approaching a dip in the road"},
{"id": "43729", "question": "Where may you overtake on a one-way street?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-may-you-overtake-on-a-one-way-street-4/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["On either the right or the left", "Only on the right-hand side", "Only on the left-hand side", "Overtaking isn't allowed"], "answer": "On either the right or the left"},
{"id": "44091", "question": "Where is your vehicle most likely to be affected by side winds?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-is-your-vehicle-most-likely-to-be-affected-by-side-winds/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["On a long, straight road", "On an open stretch of road", "On a busy stretch of road", "On a narrow country lane"], "answer": "On an open stretch of road"},
{"id": "43992", "question": "Where can you find reflective amber studs on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-can-you-find-reflective-amber-studs-on-a-motorway-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["On the left-hand edge of the road", "On the right-hand edge of the road", "Separating the lanes", "Separating the slip road from the motorway"], "answer": "On the right-hand edge of the road"},
{"id": "43714", "question": "Where are amber reflective studs found on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/where-are-amber-reflective-studs-found-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Between the central reservation and the carriageway", "Between each pair of lanes", "Between the hard shoulder and the carriageway", "Between the acceleration lane and the carriageway"], "answer": "Between the central reservation and the carriageway"},
{"id": "44118", "question": "When would you use the right-hand lane on a three-lane motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-would-you-use-the-right-hand-lane-on-a-three-lane-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When you're driving above the speed limit", "When you're turning right", "When you're overtaking", "When you're trying to save fuel"], "answer": "When you're overtaking"},
{"id": "44042", "question": "When would you use the right-hand lane of a two-lane dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-would-you-use-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-two-lane-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When you're passing a side road on the left", "When you're staying at the minimum allowed speed", "When you're turning right or overtaking", "When you're driving at a constant high speed"], "answer": "When you're turning right or overtaking"},
{"id": "44143", "question": "When would you use an emergency refuge area on a smart motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-would-you-use-an-emergency-refuge-area-on-a-smart-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["In cases of emergency or breakdown", "To make a private phone call", "To stop and check where you are", "If you think you'll be involved in a road rage incident"], "answer": "In cases of emergency or breakdown"},
{"id": "44356", "question": "When would you increase the pressure in your tyres so that it’s above the normal value?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-would-you-increase-the-pressure-in-your-tyres-so-that-its-above-the-normal-value/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["When the tyre tread is worn below 2 mm", "When the roads are slippery", "When carrying a heavy load", "When the vehicle is fitted with anti-lock brakes"], "answer": "When carrying a heavy load"},
{"id": "44054", "question": "When will your vehicle use more fuel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-will-your-vehicle-use-more-fuel-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["When its tyres are under-inflated", "When its tyres are over-inflated", "When its tyres are new", "When its tyres are of different makes"], "answer": "When its tyres are under-inflated"},
{"id": "44425", "question": "When will you feel the effects of engine braking?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-will-you-feel-the-effects-of-engine-braking-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["When you only use the parking brake", "When you change to a higher gear", "When you're in neutral", "When you change to a lower gear"], "answer": "When you change to a lower gear"},
{"id": "44488", "question": "When will a new car need its first MOT test?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-will-a-new-car-need-its-first-mot-test/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When it's five years old", "When it's seven years old", "When it's one year old", "When it's three years old"], "answer": "When it's three years old"},
{"id": "43650", "question": "When should you use your vehicle’s horn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-use-your-vehicles-horn-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["To signal your annoyance", "To greet other road users", "To allow you right of way", "To alert others to your presence"], "answer": "To alert others to your presence"},
{"id": "43727", "question": "When should you use the right-hand lane of a three-lane dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-use-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-three-lane-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When you're turning right only", "When you're using cruise control", "When you're overtaking or turning right", "When you're overtaking only"], "answer": "When you're overtaking or turning right"},
{"id": "44307", "question": "When should you use the left-hand lane of a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-use-the-left-hand-lane-of-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["When you're making a phone call", "When the road ahead is clear", "When your vehicle breaks down", "When you're overtaking slower traffic in the other lanes"], "answer": "When the road ahead is clear"},
{"id": "44421", "question": "When should you use hazard warning lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-use-hazard-warning-lights-7/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["When your direction indicators aren't working", "When you're double-parked on a two-way road", "When your vehicle has broken down and is causing an obstruction", "When warning oncoming traffic that you intend to stop"], "answer": "When your vehicle has broken down and is causing an obstruction"},
{"id": "44238", "question": "When should you update your vehicle registration certificate?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-update-your-vehicle-registration-certificate-3/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When you have a collision", "When your vehicle needs an MOT", "When you move house", "When you pass your driving test"], "answer": "When you move house"},
{"id": "44449", "question": "When should you leave a two-second gap between your vehicle and the one in front?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-leave-a-two-second-gap-between-your-vehicle-and-the-one-in-front/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["When it's dry", "When it's raining", "When it's icy", "When it's foggy"], "answer": "When it's dry"},
{"id": "44059", "question": "When should you flash your headlights at other road users?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-flash-your-headlights-at-other-road-users-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["When showing that you're giving way", "When letting them know that you're there", "When showing that you're about to turn", "When telling them that you have right of way"], "answer": "When letting them know that you're there"},
{"id": "44435", "question": "When should you check the engine oil level?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-you-check-the-engine-oil-level/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Early in the morning", "Every time you drive the car", "Before a long journey", "When the engine is hot"], "answer": "Before a long journey"},
{"id": "44012", "question": "When should tyre pressures be checked?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-should-tyre-pressures-be-checked/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["After any lengthy journey", "When tyres are hot", "After travelling at high speed", "When tyres are cold"], "answer": "When tyres are cold"},
{"id": "44189", "question": "When must your vehicle have valid insurance cover?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-must-your-vehicle-have-valid-insurance-cover/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Before you can make a SORN", "Before you can sell the vehicle", "Before you can scrap the vehicle", "Before you can tax the vehicle"], "answer": "Before you can tax the vehicle"},
{"id": "44517", "question": "When must you use dipped headlights during the day?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-must-you-use-dipped-headlights-during-the-day-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["When you're driving along narrow streets", "When you're driving in poor visibility", "When you're parking", "All the time you're driving"], "answer": "When you're driving in poor visibility"},
{"id": "44534", "question": "When must you stop your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-must-you-stop-your-vehicle-2-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Before merging onto a motorway", "At the end of a one-way street", "At a junction where there are 'give way' lines", "If you're involved in an incident that causes damage or injury"], "answer": "If you're involved in an incident that causes damage or injury"},
{"id": "44407", "question": "When must you contact the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency (DVLA)?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-must-you-contact-the-driver-and-vehicle-licensing-agency-dvla/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When you change your vehicle", "When you use your vehicle for work", "When you get a parking ticket", "When your vehicle's insurance is due"], "answer": "When you change your vehicle"},
{"id": "43704", "question": "When may you wait in a box junction?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2211.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-wait-in-a-box-junction-5/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["When you're stationary in a queue of traffic", "When approaching a pelican crossing", "When oncoming traffic prevents you turning right", "When approaching a zebra crossing"], "answer": "When oncoming traffic prevents you turning right"},
{"id": "44328", "question": "When may you use hazard warning lights while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-use-hazard-warning-lights-while-youre-driving-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["On a motorway or unrestricted dual carriageway, to warn of a hazard ahead", "On the approach to toucan crossings, where cyclists are waiting to cross", "Instead of sounding the horn in a built-up area between 11.30 pm and 7.00 am", "On rural routes, after a sign warning of animals"], "answer": "On a motorway or unrestricted dual carriageway, to warn of a hazard ahead"},
{"id": "44469", "question": "When may you use hazard warning lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-use-hazard-warning-lights-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["When you're double-parked on a two-way road", "When warning oncoming traffic that you intend to stop", "When your direction indicators aren't working", "When driving on a motorway to warn traffic behind of a hazard ahead"], "answer": "When driving on a motorway to warn traffic behind of a hazard ahead"},
{"id": "44403", "question": "When may you stop on an urban clearway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-stop-on-an-urban-clearway-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["To load or unload goods", "To set down and pick up passengers", "To use a mobile telephone", "To ask for directions"], "answer": "To set down and pick up passengers"},
{"id": "44168", "question": "When may you stop on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-stop-on-a-motorway-4/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["If you have to read a map", "In an emergency or breakdown", "If your mobile phone rings", "When you're tired and need a rest"], "answer": "In an emergency or breakdown"},
{"id": "43724", "question": "When may you stop on a clearway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-stop-on-a-clearway/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Never", "When it's busy", "During daylight hours", "In the rush hour"], "answer": "Never"},
{"id": "43733", "question": "When may you stop and wait in a box junction?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2282.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-stop-and-wait-in-a-box-junction-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["When oncoming traffic prevents you from turning right", "When you're in a queue of traffic turning left", "When you're in a queue of traffic going ahead", "When you're on a roundabout"], "answer": "When oncoming traffic prevents you from turning right"},
{"id": "44051", "question": "When may you sound your vehicle’s horn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-sound-your-vehicles-horn/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["To attract a friend's attention", "To make slower drivers move over", "To give you right of way", "To warn others of your presence"], "answer": "To warn others of your presence"},
{"id": "43701", "question": "When may you overtake another vehicle on their left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/when-may-you-overtake-another-vehicle-on-their-left/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["When you're in a one-way street", "When the vehicle in front is signalling to turn left", "When approaching a motorway slip road where you'll be turning off", "When a slower vehicle is travelling in the right-hand lane of a dual carriageway"], "answer": "When you're in a one-way street"},
{"id": "44373", "question": "What’s the safest thing to do if you have to leave valuables in your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-safest-thing-to-do-if-you-have-to-leave-valuables-in-your-car/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Park near a bus stop", "Lock them out of sight", "Park near a school entrance", "Put them in a carrier bag"], "answer": "Lock them out of sight"},
{"id": "44005", "question": "What’s the reason for traffic-calming measures?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-reason-for-traffic-calming-measures/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To slow traffic down", "To stop road rage", "To make parking easier", "To make overtaking easier"], "answer": "To slow traffic down"},
{"id": "44073", "question": "What’s the reason for the hatched area along the centre of this road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2681.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-reason-for-the-hatched-area-along-the-centre-of-this-road/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["It marks an area to be used by overtaking motorcyclists", "It separates traffic flowing in opposite directions", "It's a temporary marking to warn of the roadworks", "It separates the two sides of the dual carriageway"], "answer": "It separates traffic flowing in opposite directions"},
{"id": "43769", "question": "What’s the purpose of triangular shaped signs?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2340.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-purpose-of-triangular-shaped-signs/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["To give orders", "To give directions", "To give warnings", "To give information"], "answer": "To give warnings"},
{"id": "44103", "question": "What’s the purpose of these road markings?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2729.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-purpose-of-these-road-markings-3/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To ensure children can see and be seen when they're crossing the road", "To enable parents to pick up or drop off children safely", "To ensure delivery vehicles have easy access to the school", "To enable teachers to have clear access to the school"], "answer": "To ensure children can see and be seen when they're crossing the road"},
{"id": "44067", "question": "What’s the purpose of the yellow lines painted across the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2665.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-purpose-of-the-yellow-lines-painted-across-the-road-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To make you aware of your speed", "To warn you to change direction", "To show a safe distance between vehicles", "To keep the area clear of traffic"], "answer": "To make you aware of your speed"},
{"id": "43657", "question": "What’s the purpose of road humps, chicanes and narrowings?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-purpose-of-road-humps-chicanes-and-narrowings-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To allow pedestrians to cross", "To reduce traffic speed", "To separate lanes of traffic", "To increase traffic speed"], "answer": "To reduce traffic speed"},
{"id": "44003", "question": "What’s the purpose of a catalytic converter?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-purpose-of-a-catalytic-converter-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To reduce engine wear", "To reduce the risk of fire", "To reduce harmful exhaust gases", "To reduce fuel consumption"], "answer": "To reduce harmful exhaust gases"},
{"id": "44048", "question": "What’s the nearest you may park to a junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-nearest-you-may-park-to-a-junction-4/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["20 metres (66 feet)", "15 metres (49 feet)", "12 metres (39 feet)", "10 metres (32 feet)"], "answer": "10 metres (32 feet)"},
{"id": "43707", "question": "What’s the national speed limit on motorways for cars and motorcycles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-national-speed-limit-on-motorways-for-cars-and-motorcycles-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["60 mph", "70 mph", "50 mph", "30 mph"], "answer": "70 mph"},
{"id": "44157", "question": "What’s the national speed limit on a single carriageway road for cars and motorcycles?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-national-speed-limit-on-a-single-carriageway-road-for-cars-and-motorcycles-3/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["70 mph", "50 mph", "60 mph", "30 mph"], "answer": "60 mph"},
{"id": "43997", "question": "What’s the national speed limit on a single carriageway road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-national-speed-limit-on-a-single-carriageway-road/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["40 mph", "50 mph", "60 mph", "70 mph"], "answer": "60 mph"},
{"id": "43718", "question": "What’s the national speed limit for cars and motorcycles on a dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-national-speed-limit-for-cars-and-motorcycles-on-a-dual-carriageway-4/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["60 mph", "30 mph", "70 mph", "50 mph"], "answer": "70 mph"},
{"id": "44170", "question": "What’s the national speed limit for a car or motorcycle on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-national-speed-limit-for-a-car-or-motorcycle-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["80 mph", "70 mph", "50 mph", "60 mph"], "answer": "70 mph"},
{"id": "44452", "question": "What’s the most important reason for having a properly adjusted head restraint?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-most-important-reason-for-having-a-properly-adjusted-head-restraint-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["To help you maintain your driving position", "To help you avoid neck injury", "To make you more comfortable", "To help you relax"], "answer": "To help you avoid neck injury"},
{"id": "43643", "question": "What’s the minimum time gap you should leave when following a vehicle on a wet road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-minimum-time-gap-you-should-leave-when-following-a-vehicle-on-a-wet-road-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["One second", "Two seconds", "Three seconds", "Four seconds"], "answer": "Four seconds"},
{"id": "47582", "question": "What’s the minimum depth of tread on the tyres of a trailer?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-minimum-depth-of-tread-on-the-tyres-of-a-trailer/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["1.6 mm", "1 mm", "2.2 mm", "2 mm"], "answer": "1.6 mm"},
{"id": "43758", "question": "What’s the meaning of this traffic sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2320.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-meaning-of-this-traffic-sign-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["You have priority over vehicles coming towards you", "End of two-way road", "Give priority to vehicles coming towards you", "Bus lane ahead"], "answer": "You have priority over vehicles coming towards you"},
{"id": "43725", "question": "What’s the meaning of this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2264.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-meaning-of-this-sign-29/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["School crossing patrol", "Waiting restrictions", "No entry", "National speed limit"], "answer": "Waiting restrictions"},
{"id": "43717", "question": "What’s the meaning of this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2246.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-meaning-of-this-sign-28/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["No entry for vehicles", "Local speed limit applies", "No waiting on the carriageway", "National speed limit applies"], "answer": "National speed limit applies"},
{"id": "44153", "question": "What’s the maximum fine for driving without insurance?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-maximum-fine-for-driving-without-insurance-4/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Unlimited", "£1,000", "£5,000", "£500"], "answer": "Unlimited"},
{"id": "44096", "question": "What’s the main hazard you should be aware of when following this cyclist?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2720.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-main-hazard-you-should-be-aware-of-when-following-this-cyclist-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The cyclist may wish to turn right at the end of the road", "The cyclist may move to the left and dismount", "The cyclist may get off and push their bicycle", "The cyclist may swerve into the road"], "answer": "The cyclist may swerve into the road"},
{"id": "44093", "question": "What’s the main hazard the driver of the red car (arrowed) should be aware of?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2717.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-main-hazard-the-driver-of-the-red-car-arrowed-should-be-aware-of-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The bus may move out into the road", "Oncoming vehicles will assume the driver is turning right", "Glare from the sun may affect the driver's vision", "The black car may stop suddenly"], "answer": "The bus may move out into the road"},
{"id": "43661", "question": "What’s the main hazard shown in this picture?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2087.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-main-hazard-shown-in-this-picture-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Parked cars around the corner", "The cyclist crossing the road", "Vehicles turning right", "Vehicles doing U-turns"], "answer": "The cyclist crossing the road"},
{"id": "44259", "question": "What’s the main cause of skidding?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-main-cause-of-skidding-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["The driver", "The weather", "The vehicle", "The road"], "answer": "The driver"},
{"id": "44264", "question": "What’s the main benefit of driving a four-wheel-drive vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-main-benefit-of-driving-a-four-wheel-drive-vehicle-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Shorter stopping distances", "Improved passenger comfort", "Improved grip on the road", "Lower fuel consumption"], "answer": "Improved grip on the road"},
{"id": "44509", "question": "What’s the legal minimum tread depth for tyres on your trailer or caravan?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-legal-minimum-tread-depth-for-tyres-on-your-trailer-or-caravan/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["2.6 mm", "2 mm", "1 mm", "1.6 mm"], "answer": "1.6 mm"},
{"id": "44497", "question": "What’s the legal minimum insurance cover you must have to drive on public roads?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-legal-minimum-insurance-cover-you-must-have-to-drive-on-public-roads-2/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Third party, fire and theft", "Third party only", "Comprehensive", "Personal injury cover"], "answer": "Third party only"},
{"id": "44337", "question": "What’s the legal minimum depth of tread for car tyres?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-legal-minimum-depth-of-tread-for-car-tyres-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["4 mm", "1.6 mm", "2.5 mm", "1 mm"], "answer": "1.6 mm"},
{"id": "44531", "question": "What’s the first thing you must do if you have a collision while you’re driving your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-the-first-thing-you-must-do-if-you-have-a-collision-while-youre-driving-your-car/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Call your insurance company", "Stop at the scene of the incident", "Stop only if someone waves at you", "Call the emergency services"], "answer": "Stop at the scene of the incident"},
{"id": "44345", "question": "What’s most likely to waste fuel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-most-likely-to-waste-fuel-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Driving on motorways", "Using different brands of fuel", "Under-inflated tyres", "Reducing your speed"], "answer": "Under-inflated tyres"},
{"id": "44058", "question": "What’s most likely to increase fuel consumption?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-most-likely-to-increase-fuel-consumption/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Poor steering control", "Staying in high gears", "Accelerating around bends", "Harsh braking and accelerating"], "answer": "Harsh braking and accelerating"},
{"id": "44340", "question": "What’s most likely to distract you while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-most-likely-to-distract-you-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Using the mirrors", "Using the demisters", "Using a mobile phone", "Using the windscreen wipers"], "answer": "Using a mobile phone"},
{"id": "44539", "question": "What’s likely to happen if you use a hands-free phone while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-likely-to-happen-if-you-use-a-hands-free-phone-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["It will divert your attention", "It will improve your safety", "It will increase your concentration", "It will reduce your view"], "answer": "It will divert your attention"},
{"id": "44521", "question": "What’s likely to happen if you put too much oil in your engine?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-likely-to-happen-if-you-put-too-much-oil-in-your-engine/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The clutch pedal will lock", "The air intake will become blocked", "The timing belt will slip", "The oil seals will leak"], "answer": "The oil seals will leak"},
{"id": "44393", "question": "What’s covered by third-party insurance?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-covered-by-third-party-insurance/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Flood damage to your vehicle", "Fire damage to your vehicle", "Damage to your vehicle", "Damage to other vehicles"], "answer": "Damage to other vehicles"},
{"id": "44142", "question": "What’s a Statutory Off-Road Notification (SORN)?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-a-statutory-off-road-notification-sorn-2/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["A notification to tell DVLA that a vehicle isn't being used on the road", "A notification to tell DVSA that a vehicle doesn't have a current MOT", "Information kept by the police about the owner of a vehicle", "Information held by insurance companies to check a vehicle is insured"], "answer": "A notification to tell DVLA that a vehicle isn't being used on the road"},
{"id": "44022", "question": "What’s a rumble device designed to do?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2572.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-a-rumble-device-designed-to-do-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Give directions", "Alert you to low tyre pressure", "Alert you to a hazard", "Prevent cattle escaping"], "answer": "Alert you to a hazard"},
{"id": "44010", "question": "What’s a cover note?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/whats-a-cover-note-2/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["A document issued before you receive your insurance certificate", "A document issued before you receive your MOT certificate", "A document issued before you receive your driving licence", "A document issued before you receive your registration document"], "answer": "A document issued before you receive your insurance certificate"},
{"id": "44482", "question": "What would you expect to find at a contraflow system on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-would-you-expect-to-find-at-a-contraflow-system-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Wider lanes than normal", "Temporary traffic lights", "Lower speed limits", "Road humps"], "answer": "Lower speed limits"},
{"id": "43682", "question": "What would you do if you see older people crossing the road ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2138.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-would-you-do-if-you-see-older-people-crossing-the-road-ahead/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Wave them across so they know that you've seen them", "Tap the horn in case they're hard of hearing", "Rev the engine to let them know that you're waiting", "Be patient and allow them to cross in their own time"], "answer": "Be patient and allow them to cross in their own time"},
{"id": "44370", "question": "What would suggest you’re driving on an icy road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-would-suggest-youre-driving-on-an-icy-road/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["There's less wind noise", "There's less engine noise", "There's less transmission noise", "There's less tyre noise"], "answer": "There's less tyre noise"},
{"id": "44409", "question": "What would be affected if you carry a very heavy load on your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-would-be-affected-if-you-carry-a-very-heavy-load-on-your-vehicle/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["The vehicle's battery", "The vehicle's gearbox", "The vehicle's handling", "The vehicle's ventilation"], "answer": "The vehicle's handling"},
{"id": "43720", "question": "What will the speed limit usually be where you can see street lights but no speed-limit signs?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-the-speed-limit-usually-be-where-you-can-see-street-lights-but-no-speed-limit-signs/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["30 mph", "50 mph", "60 mph", "40 mph"], "answer": "30 mph"},
{"id": "44392", "question": "What will reduce fuel consumption?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-reduce-fuel-consumption/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Late and heavy braking", "Accelerating rapidly", "Driving more slowly", "Staying in lower gears"], "answer": "Driving more slowly"},
{"id": "44262", "question": "What will help you to move off on a snowy surface?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-help-you-to-move-off-on-a-snowy-surface/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Using the parking brake and footbrake together", "Using a higher gear than normal", "Using the car's lowest gear", "Using a high engine speed"], "answer": "Using a higher gear than normal"},
{"id": "44461", "question": "What will help you to keep your car secure?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-help-you-to-keep-your-car-secure/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Passing an advanced driving test", "Taking car maintenance classes", "Registering with a Vehicle Watch scheme", "Being a member of a vehicle breakdown organisation"], "answer": "Registering with a Vehicle Watch scheme"},
{"id": "44301", "question": "What will happen to your car when you drive up a steep hill?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-happen-to-your-car-when-you-drive-up-a-steep-hill/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["The steering will feel heavier", "Overtaking will be easier", "The high gears will pull better", "The engine will work harder"], "answer": "The engine will work harder"},
{"id": "44366", "question": "What will happen if your car’s wheels are unbalanced?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-happen-if-your-cars-wheels-are-unbalanced-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The steering will pull to one side", "The brakes will fail", "The tyres will deflate", "The steering will vibrate"], "answer": "The steering will vibrate"},
{"id": "44349", "question": "What will happen if you use rear fog lights in good conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-happen-if-you-use-rear-fog-lights-in-good-conditions-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["They'll make drivers behind keep back", "They'll dazzle other drivers", "They'll protect you from larger vehicles", "They'll make it safer when towing a trailer"], "answer": "They'll dazzle other drivers"},
{"id": "44479", "question": "What will happen if you hold the clutch pedal down or roll in neutral for too long?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-happen-if-you-hold-the-clutch-pedal-down-or-roll-in-neutral-for-too-long-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["It will cause the engine to overheat", "It will reduce your control", "It will use more fuel", "It will improve tyre wear"], "answer": "It will reduce your control"},
{"id": "43642", "question": "What will happen if you follow this vehicle too closely?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2023.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-happen-if-you-follow-this-vehicle-too-closely/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Your engine will overheat", "Your brakes will overheat", "Your fuel consumption will be increased", "Your view ahead will be reduced"], "answer": "Your view ahead will be reduced"},
{"id": "44277", "question": "What will become more expensive after you’ve been convicted of driving while unfit through drink or drugs?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-become-more-expensive-after-youve-been-convicted-of-driving-while-unfit-through-drink-or-drugs/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Road fund licence", "Driving licence", "Insurance premiums", "Vehicle test certificate"], "answer": "Insurance premiums"},
{"id": "44090", "question": "What will be affected if the road surface becomes soft in very hot weather?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-be-affected-if-the-road-surface-becomes-soft-in-very-hot-weather/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["The suspension", "The exhaust emissions", "The fuel consumption", "The tyre grip"], "answer": "The tyre grip"},
{"id": "44361", "question": "What will be a serious distraction while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-be-a-serious-distraction-while-youre-driving/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Looking at road maps", "Switching on your demister", "Using your windscreen washers", "Looking in your door mirror"], "answer": "Looking at road maps"},
{"id": "44399", "question": "What will affect your vehicle’s stopping distance?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-will-affect-your-vehicles-stopping-distance-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["The street lighting", "The condition of the tyres", "The time of day", "The speed limit"], "answer": "The condition of the tyres"},
{"id": "44169", "question": "What type of vehicle uses an amber flashing beacon on a dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-type-of-vehicle-uses-an-amber-flashing-beacon-on-a-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["A tractor", "A fire engine", "An ambulance", "A doctor on call"], "answer": "A tractor"},
{"id": "44094", "question": "What type of vehicle displays this yellow sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2718.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-type-of-vehicle-displays-this-yellow-sign-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["A school bus", "A broken-down vehicle", "An ice-cream van", "A private ambulance"], "answer": "A school bus"},
{"id": "43669", "question": "What type of vehicle could you expect to meet in the middle of the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2103.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-type-of-vehicle-could-you-expect-to-meet-in-the-middle-of-the-road-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Car", "Motorcycle", "Bicycle", "Lorry"], "answer": "Lorry"},
{"id": "43647", "question": "What type of emergency vehicle is fitted with a green flashing beacon?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-type-of-emergency-vehicle-is-fitted-with-a-green-flashing-beacon-5/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Doctor's car", "Road gritter", "Ambulance", "Fire engine"], "answer": "Doctor's car"},
{"id": "44505", "question": "What style of driving causes increased risk to everyone?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-style-of-driving-causes-increased-risk-to-everyone-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Competitive", "Responsible", "Considerate", "Defensive"], "answer": "Competitive"},
{"id": "43730", "question": "What signal should you give when you’re going straight ahead at a roundabout?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-signal-should-you-give-when-youre-going-straight-ahead-at-a-roundabout/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Signal left before leaving the roundabout", "Signal left when you're approaching the roundabout", "Don't signal at any time", "Signal right when you're approaching the roundabout"], "answer": "Signal left before leaving the roundabout"},
{"id": "44375", "question": "What should you remove from your car before leaving it unattended?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-remove-from-your-car-before-leaving-it-unattended/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The car dealer's details", "The service record", "The vehicle registration document", "The owner's manual"], "answer": "The vehicle registration document"},
{"id": "43665", "question": "What should you expect if you see this sign ahead?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2098.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-expect-if-you-see-this-sign-ahead/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["The road will bend sharply to the right", "The road will bend sharply to the left", "The road will go steeply uphill", "The road will go steeply downhill"], "answer": "The road will bend sharply to the left"},
{"id": "44116", "question": "What should you do while you’re driving or riding along a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-while-youre-driving-or-riding-along-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Travel much faster than you would on other roads", "Concentrate more than you would on other roads", "Maintain a shorter separation distance than you would on other roads", "Look much further ahead than you would on other roads"], "answer": "Look much further ahead than you would on other roads"},
{"id": "44234", "question": "What should you do when you’re using a contraflow system?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-using-a-contraflow-system/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Choose an appropriate lane in good time", "Follow other motorists closely to avoid long queues", "Switch lanes to make better progress", "Increase speed to get through the contraflow more quickly"], "answer": "Choose an appropriate lane in good time"},
{"id": "44322", "question": "What should you do when you’re unsure whether it’s safe to reverse your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-unsure-whether-its-safe-to-reverse-your-vehicle-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Get out and check", "Sound your horn", "Rev your engine", "Reverse slowly"], "answer": "Get out and check"},
{"id": "44210", "question": "What should you do when you’re passing loose sheep on the road?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2908.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-passing-loose-sheep-on-the-road/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Briefly sound your horn", "Pass quickly but quietly", "Go very slowly", "Herd them to the side of the road"], "answer": "Go very slowly"},
{"id": "43703", "question": "What should you do when you’re overtaking at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-overtaking-at-night-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Go past slowly so that you can react to unseen hazards", "Beware of bends in the road ahead", "Wait until a bend so that you can see oncoming headlights", "Sound your horn twice before moving out"], "answer": "Beware of bends in the road ahead"},
{"id": "44535", "question": "What should you do when you’re overtaking a motorcyclist on a windy day?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-overtaking-a-motorcyclist-on-a-windy-day/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Pass very slowly", "Pass closely", "Pass widely", "Pass immediately"], "answer": "Pass widely"},
{"id": "44251", "question": "What should you do when you’re overtaking a horse and rider?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-overtaking-a-horse-and-rider-2/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Go past as quickly as possible", "Flash your headlights as a warning", "Go past slowly and carefully", "Sound your horn as a warning"], "answer": "Go past slowly and carefully"},
{"id": "44105", "question": "What should you do when you’re following a motorcyclist along a road that has a poor surface?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-following-a-motorcyclist-along-a-road-that-has-a-poor-surface-3/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Allow the same room as normal to avoid wasting road space", "Allow extra room in case they swerve to avoid potholes", "Overtake immediately to avoid delays", "Follow closely so they can see you in their mirrors"], "answer": "Allow extra room in case they swerve to avoid potholes"},
{"id": "44019", "question": "What should you do when you’re following a learner driver who stalls at a junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-following-a-learner-driver-who-stalls-at-a-junction-3/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Be patient, as you expect them to make mistakes", "Stay very close behind and flash your headlights", "Immediately steer around them and drive on", "Start to rev your engine if they take too long to restart"], "answer": "Be patient, as you expect them to make mistakes"},
{"id": "44263", "question": "What should you do when you’re driving in snowy conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-driving-in-snowy-conditions-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Brake gently in plenty of time", "Use sidelights only", "Brake firmly and quickly", "Be ready to steer sharply"], "answer": "Brake gently in plenty of time"},
{"id": "47546", "question": "What should you do when you’re driving along a road that has a series of road humps?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-driving-along-a-road-that-has-a-series-of-road-humps/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Set your car's cruise control", "Brake firmly when you reach each road hump", "Vary your speed between each road hump", "Stay at a reduced speed for the whole stretch of road"], "answer": "Stay at a reduced speed for the whole stretch of road"},
{"id": "44139", "question": "What should you do when you’re approaching traffic lights that have red and amber showing together?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-approaching-traffic-lights-that-have-red-and-amber-showing-together/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Stop because the lights are changing to red", "Take care because there's a fault with the lights", "Wait for the green light", "Pass the lights if the road is clear"], "answer": "Wait for the green light"},
{"id": "44001", "question": "What should you do when you’re approaching traffic lights that have been green for some time?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-approaching-traffic-lights-that-have-been-green-for-some-time/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Accelerate hard", "Maintain your speed", "Brake hard", "Be ready to stop"], "answer": "Be ready to stop"},
{"id": "44175", "question": "What should you do when you’re approaching this crossing?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2850.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-approaching-this-crossing/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Continue unless the pedestrians step out", "Stop and wave the pedestrians across", "Speed up and pass by quickly", "Prepare to slow down and stop"], "answer": "Prepare to slow down and stop"},
{"id": "44079", "question": "What should you do when you’re approaching roadworks on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-approaching-roadworks-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Stay very close to the vehicle in front", "Speed up to clear the area quickly", "Always use the hard shoulder", "Obey the speed limit"], "answer": "Obey the speed limit"},
{"id": "44106", "question": "What should you do when you’re approaching a bus that’s signalling to move away from a bus stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-youre-approaching-a-bus-thats-signalling-to-move-away-from-a-bus-stop-3/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Signal left and wave the bus on", "Get past before it moves", "Flash your headlights as you approach", "Allow it to pull away, if it's safe to do so"], "answer": "Allow it to pull away, if it's safe to do so"},
{"id": "44028", "question": "What should you do when you see this sign at a crossroads?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2579.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-see-this-sign-at-a-crossroads-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Maintain the same speed", "Find another route", "Telephone the police", "Carry on with great care"], "answer": "Carry on with great care"},
{"id": "43994", "question": "What should you do when you see this sign as you travel along a motorway?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2426.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-see-this-sign-as-you-travel-along-a-motorway-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Move onto the hard shoulder", "Leave the motorway at the next exit", "Change lane", "Turn left immediately"], "answer": "Leave the motorway at the next exit"},
{"id": "44102", "question": "What should you do when you see these horse riders in front?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2727.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-see-these-horse-riders-in-front/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Switch on your hazard warning lights", "Pull out to the middle of the road", "Slow down and be ready to stop", "Give a right-turn signal"], "answer": "Slow down and be ready to stop"},
{"id": "43683", "question": "What should you do when you see an older person about to cross the road ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-see-an-older-person-about-to-cross-the-road-ahead/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Expect them to wait for you to pass", "Be careful; they may misjudge your speed", "Speed up to get past them quickly", "Stop and wave them across the road"], "answer": "Be careful; they may misjudge your speed"},
{"id": "44158", "question": "What should you do when you park at night on a road that has a 40 mph speed limit?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-park-at-night-on-a-road-that-has-a-40-mph-speed-limit/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Park facing the traffic", "Leave dipped headlights switched on", "Leave parking lights switched on", "Park near a street light"], "answer": "Leave parking lights switched on"},
{"id": "44266", "question": "What should you do when you park a car facing downhill?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-park-a-car-facing-downhill/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Turn the steering wheel away from the kerb", "Turn the steering wheel towards the kerb", "Park with two wheels on the kerb", "Park close to the bumper of another car"], "answer": "Turn the steering wheel towards the kerb"},
{"id": "44364", "question": "What should you do when you move off from behind a parked car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-move-off-from-behind-a-parked-car/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Use the exterior mirrors only", "Give a signal after moving off", "Look around before moving off", "Look around after moving off"], "answer": "Look around before moving off"},
{"id": "44114", "question": "What should you do when you meet an oncoming vehicle on a single-track road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-meet-an-oncoming-vehicle-on-a-single-track-road-3/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Stop at a passing place", "Reverse back to the main road", "Carry out an emergency stop", "Switch on your hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Stop at a passing place"},
{"id": "44437", "question": "What should you do when you leave your car unattended for a few minutes?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-you-leave-your-car-unattended-for-a-few-minutes-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Switch the engine off but leave the key in", "Lock it and remove the key", "Park near a traffic warden", "Leave the engine running"], "answer": "Lock it and remove the key"},
{"id": "44041", "question": "What should you do when there’s an obstruction on your side of the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-theres-an-obstruction-on-your-side-of-the-road/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Accelerate to get past first", "Give way to oncoming traffic", "Carry on, as you have priority", "Wave oncoming vehicles through"], "answer": "Give way to oncoming traffic"},
{"id": "44376", "question": "What should you do when leaving your vehicle parked and unattended?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-leaving-your-vehicle-parked-and-unattended-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Park in a housing estate", "Park near a busy junction", "Lock it and remove the key", "Leave the left indicator on"], "answer": "Lock it and remove the key"},
{"id": "44038", "question": "What should you do when going through a contraflow system on a motorway?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2611.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-going-through-a-contraflow-system-on-a-motorway-3/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Stay close to the vehicle ahead to reduce queues", "Switch lanes to keep the traffic flowing", "Keep a good distance from the vehicle ahead", "Use dipped headlights"], "answer": "Keep a good distance from the vehicle ahead"},
{"id": "44500", "question": "What should you do when dealing with this hazard?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1718.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-dealing-with-this-hazard-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Use a high gear to prevent wheelspin", "Switch on your hazard warning lights", "Switch on your windscreen wipers", "Use a low gear and drive slowly"], "answer": "Use a low gear and drive slowly"},
{"id": "44250", "question": "What should you do when a person herding sheep asks you to stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-when-a-person-herding-sheep-asks-you-to-stop-2-2/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Continue on but drive slowly", "Try to get past quickly", "Ignore them as they have no authority", "Stop and switch off your engine"], "answer": "Stop and switch off your engine"},
{"id": "44445", "question": "What should you do to reduce the risk of your vehicle catching fire?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-to-reduce-the-risk-of-your-vehicle-catching-fire/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Check out any strong smell of fuel", "Use fuel additives", "Avoid driving with a full tank of fuel", "Keep water levels above maximum"], "answer": "Check out any strong smell of fuel"},
{"id": "44454", "question": "What should you do to avoid fuel spillage?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-to-avoid-fuel-spillage/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Check that your tank is only three-quarters full", "Check that you've used a locking filler cap", "Check that your fuel gauge is working", "Check that your filler cap is securely fastened"], "answer": "Check that your filler cap is securely fastened"},
{"id": "44117", "question": "What should you do immediately after joining a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-immediately-after-joining-a-motorway-4/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Position your vehicle in the centre lane", "Try to overtake", "Re-adjust your mirrors", "Stay in the left-hand lane"], "answer": "Stay in the left-hand lane"},
{"id": "44335", "question": "What should you do if you’re towing a trailer and it starts to swing from side to side?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-youre-towing-a-trailer-and-it-starts-to-swing-from-side-to-side/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Ease off the accelerator to reduce your speed", "Let go of the steering wheel and let it correct itself", "Accelerate until it stabilises", "Brake hard and hold the pedal down"], "answer": "Ease off the accelerator to reduce your speed"},
{"id": "44310", "question": "What should you do if you’re driving on a motorway and you miss the exit that you wanted to take?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-youre-driving-on-a-motorway-and-you-miss-the-exit-that-you-wanted-to-take/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Carry on to the next exit", "Carefully reverse along the hard shoulder", "Carefully reverse in the left-hand lane", "Make a U-turn at the next gap in the central reservation"], "answer": "Carry on to the next exit"},
{"id": "44451", "question": "What should you do if you’re driving a slow-moving vehicle on a narrow winding road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-youre-driving-a-slow-moving-vehicle-on-a-narrow-winding-road/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Wave the vehicles behind to come past you if you think they can overtake quickly", "Give a left signal when it's safe for vehicles to overtake you", "Pull in when you can, to let the vehicles behind overtake", "Keep well out to stop vehicles overtaking dangerously"], "answer": "Pull in when you can, to let the vehicles behind overtake"},
{"id": "43646", "question": "What should you do if you’re being followed by an ambulance showing flashing blue lights?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-youre-being-followed-by-an-ambulance-showing-flashing-blue-lights/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Pull over as soon as it's safe to do so", "Accelerate hard to get away from it", "Maintain your speed and course", "Brake harshly and stop well out into the road"], "answer": "Pull over as soon as it's safe to do so"},
{"id": "44359", "question": "What should you do if your vehicle pulls to one side when you use the brakes?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-vehicle-pulls-to-one-side-when-you-use-the-brakes/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Have the brakes checked as soon as possible", "Change gear and pump the brake pedal", "Use your parking brake at the same time", "Increase the pressure in your tyres"], "answer": "Have the brakes checked as soon as possible"},
{"id": "44334", "question": "What should you do if your vehicle has a puncture on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-vehicle-has-a-puncture-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Pull up on the hard shoulder or in an emergency refuge area and call for assistance", "Pull up on the hard shoulder or in an emergency refuge area. Change the wheel as quickly as possible", "Drive slowly to the next service area to get assistance", "Switch on your hazard warning lights. Stop in your lane"], "answer": "Pull up on the hard shoulder or in an emergency refuge area and call for assistance"},
{"id": "44502", "question": "What should you do if your vehicle catches fire while you’re driving through a tunnel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-vehicle-catches-fire-while-youre-driving-through-a-tunnel/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Leave it where it is, with the engine running", "Drive it out of the tunnel if it's safe to do so", "Park it away from the carriageway", "Pull up, then walk to an emergency telephone"], "answer": "Drive it out of the tunnel if it's safe to do so"},
{"id": "44490", "question": "What should you do if your vehicle breaks down in a tunnel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-vehicle-breaks-down-in-a-tunnel/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Stand in the lane behind your vehicle to warn others", "Switch on hazard warning lights, then go and call for help", "Stand in front of your vehicle to warn oncoming drivers", "Stay in your vehicle and wait for the police"], "answer": "Switch on hazard warning lights, then go and call for help"},
{"id": "47585", "question": "What should you do if your trailer starts to swerve or snake?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-trailer-starts-to-swerve-or-snake/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Brake firmly", "Steer sharply", "Increase speed", "Reduce speed gently"], "answer": "Reduce speed gently"},
{"id": "43637", "question": "What should you do if your mobile phone rings while you’re driving or riding?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-mobile-phone-rings-while-youre-driving-or-riding/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Pull up at the nearest kerb", "Stop immediately", "Leave it until you have stopped in a safe place", "Answer it immediately"], "answer": "Leave it until you have stopped in a safe place"},
{"id": "44252", "question": "What should you do if your anti-lock brakes (ABS) warning light stays on?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-your-anti-lock-brakes-abs-warning-light-stays-on-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Have the brakes checked immediately", "Check that the parking brake is released", "Check the brake-fluid level", "Check the footbrake free play"], "answer": "Have the brakes checked immediately"},
{"id": "43674", "question": "What should you do if you want to turn left at a junction where pedestrians have started to cross?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2119.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-want-to-turn-left-at-a-junction-where-pedestrians-have-started-to-cross/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Give way to them", "Sound your horn and proceed", "Stop and wave at them to cross", "Go around them, leaving plenty of room"], "answer": "Give way to them"},
{"id": "43722", "question": "What should you do if you want to overtake a tractor but aren’t sure that it’s safe?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-want-to-overtake-a-tractor-but-arent-sure-that-its-safe/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Speed past, flashing your lights at oncoming traffic", "Follow another vehicle as it overtakes the tractor", "Stay behind it if you're in any doubt", "Sound your horn to make the tractor driver pull over"], "answer": "Stay behind it if you're in any doubt"},
{"id": "44107", "question": "What should you do if you want to overtake a long, slow-moving vehicle on a busy road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-want-to-overtake-a-long-slow-moving-vehicle-on-a-busy-road/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Follow it closely and keep moving out to see the road ahead", "Stay behind until the driver waves you past", "Flash your headlights for the oncoming traffic to give way", "Keep well back so that you get a good view of the road ahead"], "answer": "Keep well back so that you get a good view of the road ahead"},
{"id": "44092", "question": "What should you do if you think the driver of the vehicle in front has forgotten to cancel their right indicator?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-think-the-driver-of-the-vehicle-in-front-has-forgotten-to-cancel-their-right-indicator-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Overtake on the left if there's room", "Stay behind and don't overtake", "Sound your horn before overtaking", "Flash your lights to alert the driver"], "answer": "Stay behind and don't overtake"},
{"id": "44528", "question": "What should you do if you start to feel drowsy while you’re driving on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-start-to-feel-drowsy-while-youre-driving-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Open a window and stop as soon as it's safe and legal", "Speed up to arrive at your destination sooner", "Slow down and let other drivers overtake", "Stop on the hard shoulder for a sleep"], "answer": "Open a window and stop as soon as it's safe and legal"},
{"id": "43735", "question": "What should you do if you see a pedestrian waiting at a zebra crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-see-a-pedestrian-waiting-at-a-zebra-crossing/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Stop before you reach the zigzag lines and let them cross", "Ignore them as they're still on the pavement", "Be ready to slow down or stop to let them cross", "Go on quickly before they step onto the crossing"], "answer": "Be ready to slow down or stop to let them cross"},
{"id": "44201", "question": "What should you do if you see a large box fall from a lorry onto the motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-see-a-large-box-fall-from-a-lorry-onto-the-motorway-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Pull over to the hard shoulder, then remove the box", "Stop close to the box until the police arrive", "Catch up with the lorry and try to get the driver's attention", "Go to the next emergency telephone and report the hazard"], "answer": "Go to the next emergency telephone and report the hazard"},
{"id": "44304", "question": "What should you do if you park on the road when it’s foggy?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-park-on-the-road-when-its-foggy-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Leave dipped headlights and fog lights switched on", "Leave dipped headlights switched on", "Leave parking lights switched on", "Leave main-beam headlights switched on"], "answer": "Leave parking lights switched on"},
{"id": "44501", "question": "What should you do if you overtake a cyclist when it’s very windy?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-overtake-a-cyclist-when-its-very-windy/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Overtake very slowly", "Sound your horn repeatedly", "Allow extra room", "Keep close as you pass"], "answer": "Allow extra room"},
{"id": "44077", "question": "What should you do if you have to stop while you’re going through a congested tunnel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-have-to-stop-while-youre-going-through-a-congested-tunnel/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Pull up very close to the vehicle in front to save space", "Keep a safe distance from the vehicle in front", "Ignore any message signs, as they're never up to date", "Make a U-turn and find another route"], "answer": "Keep a safe distance from the vehicle in front"},
{"id": "44035", "question": "What should you do if you have to make a journey in foggy conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-have-to-make-a-journey-in-foggy-conditions/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Keep two seconds behind the vehicle ahead", "Leave plenty of time for your journey", "Follow other vehicles' tail lights closely", "Avoid using dipped headlights"], "answer": "Leave plenty of time for your journey"},
{"id": "44430", "question": "What should you do if you can’t see clearly behind when you’re reversing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-cant-see-clearly-behind-when-youre-reversing-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Ask someone to guide you", "Open the window to look behind", "Open the door to look behind", "Look in the nearside mirror"], "answer": "Ask someone to guide you"},
{"id": "44282", "question": "What should you do if you begin to feel drowsy while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-begin-to-feel-drowsy-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Turn the heater up to keep you warm and comfortable", "Continue with your journey but drive more slowly", "Close the car windows to help you concentrate", "Stop and rest as soon as possible"], "answer": "Stop and rest as soon as possible"},
{"id": "44283", "question": "What should you do if you become tired while you’re driving on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-you-become-tired-while-youre-driving-on-a-motorway-2/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Increase your speed and turn up the radio volume", "Pull up on the hard shoulder and change drivers", "Close all your windows and set the heating to warm", "Leave the motorway at the next exit and rest"], "answer": "Leave the motorway at the next exit and rest"},
{"id": "44300", "question": "What should you do if there’s a bus at a bus stop ahead of you?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-theres-a-bus-at-a-bus-stop-ahead-of-you/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Continue at the same speed but sound your horn as a warning", "Flash your lights to warn the driver of your presence", "Watch carefully for the sudden appearance of pedestrians", "Pass the bus as quickly as you possibly can"], "answer": "Watch carefully for the sudden appearance of pedestrians"},
{"id": "44372", "question": "What should you do if the vehicle starts reversing off the driveway?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1397.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-the-vehicle-starts-reversing-off-the-driveway/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Speed up and drive through quickly", "Move to the opposite side of the road", "Sound your horn and be prepared to stop", "Drive through as you have priority"], "answer": "Sound your horn and be prepared to stop"},
{"id": "44468", "question": "What should you do if the traffic in the left-hand lane is slowing?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1666.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-the-traffic-in-the-left-hand-lane-is-slowing/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Accelerate past the vehicles in the left-hand lane", "Move across and continue in the right-hand lane", "Pull up on the left-hand verge", "Slow down, keeping a safe separation distance"], "answer": "Slow down, keeping a safe separation distance"},
{"id": "44032", "question": "What should you do if the red lights start flashing as you approach a level crossing?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2596.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-the-red-lights-start-flashing-as-you-approach-a-level-crossing/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Stop before the barrier", "Go over it quickly", "Switch on your hazard warning lights", "Go over it carefully"], "answer": "Stop before the barrier"},
{"id": "44104", "question": "What should you do if the left-hand pavement is closed due to street repairs?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-the-left-hand-pavement-is-closed-due-to-street-repairs-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Watch out for pedestrians walking in the road", "Position close to the left-hand kerb", "Use your right-hand mirror more often", "Speed up to get past the roadworks more quickly"], "answer": "Watch out for pedestrians walking in the road"},
{"id": "44318", "question": "What should you do if the amber lights come on and a warning sounds while you’re driving over a level crossing?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1227.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-the-amber-lights-come-on-and-a-warning-sounds-while-youre-driving-over-a-level-crossing/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Keep going and clear the crossing", "Stop and reverse back to clear the crossing", "Stop immediately and use your hazard warning lights", "Get everyone out of the vehicle immediately"], "answer": "Keep going and clear the crossing"},
{"id": "44466", "question": "What should you do if it’s raining and you’re following this lorry on a motorway?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1664.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-its-raining-and-youre-following-this-lorry-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Move into a lane that has less spray", "Allow a two-second separation gap", "Be aware of spray reducing your vision", "Switch your headlights onto main beam"], "answer": "Be aware of spray reducing your vision"},
{"id": "44489", "question": "What should you do if an instrument panel warning light comes on while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-an-instrument-panel-warning-light-comes-on-while-youre-driving/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Continue if the engine sounds all right", "Hope that it's just a temporary electrical fault", "Deal with the problem when there's more time", "Check out the problem quickly and safely"], "answer": "Check out the problem quickly and safely"},
{"id": "44381", "question": "What should you do if a vehicle pulls out in front of you at a junction?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-a-vehicle-pulls-out-in-front-of-you-at-a-junction/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Swerve past it and sound your horn", "Accelerate past it immediately", "Flash your headlights and drive up close behind", "Slow down and be ready to stop"], "answer": "Slow down and be ready to stop"},
{"id": "44333", "question": "What should you do if a tyre bursts while you’re driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-a-tyre-bursts-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Pull up slowly at the side of the road", "Pull on the parking brake", "Continue on at a normal speed", "Brake as quickly as possible"], "answer": "Pull up slowly at the side of the road"},
{"id": "43671", "question": "What should you do if a driver pulls out of a side road in front of you, causing you to brake hard?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-a-driver-pulls-out-of-a-side-road-in-front-of-you-causing-you-to-brake-hard/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Sound your horn to show your annoyance", "Ignore the error and stay calm", "Overtake as soon as possible", "Flash your lights to show your annoyance"], "answer": "Ignore the error and stay calm"},
{"id": "44280", "question": "What should you do if a doctor prescribes drugs that are likely to affect your driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-if-a-doctor-prescribes-drugs-that-are-likely-to-affect-your-driving/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Avoid driving on motorways", "Get someone else to drive", "Never drive at more than 30 mph", "Only drive if someone is with you"], "answer": "Get someone else to drive"},
{"id": "44530", "question": "What should you do first if your vehicle has broken down on an automatic railway level crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-first-if-your-vehicle-has-broken-down-on-an-automatic-railway-level-crossing/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Get everyone out of the vehicle and clear of the crossing", "Walk along the track to give warning to any approaching trains", "Try to push the vehicle clear of the crossing as soon as possible", "Telephone your vehicle recovery service to move it"], "answer": "Get everyone out of the vehicle and clear of the crossing"},
{"id": "47579", "question": "What should you do before you tow a trailer for the first time?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-before-you-tow-a-trailer-for-the-first-time/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Ask DVLA to update your licence", "Fit P plates to your trailer", "Pass a special driving test", "Take professional training"], "answer": "Take professional training"},
{"id": "44526", "question": "What should you do before starting a journey in foggy weather?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-before-starting-a-journey-in-foggy-weather/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Allow more time", "Wear a hi-visibility jacket", "Reduce your tyre pressures", "Have a caffeinated drink"], "answer": "Allow more time"},
{"id": "44053", "question": "What should you do before slowing down or stopping your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-before-slowing-down-or-stopping-your-vehicle/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Use the mirrors", "Flash the headlights", "Sound the horn", "Select a higher gear"], "answer": "Use the mirrors"},
{"id": "43633", "question": "What should you do before making a U-turn?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-before-making-a-u-turn-3/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Give an arm signal as well as using your indicators", "Check road markings to see that U-turns are permitted", "Look over your shoulder for a final check", "Select a higher gear than normal"], "answer": "Look over your shoulder for a final check"},
{"id": "44440", "question": "What should you do before driving into a tunnel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-before-driving-into-a-tunnel-2/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Switch on your windscreen wipers", "Close your sunroof", "Take off your sunglasses", "Switch off your radio"], "answer": "Take off your sunglasses"},
{"id": "44065", "question": "What should you do as you approach this overhead bridge?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2659.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-this-overhead-bridge-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Find another route; this one is only for high vehicles", "Move across to the right-hand side before going through", "Move out to the centre of the road before going through", "Be prepared to give way to large vehicles in the middle of the road"], "answer": "Be prepared to give way to large vehicles in the middle of the road"},
{"id": "44110", "question": "What should you do as you approach this lorry?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2737.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-this-lorry-4/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Move to the right-hand side of the road", "Make the lorry wait for you", "Flash your lights at the lorry", "Slow down and be prepared to wait"], "answer": "Slow down and be prepared to wait"},
{"id": "43666", "question": "What should you do as you approach this cyclist?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2099.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-this-cyclist/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Rev your engine so the cyclist knows you're following behind", "Try to overtake before the cyclist gets to the junction", "Flash your headlights at the cyclist", "Slow down and allow the cyclist to turn"], "answer": "Slow down and allow the cyclist to turn"},
{"id": "43634", "question": "What should you do as you approach this bridge?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2003.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-as-you-approach-this-bridge-3/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Change gear", "Slow down", "Move to the right", "Keep to 30 mph"], "answer": "Slow down"},
{"id": "44279", "question": "What should you do about driving if you’ve been taking medicine that causes drowsiness?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-do-about-driving-if-youve-been-taking-medicine-that-causes-drowsiness/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Ask someone to come with you", "Drive on quiet roads", "Avoid driving and check with your doctor", "Only drive if your journey is necessary"], "answer": "Avoid driving and check with your doctor"},
{"id": "44476", "question": "What should you check before you start a journey in foggy weather?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-check-before-you-start-a-journey-in-foggy-weather/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["You have a warning triangle in the vehicle", "The windows and lights are clean and clear", "You have a mobile phone with you", "The radiator has enough anti-freeze"], "answer": "The windows and lights are clean and clear"},
{"id": "44363", "question": "What should you be prepared to do in this situation?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1399.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-be-prepared-to-do-in-this-situation/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Report the driver to the police", "Slow down and give way", "Squeeze through the gap", "Sound your horn and continue"], "answer": "Slow down and give way"},
{"id": "44205", "question": "What should you be aware of if you’ve just passed this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2899.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-you-be-aware-of-if-youve-just-passed-this-sign/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["All traffic is going one way", "Only one lane is in use", "You can't stop on this road", "This is a single-track road"], "answer": "All traffic is going one way"},
{"id": "44063", "question": "What should the driver of the red car (arrowed) do?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2657.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-the-driver-of-the-red-car-arrowed-do-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Tell the pedestrian in the road she shouldn't have crossed", "Wave towards the pedestrians who are waiting to cross", "Wait for the pedestrian in the road to cross", "Quickly drive behind the pedestrian in the road"], "answer": "Wait for the pedestrian in the road to cross"},
{"id": "43664", "question": "What should the driver of the grey car be especially aware of?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2091.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-the-driver-of-the-grey-car-be-especially-aware-of/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Traffic following behind", "Doors opening on parked cars", "Empty parking spaces", "The uneven road surface"], "answer": "Doors opening on parked cars"},
{"id": "43663", "question": "What should the driver of the car approaching the crossing do?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2089.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-should-the-driver-of-the-car-approaching-the-crossing-do-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Slow down and get ready to stop", "Continue at the same speed", "Sound the horn", "Drive through quickly"], "answer": "Slow down and get ready to stop"},
{"id": "43759", "question": "What shape is a ‘stop’ sign?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-shape-is-a-stop-sign/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2324d.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2324b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2324c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2324a.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2324d.gif'>"},
{"id": "43739", "question": "What shape are traffic signs giving orders?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-shape-are-traffic-signs-giving-orders/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2294c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2294b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2294a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2294d.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/AB2294d.gif'>"},
{"id": "44493", "question": "What safety device must be fitted to a trailer braking system?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-safety-device-must-be-fitted-to-a-trailer-braking-system/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Jockey wheel", "Stabiliser", "Corner steadies", "Breakaway cable"], "answer": "Breakaway cable"},
{"id": "44442", "question": "What restrictions apply to people who have a provisional driving licence?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-restrictions-apply-to-people-who-have-a-provisional-driving-licence/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["They can't drive at night", "They can't drive over 30 mph", "They can't drive unaccompanied", "They can't drive with more than one passenger"], "answer": "They can't drive unaccompanied"},
{"id": "43999", "question": "What restrictions apply if you’re towing a trailer on a three-lane motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-restrictions-apply-if-youre-towing-a-trailer-on-a-three-lane-motorway/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["You must have a stabiliser fitted", "You mustn't exceed 50 mph", "You mustn't overtake", "You mustn't use the right-hand lane"], "answer": "You mustn't use the right-hand lane"},
{"id": "43659", "question": "What requires extra care when you’re driving or riding in windy conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-requires-extra-care-when-youre-driving-or-riding-in-windy-conditions/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Moving off on a hill", "Passing pedal cyclists", "Turning into a narrow road", "Using the brakes"], "answer": "Passing pedal cyclists"},
{"id": "44350", "question": "What part of the car does the law require you to keep in good condition?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-part-of-the-car-does-the-law-require-you-to-keep-in-good-condition/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The door locks", "The transmission", "The gearbox", "The seat belts"], "answer": "The seat belts"},
{"id": "44191", "question": "What must you have when you apply to renew your vehicle tax?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-have-when-you-apply-to-renew-your-vehicle-tax-2/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["The handbook", "The vehicle's chassis number", "A valid driving licence", "Valid insurance"], "answer": "Valid insurance"},
{"id": "44036", "question": "What must you do when you’re overtaking a car at night?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-when-youre-overtaking-a-car-at-night/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Make sure you don't dazzle other road users", "Select a higher gear", "Switch your headlights to main beam before overtaking", "Flash your headlights before overtaking"], "answer": "Make sure you don't dazzle other road users"},
{"id": "44131", "question": "What must you do when you see this sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2762.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-when-you-see-this-sign-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Stop even if the road is clear", "Stop only if traffic is approaching", "Stop only if a red light is showing", "Stop only if children are waiting to cross"], "answer": "Stop even if the road is clear"},
{"id": "47581", "question": "What must you do when you hitch a trailer to a towing vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-when-you-hitch-a-trailer-to-a-towing-vehicle/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Make sure you can see the trailer in the mirrors", "Switch off the reversing sensor on the towing vehicle", "Fit a secondary coupling device", "Grease the tow ball and hitch"], "answer": "Fit a secondary coupling device"},
{"id": "43639", "question": "What must you do when the amber light is flashing at a pelican crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-when-the-amber-light-is-flashing-at-a-pelican-crossing/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Stop and wait for the green light", "Stop and wait for the red light", "Give way to pedestrians waiting to cross", "Give way to pedestrians already on the crossing"], "answer": "Give way to pedestrians already on the crossing"},
{"id": "44419", "question": "What must you do if your eyesight has become very poor and you’re no longer able to meet the driver’s eyesight requirements?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-if-your-eyesight-has-become-very-poor-and-youre-no-longer-able-to-meet-the-drivers-eyesight-requirements/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Tell your doctor", "Tell your optician", "Tell the driver licensing authority", "Tell the police"], "answer": "Tell the driver licensing authority"},
{"id": "44281", "question": "What must you do if your ability to drive is impaired during a period of illness?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-if-your-ability-to-drive-is-impaired-during-a-period-of-illness/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Take smaller doses of any medicines", "Stop driving until you're fit to drive again", "See your doctor each time before you drive", "Take all your medicines with you when you drive"], "answer": "Stop driving until you're fit to drive again"},
{"id": "44081", "question": "What must you do if you come across roadworks that have a temporary speed limit displayed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-if-you-come-across-roadworks-that-have-a-temporary-speed-limit-displayed/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Use your own judgment; the limit is only advisory", "Obey the speed limit", "Obey the limit, but only during rush hour", "Ignore the displayed limit"], "answer": "Obey the speed limit"},
{"id": "44512", "question": "What must you do if poor health affects your driving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-if-poor-health-affects-your-driving/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Inform the licensing authority", "Always drive accompanied", "Inform your local police", "Avoid using motorways"], "answer": "Inform the licensing authority"},
{"id": "43670", "question": "What must you do at this junction?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2105.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-do-at-this-junction-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Stop beyond the line, at a point where you can see clearly", "Stop only if there's traffic on the main road", "Stop behind the line, then edge forward to see clearly", "Stop only if you're turning right"], "answer": "Stop behind the line, then edge forward to see clearly"},
{"id": "44329", "question": "What must you check before you drive someone else’s vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-must-you-check-before-you-drive-someone-elses-vehicle/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["That the insurance documents are in the vehicle", "That your own vehicle has insurance cover", "That the vehicle is insured for your use", "That the vehicle owner has third-party insurance cover"], "answer": "That the vehicle is insured for your use"},
{"id": "44274", "question": "What might you expect to happen in this situation?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1099.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-might-you-expect-to-happen-in-this-situation-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Traffic won't need to change position", "Traffic will move into the right-hand lane", "Traffic will move into the left-hand lane", "Traffic speed will increase"], "answer": "Traffic will move into the left-hand lane"},
{"id": "43764", "question": "What messages are given by circular traffic signs that have a blue background?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2333.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-messages-are-given-by-circular-traffic-signs-that-have-a-blue-background/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["They give motorway information", "They give directions to car parks", "They give mandatory instructions", "They give temporary directions during a diversion"], "answer": "They give mandatory instructions"},
{"id": "44374", "question": "What may help to deter a thief from stealing your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-may-help-to-deter-a-thief-from-stealing-your-car-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Always keeping the interior light on", "Always keeping the headlights on", "Fitting reflective glass windows", "Etching the registration number on the windows"], "answer": "Etching the registration number on the windows"},
{"id": "44336", "question": "What makes your tyres illegal?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-makes-your-tyres-illegal/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["If they have any large, deep cuts in the side wall", "If they're of different makes", "If they were bought second-hand", "If they have different tread patterns"], "answer": "If they have any large, deep cuts in the side wall"},
{"id": "43655", "question": "What makes the vehicle in the picture ‘environmentally friendly’?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2060.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-makes-the-vehicle-in-the-picture-environmentally-friendly-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["It's powered by electricity", "It's powered by gravity", "It's powered by unleaded petrol", "It's powered by diesel"], "answer": "It's powered by electricity"},
{"id": "44475", "question": "What lights should you use when you’re driving on a wet motorway and vehicles are throwing up surface spray?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-lights-should-you-use-when-youre-driving-on-a-wet-motorway-and-vehicles-are-throwing-up-surface-spray/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Sidelights", "Dipped headlights", "Rear fog lights", "Hazard warning lights"], "answer": "Dipped headlights"},
{"id": "44367", "question": "What legal requirement must be met by a newly qualified driver?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-legal-requirement-must-be-met-by-a-newly-qualified-driver/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["They must be accompanied on their first motorway journey", "They must have valid motor insurance", "They must have a new photograph taken for their full licence", "They must display green L plates"], "answer": "They must have valid motor insurance"},
{"id": "43949", "question": "What information would be shown in a triangular road sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2345.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-information-would-be-shown-in-a-triangular-road-sign-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Keep left", "Ahead only", "Road narrows", "Minimum speed"], "answer": "Road narrows"},
{"id": "44532", "question": "What information should you share if you’re involved in a collision that causes damage to another vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-information-should-you-share-if-youre-involved-in-a-collision-that-causes-damage-to-another-vehicle/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Your national insurance number", "Your internet service provider", "Your occupation and reason for your journey", "Your name, address and vehicle registration number"], "answer": "Your name, address and vehicle registration number"},
{"id": "44406", "question": "What information is found on a vehicle registration document?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-information-is-found-on-a-vehicle-registration-document-3/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["The type of insurance cover", "The date of the MOT", "The service history details", "The registered keeper"], "answer": "The registered keeper"},
{"id": "44165", "question": "What helps to reduce traffic bunching on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-helps-to-reduce-traffic-bunching-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Lane closures", "National speed limits", "Variable speed limits", "Contraflow systems"], "answer": "Variable speed limits"},
{"id": "43675", "question": "What hazard should you be especially aware of if you’re turning left into a side road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-hazard-should-you-be-especially-aware-of-if-youre-turning-left-into-a-side-road/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Traffic congestion", "One-way street", "Pedestrians", "Parked vehicles"], "answer": "Pedestrians"},
{"id": "44095", "question": "What hazard should you be aware of when travelling along this street?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2719.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-hazard-should-you-be-aware-of-when-travelling-along-this-street-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Glare from the sun", "Children running out between vehicles", "Large goods vehicles", "Lack of road markings"], "answer": "Children running out between vehicles"},
{"id": "44325", "question": "What does this white arrow on the road mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1236.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-white-arrow-on-the-road-mean-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Entrance on the left", "Road bends to the left", "All vehicles turn left", "Return to your side of the road"], "answer": "Return to your side of the road"},
{"id": "44027", "question": "What does this traffic sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2578.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-traffic-sign-mean-13/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Compulsory maximum speed limit", "Advisory maximum speed limit", "Compulsory minimum speed limit", "Advised separation distance"], "answer": "Compulsory maximum speed limit"},
{"id": "43958", "question": "What does this traffic sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2361.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-traffic-sign-mean-12/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Danger ahead", "Service area ahead", "Tyres liable to punctures ahead", "Slippery road ahead"], "answer": "Danger ahead"},
{"id": "43757", "question": "What does this traffic sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2319.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-traffic-sign-mean-11/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Give priority to oncoming traffic", "One-way traffic only", "Two-way traffic", "No overtaking allowed"], "answer": "Give priority to oncoming traffic"},
{"id": "44111", "question": "What does this signal mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2738.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-signal-mean-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Cars must stop", "Both trams and cars can continue", "Trams must stop", "Both trams and cars must stop"], "answer": "Trams must stop"},
{"id": "44172", "question": "What does this signal from a police officer mean to oncoming traffic?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2847.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-signal-from-a-police-officer-mean-to-oncoming-traffic-4/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Go ahead", "Turn right", "Stop", "Turn left"], "answer": "Stop"},
{"id": "44213", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2912.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-247/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Traffic danger spot ahead", "Tunnel ahead", "Low bridge ahead", "Ancient monument ahead"], "answer": "Tunnel ahead"},
{"id": "44199", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2889.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-246/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["School crossing patrol", "No pedestrians allowed", "Zebra crossing ahead", "Pedestrian zone - no vehicles"], "answer": "Zebra crossing ahead"},
{"id": "44197", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2886.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-245/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["With-flow bus and cycle lane", "Contraflow bus and cycle lane", "No waiting for buses and cycles", "No buses and cycles allowed"], "answer": "With-flow bus and cycle lane"},
{"id": "44166", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2840.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-244/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Cycle parking only", "No cycling", "Cycle route ahead", "End of cycle route"], "answer": "Cycle route ahead"},
{"id": "44138", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2769.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-243/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Parking area for cars and coaches", "Direction to bus and coach park", "No parking for buses or coaches", "Direction to park-and-ride car park"], "answer": "Direction to park-and-ride car park"},
{"id": "44136", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2767.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-242/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Uneven road", "Low bridge", "Hump bridge", "Traffic-calming hump"], "answer": "Hump bridge"},
{"id": "44135", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2766.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-241/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Two-way traffic crosses a one-way road", "Motorway contraflow system ahead", "Two-way traffic straight ahead", "Traffic approaching you has priority"], "answer": "Two-way traffic straight ahead"},
{"id": "44134", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2765.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-240/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Two-way traffic crosses a two-way road", "Two-way traffic over a bridge", "Two-way traffic straight ahead", "Two-way traffic crosses a one-way road"], "answer": "Two-way traffic crosses a one-way road"},
{"id": "44133", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2764.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-239/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Mini-roundabout", "Buses turning", "Keep right", "Ring road"], "answer": "Mini-roundabout"},
{"id": "44101", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2726.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-238/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Contraflow cycle lane", "With-flow cycle lane", "No cycles or buses", "Cycles and buses only"], "answer": "With-flow cycle lane"},
{"id": "44070", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2671.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-237/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Uneven road surface", "Road liable to flooding", "Quayside or river bank", "Steep hill downwards"], "answer": "Quayside or river bank"},
{"id": "44069", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2670.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-236/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No parking on the days and times shown", "You can park on the days and times shown", "No parking at all from Monday to Friday", "End of the urban clearway restrictions"], "answer": "No parking on the days and times shown"},
{"id": "44068", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2669.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-235/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Free-parking zone ends", "End of controlled parking zone", "End of traffic-calming zone", "No through road"], "answer": "End of controlled parking zone"},
{"id": "44030", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2591.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-234/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No cars", "Cars only", "Motorcycles only", "No motorcycles"], "answer": "No motorcycles"},
{"id": "44008", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2529.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-233/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Free recovery ends", "End of restriction", "Lane ends ahead", "End of motorway"], "answer": "End of restriction"},
{"id": "43995", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2428.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-232/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No through road", "No motor vehicles", "End of motorway", "End of bus lane"], "answer": "End of motorway"},
{"id": "43989", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2420.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-231/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Right-hand lane T-junction only", "Right-hand lane closed ahead", "11 tonne weight limit", "Through traffic to use left lane"], "answer": "Right-hand lane closed ahead"},
{"id": "43974", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2390.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-230/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Amber signal out of order", "New traffic lights ahead", "Traffic lights out of order", "Temporary traffic lights ahead"], "answer": "Traffic lights out of order"},
{"id": "43969", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2381.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-229/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Lane for heavy and slow vehicles", "Rest area for lorries", "All lorries use the hard shoulder", "Leave motorway at next exit"], "answer": "Lane for heavy and slow vehicles"},
{"id": "43968", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2379.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-228/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["One-way street", "Change to the left-hand lane", "Leave at the next exit", "Contraflow system"], "answer": "Contraflow system"},
{"id": "43967", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2378.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-227/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Right-hand lane for buses only", "The right-hand lane ahead is narrow", "The right-hand lane is closed", "Right-hand lane for turning right"], "answer": "The right-hand lane is closed"},
{"id": "43965", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2370.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-226/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Telephone box ahead", "T-junction", "No through road", "Toilet ahead"], "answer": "No through road"},
{"id": "43964", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2369.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-225/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Turn left for ferry terminal", "No entry for traffic turning left", "No through road on the left", "Turn left for parking area"], "answer": "No through road on the left"},
{"id": "43963", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2367.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-224/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Bridge over the road", "Water across the road", "Road ahead ends", "Uneven road surface"], "answer": "Water across the road"},
{"id": "43962", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2365.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-223/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Uneven road", "Steep hill downwards", "Steep hill upwards", "Adverse camber"], "answer": "Steep hill downwards"},
{"id": "43961", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2364.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-222/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Oncoming trams", "No trams ahead", "Trams only", "Trams crossing ahead"], "answer": "Trams crossing ahead"},
{"id": "43960", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2363.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-221/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Level crossing without gate or barrier", "Cattle grid ahead", "Gated road ahead", "Level crossing with gate or barrier"], "answer": "Level crossing with gate or barrier"},
{"id": "43957", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2360.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-220/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Adverse camber", "Road noise", "Airport", "Side winds"], "answer": "Side winds"},
{"id": "43956", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2358.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-219/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Road narrows", "End of dual carriageway", "Tall bridge", "End of narrow bridge"], "answer": "End of dual carriageway"},
{"id": "43954", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2353.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-218/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Humps in the road", "Entrance to tunnel", "Hump bridge", "Soft verges"], "answer": "Humps in the road"},
{"id": "43953", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2352.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-217/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Wait at the barriers", "Wait at the crossroads", "Give way to farm vehicles", "Give way to trams"], "answer": "Give way to trams"},
{"id": "43950", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2346.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-216/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Cycle route ahead", "Cyclists must dismount", "Cycle in single file", "Cycles aren't allowed"], "answer": "Cycle route ahead"},
{"id": "43948", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2344.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-215/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No vehicles", "Roundabout", "Mini-roundabout", "Ring road"], "answer": "Roundabout"},
{"id": "43772", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2343.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-213/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Crossroads", "Level crossing without gate", "Ahead only", "Level crossing with gate"], "answer": "Crossroads"},
{"id": "43771", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2342.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-212/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Risk of ice", "Place of historical interest", "Six roads converge", "Multi-exit roundabout"], "answer": "Risk of ice"},
{"id": "43770", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2341.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-211/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Give way", "No through road", "T-junction", "Turn left ahead"], "answer": "T-junction"},
{"id": "43768", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2339.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-210/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Level crossing", "Beware of trains", "Tourist attraction", "Beware of trams"], "answer": "Tourist attraction"},
{"id": "43766", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2336.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-209/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Bus station on the right", "Contraflow bus lane", "With-flow bus lane", "Give way to buses"], "answer": "Contraflow bus lane"},
{"id": "43763", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2332.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-208/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Route for buses", "Route for trams", "Give way to trams", "Give way to buses"], "answer": "Route for trams"},
{"id": "43762", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2331.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-207/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Turn off at the next available junction", "Approaching traffic passes you on both sides", "Pass either side to get to the same destination", "Give way to oncoming vehicles"], "answer": "Pass either side to get to the same destination"},
{"id": "43761", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2327.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-206/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Lay-by 30 miles ahead", "Service area 30 miles ahead", "Minimum speed 30 mph", "Maximum speed 30 mph"], "answer": "Minimum speed 30 mph"},
{"id": "43756", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2318.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-205/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Vehicles may park on the right-hand side of the road only", "Vehicles may not park on the verge or footway", "Vehicles may park fully on the verge or footway", "Vehicles may park on the left-hand side of the road only"], "answer": "Vehicles may park fully on the verge or footway"},
{"id": "43755", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2317.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-204/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Distance to public telephone ahead", "Distance to passing place ahead", "Distance to parking place ahead", "Distance to public house ahead"], "answer": "Distance to parking place ahead"},
{"id": "43754", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2316.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-203/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No stopping", "No entry", "Waiting restrictions apply", "National speed limit applies"], "answer": "No stopping"},
{"id": "43752", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2313.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-202/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["End of cycle route", "End of restricted parking area", "End of clearway", "End of restricted speed area"], "answer": "End of restricted parking area"},
{"id": "43751", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2311.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-201/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Waiting restrictions apply", "Clearway (no stopping)", "National speed limit applies", "Waiting permitted"], "answer": "Waiting restrictions apply"},
{"id": "43750", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2308.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-200/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No overtaking", "No motor vehicles", "Two-way traffic", "You have priority"], "answer": "No overtaking"},
{"id": "43747", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2305.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-199/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Route for buses only", "Parking for buses only", "Parking for trams only", "Route for trams only"], "answer": "Route for trams only"},
{"id": "43745", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2303.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-198/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Bend to the right", "Road on the right closed", "No right turn", "No traffic from the right"], "answer": "No right turn"},
{"id": "43744", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2302.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-197/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No through road", "No parking", "No entry", "No road markings"], "answer": "No entry"},
{"id": "43743", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2301.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-196/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Clearway (no stopping)", "Cars and motorcycles only", "No motor vehicles", "No overtaking"], "answer": "No motor vehicles"},
{"id": "43742", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2299.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-195/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["End of 20 mph zone", "New speed limit 20 mph", "No vehicles over 30 tonnes", "Minimum speed limit 30 mph"], "answer": "End of 20 mph zone"},
{"id": "43741", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2296.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-194/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Maximum speed limit with traffic calming", "'20 cars only' parking zone", "Minimum speed limit with traffic calming", "Only 20 cars allowed at any one time"], "answer": "Maximum speed limit with traffic calming"},
{"id": "43721", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2254.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-193/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Maximum speed 30 mph", "Minimum speed 30 mph", "End of maximum speed", "End of minimum speed"], "answer": "End of minimum speed"},
{"id": "43680", "question": "What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2134.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-mean-192/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["A route for cyclists only", "A route for pedestrians and cyclists", "A route for pedestrians only", "No route for pedestrians and cyclists"], "answer": "A route for pedestrians and cyclists"},
{"id": "44009", "question": "What does this sign indicate?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2530.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-sign-indicate-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["A picnic area", "A diversion route", "A cycle route", "A pedestrian zone"], "answer": "A diversion route"},
{"id": "43979", "question": "What does this road marking mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2398.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-road-marking-mean-6/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Don't cross the line", "No stopping allowed", "You're approaching a hazard", "No overtaking allowed"], "answer": "You're approaching a hazard"},
{"id": "43988", "question": "What does this motorway sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2419.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-motorway-sign-mean-12/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Obstruction 50 metres (164 feet) ahead", "Temporary minimum speed 50 mph", "Temporary maximum speed 50 mph", "No services for 50 miles"], "answer": "Temporary maximum speed 50 mph"},
{"id": "43987", "question": "What does this motorway sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2418.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-motorway-sign-mean-11/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Change to the opposite carriageway", "Change to the lane on your left", "Leave the motorway at the next exit", "Pull up on the hard shoulder"], "answer": "Change to the lane on your left"},
{"id": "43983", "question": "What does this line across the road at the entrance to a roundabout mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2403.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-line-across-the-road-at-the-entrance-to-a-roundabout-mean/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Stop at the line", "You have right of way", "Traffic from the left has right of way", "Give way to traffic from the right"], "answer": "Give way to traffic from the right"},
{"id": "43636", "question": "What does this curved arrow road marking mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2007.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-curved-arrow-road-marking-mean/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Overtaking traffic should move back to the left", "The road ahead bends to the left", "The road ahead has a camber to the left", "Heavy vehicles should take the next road on the left to avoid a weight limit"], "answer": "Overtaking traffic should move back to the left"},
{"id": "43986", "question": "What does this arm signal mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2408.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-this-arm-signal-mean-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["The driver is slowing down", "The driver intends to turn right", "The driver intends to turn left", "The driver wishes to overtake"], "answer": "The driver intends to turn left"},
{"id": "44496", "question": "What does third-party insurance cover?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-third-party-insurance-cover-2/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Damage to your vehicle", "Damage to other vehicles", "Injury to yourself", "All damage and injury"], "answer": "Damage to other vehicles"},
{"id": "44324", "question": "What does the white line along the side of the road indicate?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1235.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-the-white-line-along-the-side-of-the-road-indicate-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["The approach to a hazard", "No overtaking", "No parking", "The edge of the carriageway"], "answer": "The edge of the carriageway"},
{"id": "44446", "question": "What does the term ‘blind spot’ mean?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-the-term-blind-spot-mean-2/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["An area covered by your left-hand mirror", "An area not covered by your headlights", "An area not visible to the driver", "An area covered by your right-hand mirror"], "answer": "An area not visible to the driver"},
{"id": "44269", "question": "What does the solid white line at the side of the road indicate?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1081.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-the-solid-white-line-at-the-side-of-the-road-indicate-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Cycle path", "Edge of the carriageway", "Footpath on the left", "Traffic lights ahead"], "answer": "Edge of the carriageway"},
{"id": "44080", "question": "What does it mean when a moving vehicle is showing a flashing amber beacon?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-when-a-moving-vehicle-is-showing-a-flashing-amber-beacon/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["The vehicle is a doctor's car", "The vehicle has broken down", "The vehicle belongs to a school crossing patrol", "The vehicle is slow moving"], "answer": "The vehicle is slow moving"},
{"id": "44256", "question": "What does it mean if your vehicle keeps bouncing after you sharply press down and release on the bodywork over a wheel?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-your-vehicle-keeps-bouncing-after-you-sharply-press-down-and-release-on-the-bodywork-over-a-wheel/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The vehicle is on soft ground", "The tyres are under inflated", "The tyres are worn", "The shock absorbers are worn"], "answer": "The shock absorbers are worn"},
{"id": "47584", "question": "What does it mean if your trailer has a maximum authorised mass (MAM) of 3,500 kg?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-your-trailer-has-a-maximum-authorised-mass-mam-of-3500-kg/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Your trailer and towing vehicle combined cannot weigh more than 3,500 kg", "Your trailer and load combined cannot weigh more than 3,500 kg", "Your trailer can carry a load of 3,500 kg", "Your empty trailer weighs 3,500 kg "], "answer": "Your trailer and load combined cannot weigh more than 3,500 kg"},
{"id": "44498", "question": "What does it mean if your insurance policy has an excess of £500?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-your-insurance-policy-has-an-excess-of-500/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["Your vehicle is insured for a value of £500 if it's stolen", "The insurance company will pay the first £500 of any claim", "You'll be paid £500 if you don't claim within one year", "You'll have to pay the first £500 of the cost of any claim"], "answer": "You'll have to pay the first £500 of the cost of any claim"},
{"id": "44130", "question": "What does it mean if you see this signal on the motorway?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2760.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-you-see-this-signal-on-the-motorway/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Stop: all lanes ahead closed", "All vehicles use the hard shoulder", "Sharp bend to the left ahead", "Leave the motorway at the next exit"], "answer": "Leave the motorway at the next exit"},
{"id": "44176", "question": "What does it mean if you see a pedestrian with a dog that has a yellow or burgundy coat?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-you-see-a-pedestrian-with-a-dog-that-has-a-yellow-or-burgundy-coat/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["The pedestrian is colour-blind", "The pedestrian is a dog trainer", "The pedestrian is an older person", "The pedestrian is deaf"], "answer": "The pedestrian is deaf"},
{"id": "44253", "question": "What does it mean if this light comes on while you’re driving?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1039.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-this-light-comes-on-while-youre-driving-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["A fault in the braking system", "Your seat belt isn't fastened", "A rear light has failed", "The engine oil is low"], "answer": "A fault in the braking system"},
{"id": "44249", "question": "What does it mean if the signs at a bus lane show no times of operation?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1022.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-the-signs-at-a-bus-lane-show-no-times-of-operation/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["The lane isn't in operation", "The lane is only in operation at peak times", "The lane is in operation 24 hours a day", "The lane is only in operation in daylight hours"], "answer": "The lane is in operation 24 hours a day"},
{"id": "44536", "question": "What does it mean if the Electronic Stability Control (ESC) indicator lamp lights up while you’re driving?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BB4417.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-it-mean-if-the-electronic-stability-control-esc-indicator-lamp-lights-up-while-youre-driving/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The ESC system is running a routine test", "The ESC system has activated", "The ESC system is switched off", "The ESC system has a fault"], "answer": "The ESC system has activated"},
{"id": "44504", "question": "What does fuel-efficient driving achieve?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-fuel-efficient-driving-achieve/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Damage to the environment", "Increased fuel consumption", "Improved road safety", "Increased exhaust emissions"], "answer": "Improved road safety"},
{"id": "43767", "question": "What does a sign with a brown background show?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2338.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-a-sign-with-a-brown-background-show-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Primary roads", "Minor roads", "Tourist directions", "Motorway routes"], "answer": "Tourist directions"},
{"id": "43970", "question": "What does a red traffic light mean?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-a-red-traffic-light-mean-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Stop, if you're able to brake safely", "You should stop unless turning left", "Proceed with care", "You must stop and wait behind the stop line"], "answer": "You must stop and wait behind the stop line"},
{"id": "43990", "question": "What does ’25’ mean on this motorway sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2422.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-does-25-mean-on-this-motorway-sign-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["The route number of the road", "The distance to the nearest town", "The number of the next junction", "The speed limit on the slip road"], "answer": "The number of the next junction"},
{"id": "44190", "question": "What do you need before you can legally use a motor vehicle on the road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-do-you-need-before-you-can-legally-use-a-motor-vehicle-on-the-road/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["An appropriate driving licence", "A vehicle handbook", "Proof of your identity", "Breakdown cover"], "answer": "An appropriate driving licence"},
{"id": "43977", "question": "What do these zigzag white lines mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2394.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-do-these-zigzag-white-lines-mean/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["No parking at any time", "Sounding horns isn't allowed", "Slow down to 20 mph", "Parking allowed only for a short time"], "answer": "No parking at any time"},
{"id": "43713", "question": "What do these motorway signs mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2241.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-do-these-motorway-signs-mean/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["They're countdown markers to a bridge", "They warn of a police control ahead", "They're distance markers to the next telephone", "They're countdown markers to the next exit"], "answer": "They're countdown markers to the next exit"},
{"id": "44072", "question": "What do the long white lines along the centre of the road mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2676.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-do-the-long-white-lines-along-the-centre-of-the-road-mean/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Lane marking", "Bus lane", "Hazard warning", "Give way"], "answer": "Hazard warning"},
{"id": "44344", "question": "What could you do to reduce the volume of traffic on the roads?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-could-you-do-to-reduce-the-volume-of-traffic-on-the-roads-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Travel by car at all times", "Walk or cycle on short journeys", "Drive in a bus lane", "Use a car with a smaller engine"], "answer": "Walk or cycle on short journeys"},
{"id": "44218", "question": "What could you do to help injured people at an incident?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-could-you-do-to-help-injured-people-at-an-incident/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Keep them warm and comfortable", "Give them a warm drink", "Keep them on the move by walking them around", "Give them something to eat"], "answer": "Keep them warm and comfortable"},
{"id": "44230", "question": "What could cause you to crash if the level is allowed to get too low?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-could-cause-you-to-crash-if-the-level-is-allowed-to-get-too-low/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Battery-water level", "Radiator-coolant level", "Brake-fluid level", "Anti-freeze level"], "answer": "Brake-fluid level"},
{"id": "43715", "question": "What colour are the reflective studs between the lanes on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-colour-are-the-reflective-studs-between-the-lanes-on-a-motorway-5/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Amber", "White", "Red", "Green"], "answer": "White"},
{"id": "44025", "question": "What colour are the reflective studs between the hard shoulder and the left-hand lane of a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-colour-are-the-reflective-studs-between-the-hard-shoulder-and-the-left-hand-lane-of-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Green", "White", "Amber", "Red"], "answer": "Red"},
{"id": "43716", "question": "What colour are the reflective studs between a motorway and a slip road?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-colour-are-the-reflective-studs-between-a-motorway-and-a-slip-road/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["White", "Red", "Green", "Amber"], "answer": "Green"},
{"id": "44021", "question": "What colour are the reflective studs along the left-hand edge of the motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-colour-are-the-reflective-studs-along-the-left-hand-edge-of-the-motorway/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["White", "Red", "Green", "Amber"], "answer": "Red"},
{"id": "44408", "question": "What circumstances require you to notify the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency (DVLA)?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-circumstances-require-you-to-notify-the-driver-and-vehicle-licensing-agency-dvla/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["When you have to work abroad", "When you lend your vehicle to someone", "When your vehicle needs an MOT certificate", "When your health affects your driving"], "answer": "When your health affects your driving"},
{"id": "44162", "question": "What can you expect if you drive using rapid acceleration and heavy braking?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-you-expect-if-you-drive-using-rapid-acceleration-and-heavy-braking/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Increased fuel consumption", "Reduced exhaust emissions", "Increased road safety", "Reduced pollution"], "answer": "Increased fuel consumption"},
{"id": "44455", "question": "What can you do to reduce environmental damage caused by your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-you-do-to-reduce-environmental-damage-caused-by-your-vehicle/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Use the gears to slow the vehicle", "Use the air conditioning whenever you drive", "Avoid using the cruise control", "Avoid making a lot of short journeys"], "answer": "Avoid making a lot of short journeys"},
{"id": "44285", "question": "What can you do to help prevent tiredness on a long journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-you-do-to-help-prevent-tiredness-on-a-long-journey/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Take regular refreshment breaks", "Eat a large meal before driving", "Complete the journey without stopping", "Play loud music in the car"], "answer": "Take regular refreshment breaks"},
{"id": "44494", "question": "What can you achieve if you drive smoothly?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-you-achieve-if-you-drive-smoothly/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Increase in fuel consumption by about 15%", "Increase in journey times by about 15%", "Reduction in journey times by about 15%", "Reduction in fuel consumption by about 15%"], "answer": "Reduction in fuel consumption by about 15%"},
{"id": "44417", "question": "What can seriously reduce your ability to concentrate?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-seriously-reduce-your-ability-to-concentrate/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Tinted windows", "Drugs", "Weather conditions", "Busy roads"], "answer": "Drugs"},
{"id": "44511", "question": "What can result when you travel for long distances in neutral (known as coasting)?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-result-when-you-travel-for-long-distances-in-neutral-known-as-coasting-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Improvement in control", "Reduction in control", "Easier steering", "Increased fuel consumption"], "answer": "Reduction in control"},
{"id": "44456", "question": "What can people who live or work in towns and cities do to help reduce urban pollution levels?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-people-who-live-or-work-in-towns-and-cities-do-to-help-reduce-urban-pollution-levels-2/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Drive more quickly", "Walk or cycle", "Over-rev in a low gear", "Drive short journeys"], "answer": "Walk or cycle"},
{"id": "44088", "question": "What can cause excessive or uneven tyre wear?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-cause-excessive-or-uneven-tyre-wear-4/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["A faulty gearbox", "A faulty exhaust system", "A faulty electrical system", "A faulty braking system"], "answer": "A faulty braking system"},
{"id": "44368", "question": "What can be damaged if you turn the steering wheel when the car isn’t moving?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-can-be-damaged-if-you-turn-the-steering-wheel-when-the-car-isnt-moving/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The tyres", "The gearbox", "The engine", "The brakes"], "answer": "The tyres"},
{"id": "44278", "question": "What advice should you give to a driver who has had a few alcoholic drinks at a party?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-advice-should-you-give-to-a-driver-who-has-had-a-few-alcoholic-drinks-at-a-party-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Drive home carefully and slowly", "Have a strong cup of coffee and then drive home", "Wait a short while and then drive home", "Go home by public transport"], "answer": "Go home by public transport"},
{"id": "44004", "question": "What action should you take when you see flashing amber lights under a school warning sign?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2516.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/what-action-should-you-take-when-you-see-flashing-amber-lights-under-a-school-warning-sign/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Keep up your speed and sound the horn", "Wait at the lights until they stop flashing", "Increase your speed to clear the area quickly", "Reduce speed until you're clear of the area"], "answer": "Reduce speed until you're clear of the area"},
{"id": "44144", "question": "Traffic officers operate on motorways and some primary routes in England and Wales. What are they authorised to do?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2788.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/traffic-officers-operate-on-motorways-and-some-primary-routes-in-england-and-wales-what-are-they-authorised-to-do/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Repair broken-down vehicles on the motorway", "Stop and arrest drivers who break the law", "Stop and direct anyone on a motorway", "Issue fixed penalty notices"], "answer": "Stop and direct anyone on a motorway"},
{"id": "44182", "question": "This junction, controlled by traffic lights, has a marked area between two stop lines. What’s this for?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2860.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/this-junction-controlled-by-traffic-lights-has-a-marked-area-between-two-stop-lines-whats-this-for/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["To allow people with disabilities to cross the road", "To allow taxis to position in front of other traffic", "To allow cyclists and pedestrians to cross the road together", "To allow cyclists to position in front of other traffic"], "answer": "To allow cyclists to position in front of other traffic"},
{"id": "44443", "question": "There’s been a heavy fall of snow. What should you consider before driving in these conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/theres-been-a-heavy-fall-of-snow-what-should-you-consider-before-driving-in-these-conditions/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["Whether your journey is essential", "Whether you should fit an amber flashing beacon to your car", "Whether you should wear sunglasses to reduce the glare", "Whether you should drive without wearing your seat belt"], "answer": "Whether your journey is essential"},
{"id": "44219", "question": "There’s been a collision. How can you help a driver who’s suffering from shock?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/theres-been-a-collision-how-can-you-help-a-driver-whos-suffering-from-shock/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Give them a drink", "Reassure them confidently", "Ask who caused the incident", "Offer them a cigarette"], "answer": "Reassure them confidently"},
{"id": "44239", "question": "There’s been a collision. A motorcyclist is lying injured and unconscious. Why should you only remove their helmet if it’s essential?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/theres-been-a-collision-a-motorcyclist-is-lying-injured-and-unconscious-why-should-you-only-remove-their-helmet-if-its-essential/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["You could scratch the helmet as you remove it", "They might not want you to remove it", "Removing it could let them get cold", "Removing it could make any injuries worse"], "answer": "Removing it could make any injuries worse"},
{"id": "44241", "question": "There are objects hanging from your interior mirror. Why could this be a hazard?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/there-are-objects-hanging-from-your-interior-mirror-why-could-this-be-a-hazard/", "category": "Alertness", "options": ["Your view could be obstructed", "Your sun visor might get tangled", "Your radio reception might be affected", "Your windscreen could mist up more easily"], "answer": "Your view could be obstructed"},
{"id": "43719", "question": "There are no speed-limit signs on the road. How is a 30 mph limit generally indicated?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/there-are-no-speed-limit-signs-on-the-road-how-is-a-30-mph-limit-generally-indicated/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["By hazard warning lines", "By pedestrian islands", "By double or single yellow lines", "By street lighting"], "answer": "By street lighting"},
{"id": "44423", "question": "The road outside this school is marked with yellow zigzag lines. What do these lines mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1577.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/the-road-outside-this-school-is-marked-with-yellow-zigzag-lines-what-do-these-lines-mean-4/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["You must stay with your vehicle if you park here", "You may park on the lines when dropping off schoolchildren", "You shouldn't wait or park your vehicle here", "You may park on the lines when picking up schoolchildren"], "answer": "You shouldn't wait or park your vehicle here"},
{"id": "44154", "question": "The road is wet. Why would a motorcyclist steer around drain covers while they were cornering?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/the-road-is-wet-why-would-a-motorcyclist-steer-around-drain-covers-while-they-were-cornering/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["To prevent the motorcycle sliding on the metal drain covers", "To avoid splashing pedestrians on the pavement", "To avoid puncturing the tyres on the edge of the drain covers", "To help judge the bend using the drain covers as marker points"], "answer": "To prevent the motorcycle sliding on the metal drain covers"},
{"id": "44061", "question": "The fluid level in your battery is low. What fluid should you use to top it up?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/the-fluid-level-in-your-battery-is-low-what-fluid-should-you-use-to-top-it-up/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Engine coolant", "Battery acid", "Engine oil", "Distilled water"], "answer": "Distilled water"},
{"id": "44082", "question": "The conditions are good and dry. When should you use the ‘two-second rule’?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/the-conditions-are-good-and-dry-when-should-you-use-the-two-second-rule-3/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["When checking your gap from the vehicle in front", "Before restarting the engine after it has stalled", "Before using the 'Mirrors - Signal - Manoeuvre' routine", "When traffic lights change to green"], "answer": "When checking your gap from the vehicle in front"},
{"id": "44109", "question": "Some two-way roads are divided into three lanes. Why are they particularly dangerous?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/some-two-way-roads-are-divided-into-three-lanes-why-are-they-particularly-dangerous/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Traffic in both directions can use the middle lane to overtake", "Traffic can travel faster in poor weather conditions", "Traffic can overtake on the left", "Traffic uses the middle lane for emergencies only"], "answer": "Traffic in both directions can use the middle lane to overtake"},
{"id": "44066", "question": "Powered vehicles used by disabled people are small and can be hard to see. What must they display if they’re travelling on a dual carriageway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/powered-vehicles-used-by-disabled-people-are-small-and-can-be-hard-to-see-what-must-they-display-if-theyre-travelling-on-a-dual-carriageway/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Flashing amber beacon", "Flashing green beacon", "Flashing blue beacon", "Flashing red beacon"], "answer": "Flashing amber beacon"},
{"id": "44444", "question": "Other than direction indicators, how can you give signals to other road users?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/other-than-direction-indicators-how-can-you-give-signals-to-other-road-users-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["By using sidelights", "By using fog lights", "By using interior lights", "By using brake lights"], "answer": "By using brake lights"},
{"id": "44078", "question": "Other drivers may sometimes flash their headlights at you. What’s the official meaning of this signal?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/other-drivers-may-sometimes-flash-their-headlights-at-you-whats-the-official-meaning-of-this-signal/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["There's a fault with your vehicle", "There's a radar speed trap ahead", "They're warning you of their presence", "They're giving way to you"], "answer": "They're warning you of their presence"},
{"id": "44346", "question": "On what type of road surface may anti-lock brakes be ineffective?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/on-what-type-of-road-surface-may-anti-lock-brakes-be-ineffective/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Firm", "Smooth", "Loose", "Dry"], "answer": "Loose"},
{"id": "44462", "question": "On a vehicle, where would you find a catalytic converter?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/on-a-vehicle-where-would-you-find-a-catalytic-converter-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["On the exhaust system", "On the cooling system", "In the fuel tank", "In the air filter"], "answer": "On the exhaust system"},
{"id": "44037", "question": "On a three-lane motorway, which lane should you use if there’s no traffic ahead?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/on-a-three-lane-motorway-which-lane-should-you-use-if-theres-no-traffic-ahead/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Centre", "Right", "Either the right or centre", "Left"], "answer": "Left"},
{"id": "44181", "question": "On a smart motorway, what does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2857.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/on-a-smart-motorway-what-does-this-sign-mean/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Use any lane except the hard shoulder", "Use the hard shoulder only", "Use the three right-hand lanes only", "Use all the lanes, including the hard shoulder"], "answer": "Use all the lanes, including the hard shoulder"},
{"id": "43649", "question": "On a road where trams operate, which vehicles will be most at risk from the tram rails?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/on-a-road-where-trams-operate-which-vehicles-will-be-most-at-risk-from-the-tram-rails/", "category": "Attitude", "options": ["Cars", "Buses", "Cycles", "Lorries"], "answer": "Cycles"},
{"id": "44299", "question": "It’s very windy. What should you do if you’re behind a motorcyclist who’s overtaking a high-sided vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/its-very-windy-what-should-you-do-if-youre-behind-a-motorcyclist-whos-overtaking-a-high-sided-vehicle-2/", "category": "Other types of vehicle", "options": ["Overtake the motorcyclist immediately", "Stay level with the motorcyclist", "Keep well back", "Keep close to the motorcyclist"], "answer": "Keep well back"},
{"id": "43760", "question": "In winter, road signs can become covered by snow. What does this sign mean?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/AB2325.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/in-winter-road-signs-can-become-covered-by-snow-what-does-this-sign-mean/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Give way", "Crossroads", "Stop", "Turn right"], "answer": "Stop"},
{"id": "44382", "question": "In which conditions will your overall stopping distance increase?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/in-which-conditions-will-your-overall-stopping-distance-increase-2/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["In strong winds", "At night", "In fog", "In the rain"], "answer": "In the rain"},
{"id": "44486", "question": "In order to supervise a learner driver you need to have held a full driving licence for the same category of vehicle, for at least three years. What other requirement must you meet?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/in-order-to-supervise-a-learner-driver-you-need-to-have-held-a-full-driving-licence-for-the-same-category-of-vehicle-for-at-least-three-years-what-other-requirement-must-you-meet/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["To have a car with dual controls", "To hold an advanced driving certificate", "To be an approved driving instructor", "To be at least 21 years old"], "answer": "To be at least 21 years old"},
{"id": "44255", "question": "If you’re involved in a collision, what will reduce the risk of neck injury?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/if-youre-involved-in-a-collision-what-will-reduce-the-risk-of-neck-injury/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["A properly adjusted head restraint", "An air-sprung seat", "A collapsible steering wheel", "Anti-lock brakes"], "answer": "A properly adjusted head restraint"},
{"id": "43653", "question": "How would under-inflated tyres affect your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-would-under-inflated-tyres-affect-your-vehicle/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The vehicle's gear change mechanism would become stiff", "The flash rate of the vehicle's indicators would increase", "The vehicle's stopping distance would increase", "The vehicle's headlights would aim high"], "answer": "The vehicle's stopping distance would increase"},
{"id": "43672", "question": "How would age affect an older person’s driving ability?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-would-age-affect-an-older-persons-driving-ability/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["They'll take longer to react to hazards", "They won't be able to obtain car insurance", "They won't signal at junctions", "They'll need glasses to read road signs"], "answer": "They'll take longer to react to hazards"},
{"id": "44150", "question": "How will your journey be affected by travelling outside the busy times of day?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-your-journey-be-affected-by-travelling-outside-the-busy-times-of-day/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Your journey will take longer", "Your journey will have fewer delays", "Your journey will use more fuel", "Your journey will be more hazardous"], "answer": "Your journey will have fewer delays"},
{"id": "44414", "question": "How will you benefit from following the manufacturer’s service schedule for your vehicle?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-you-benefit-from-following-the-manufacturers-service-schedule-for-your-vehicle/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Your vehicle tax will be lower", "Your vehicle will remain reliable", "Your vehicle will be cheaper to insure", "Your journey times will be reduced"], "answer": "Your vehicle will remain reliable"},
{"id": "43678", "question": "How will a school crossing patrol signal you to stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-a-school-crossing-patrol-signal-you-to-stop-6/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["By giving you an arm signal", "By displaying a red light", "By pointing to children waiting to cross", "By displaying a 'stop' sign"], "answer": "By displaying a 'stop' sign"},
{"id": "44257", "question": "How will a roof rack affect your car?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-a-roof-rack-affect-your-car/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["The engine will use more oil", "The car will accelerate faster", "There will be less wind noise", "Fuel consumption will increase"], "answer": "Fuel consumption will increase"},
{"id": "43984", "question": "How will a police officer in a patrol vehicle signal for you to stop?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-a-police-officer-in-a-patrol-vehicle-signal-for-you-to-stop/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Flash the headlights, indicate left and point to the left", "Pull alongside you, use the siren and wave you to stop", "Use the siren, overtake, cut in front and stop", "Overtake and give a slowing down arm signal"], "answer": "Flash the headlights, indicate left and point to the left"},
{"id": "44357", "question": "How will a heavy load on your roof rack affect your vehicle’s handling?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-will-a-heavy-load-on-your-roof-rack-affect-your-vehicles-handling-2/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["It will make the steering lighter", "It will reduce the stopping distance", "It will reduce stability", "It will improve the road holding"], "answer": "It will reduce stability"},
{"id": "44123", "question": "How should you use the lanes on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-use-the-lanes-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Keep to the left-hand lane unless you're overtaking", "Use the lane that has the least traffic", "Overtake using the lane that's clearest", "Stay in one lane until you reach your exit"], "answer": "Keep to the left-hand lane unless you're overtaking"},
{"id": "44465", "question": "How should you use anti-lock brakes when you need to stop in an emergency?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-use-anti-lock-brakes-when-you-need-to-stop-in-an-emergency/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Brake promptly and firmly until you've stopped", "Apply the parking brake to reduce the stopping distance", "Brake normally but grip the steering wheel tightly", "Keep pumping the footbrake to prevent skidding"], "answer": "Brake promptly and firmly until you've stopped"},
{"id": "44195", "question": "How should you signal if you’re going straight ahead at a roundabout?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-signal-if-youre-going-straight-ahead-at-a-roundabout/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["Signal right on the approach and then left to leave the roundabout", "Signal right on the approach to the roundabout and keep the signal on", "Signal left just after you pass the exit before the one you're going to take", "Signal left after you leave the roundabout and enter the new road"], "answer": "Signal left just after you pass the exit before the one you're going to take"},
{"id": "47548", "question": "How should you rejoin the motorway after a breakdown on the hard shoulder?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-rejoin-the-motorway-after-a-breakdown-on-the-hard-shoulder/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Wait until a vehicle in the left-hand lane signals to you that it's safe to rejoin", "Keep your hazard lights flashing until you have safely rejoined the carriageway", "Build up speed on the hard shoulder before looking for a safe gap in the traffic", "Move straight out into the left-hand lane as you are not allowed to drive on the hard shoulder"], "answer": "Build up speed on the hard shoulder before looking for a safe gap in the traffic"},
{"id": "44018", "question": "How should you react to inexperienced drivers?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-react-to-inexperienced-drivers-2/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Overtake them as soon as possible", "Flash your headlights to indicate that it's safe for them to proceed", "Be patient and prepare for them to react more slowly", "Sound your horn to warn them of your presence"], "answer": "Be patient and prepare for them to react more slowly"},
{"id": "44024", "question": "How should you position yourself when you use the emergency telephone on a motorway?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-position-yourself-when-you-use-the-emergency-telephone-on-a-motorway/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["Stand on the hard shoulder", "Stay close to the carriageway", "Face the oncoming traffic", "Keep your back to the traffic"], "answer": "Face the oncoming traffic"},
{"id": "44298", "question": "How should you overtake horse riders?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-overtake-horse-riders-4/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Drive up close and overtake as soon as possible", "Use your horn just once to warn them", "Speed isn't important but allow plenty of room", "Drive slowly and leave plenty of room"], "answer": "Drive slowly and leave plenty of room"},
{"id": "47587", "question": "How should you load your trailer?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-load-your-trailer/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Put heavy items in the corners", "Put heavy items at the front", "Put heavy items at the back", "Put heavy items over the axle(s)"], "answer": "Put heavy items over the axle(s)"},
{"id": "44326", "question": "How should you give an arm signal to turn left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-give-an-arm-signal-to-turn-left-4/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1237b.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1237a.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1237c.gif'>", "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1237d.gif'>"], "answer": "<img src='https://theorytest.org.uk/theory-images-2018/BB1237c.gif'>"},
{"id": "44415", "question": "How should you drive when you’re driving along a road that has road humps?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1558.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-drive-when-youre-driving-along-a-road-that-has-road-humps/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Always keep to the maximum legal speed", "Drive slowly at school times only", "Maintain a reduced speed throughout", "Accelerate quickly between the humps"], "answer": "Maintain a reduced speed throughout"},
{"id": "44098", "question": "How should you drive in areas with traffic-calming measures?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/AB2723.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-drive-in-areas-with-traffic-calming-measures-3/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["In the centre of the road", "With headlights on dipped beam", "At a reduced speed", "At the speed limit"], "answer": "At a reduced speed"},
{"id": "44055", "question": "How should you dispose of a used vehicle battery?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-you-dispose-of-a-used-vehicle-battery-3/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["Bury it in your garden", "Take it to a local-authority disposal site", "Leave it on waste land", "Put it in the dustbin"], "answer": "Take it to a local-authority disposal site"},
{"id": "43991", "question": "How should the right-hand lane of a three-lane motorway be used?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-the-right-hand-lane-of-a-three-lane-motorway-be-used-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["As a right-turn lane", "As a high-speed lane", "As an overtaking lane", "As an acceleration lane"], "answer": "As an overtaking lane"},
{"id": "44514", "question": "How should a load be carried on your roof rack?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-should-a-load-be-carried-on-your-roof-rack-2/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["Securely fastened with suitable restraints", "Loaded towards the rear of the vehicle", "Visible in your exterior mirror", "Covered with plastic sheeting"], "answer": "Securely fastened with suitable restraints"},
{"id": "44351", "question": "How much more fuel will you use by driving at 70 mph, compared with driving at 50 mph?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-much-more-fuel-will-you-use-by-driving-at-70-mph-compared-with-driving-at-50-mph/", "category": "Safety and your vehicle", "options": ["About 15%", "About 75%", "About 5%", "About 100%"], "answer": "About 15%"},
{"id": "43658", "question": "How much can stopping distances increase in icy conditions?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-much-can-stopping-distances-increase-in-icy-conditions/", "category": "Safety margins", "options": ["Three times", "Ten times", "Two times", "Five times"], "answer": "Ten times"},
{"id": "44321", "question": "How far are you allowed to reverse?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-far-are-you-allowed-to-reverse/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["As far as it takes to reverse around a corner", "No more than a car's length", "No further than is necessary", "The length of a residential street"], "answer": "No further than is necessary"},
{"id": "44386", "question": "How does drinking alcohol affect your driving behaviour?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-does-drinking-alcohol-affect-your-driving-behaviour/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["It improves judgement skills", "It increases confidence", "It leads to faster reactions", "It increases concentration"], "answer": "It increases confidence"},
{"id": "44147", "question": "How do smart motorways prevent traffic bunching?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-do-smart-motorways-prevent-traffic-bunching/", "category": "Motorway rules", "options": ["By using advisory speed limits", "By using variable speed limits", "By using higher speed limits", "By using minimum speed limits"], "answer": "By using variable speed limits"},
{"id": "44371", "question": "How can you use your vehicle’s engine to control your speed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/how-can-you-use-your-vehicles-engine-to-control-your-speed-2/", "category": "Vehicle handling", "options": ["By changing to a higher gear", "By changing to a lower gear", "By selecting neutral", "By selecting reverse gear"], "answer": "By changing to a lower gear"},
{"id": "44185", "question": "Following a collision, a person has been injured. What would be a warning sign for shock?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/following-a-collision-a-person-has-been-injured-what-would-be-a-warning-sign-for-shock/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Slow pulse", "Warm dry skin", "Rapid shallow breathing", "Flushed complexion"], "answer": "Rapid shallow breathing"},
{"id": "44013", "question": "Do you need to plan rest stops when you’re planning a long journey?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/do-you-need-to-plan-rest-stops-when-youre-planning-a-long-journey/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["No, you'll be less tired if you get there as soon as possible", "Yes, you should plan to stop every half an hour", "Yes, regular stops help concentration", "No, only fuel stops will be needed"], "answer": "Yes, regular stops help concentration"},
{"id": "43971", "question": "At traffic lights, what does it mean when the amber light shows on its own?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-traffic-lights-what-does-it-mean-when-the-amber-light-shows-on-its-own-3/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Prepare to go", "Go if no pedestrians are crossing", "Stop at the stop line", "Go if the way is clear"], "answer": "Stop at the stop line"},
{"id": "44231", "question": "At night, what does it mean if you see a pedestrian wearing reflective clothing and carrying a bright red light?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-night-what-does-it-mean-if-you-see-a-pedestrian-wearing-reflective-clothing-and-carrying-a-bright-red-light/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["You're approaching an organised walk", "You're approaching roadworks", "You're approaching a traffic danger spot", "You're approaching a slow-moving vehicle"], "answer": "You're approaching an organised walk"},
{"id": "44217", "question": "At an incident, someone is unconscious and you want to help. What would be the first thing to check?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-someone-is-unconscious-and-you-want-to-help-what-would-be-the-first-thing-to-check/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Whether their vehicle is insured", "Whether they're comfortable", "Whether their airway is open", "Whether they have any allergies"], "answer": "Whether their airway is open"},
{"id": "44223", "question": "At an incident, someone is suffering from severe burns. How could you help them?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-someone-is-suffering-from-severe-burns-how-could-you-help-them/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Apply lotions to the injury", "Burst any blisters", "Remove anything sticking to the burns", "Douse the burns with clean, cool water"], "answer": "Douse the burns with clean, cool water"},
{"id": "44226", "question": "At an incident, it’s important to look after any casualties. What should you do with them when the area is safe?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-its-important-to-look-after-any-casualties-what-should-you-do-with-them-when-the-area-is-safe-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Ask them how it happened", "Give them something to eat", "Keep them where they are", "Move them away from the vehicles"], "answer": "Keep them where they are"},
{"id": "44221", "question": "At an incident, how could you help a small child who isn’t breathing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-how-could-you-help-a-small-child-who-isnt-breathing/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Talk to them confidently until an ambulance arrives", "Find their parents and explain what's happening", "Put them in the recovery position and slap their back", "Open their airway and begin CPR"], "answer": "Open their airway and begin CPR"},
{"id": "44236", "question": "At an incident, how could you help a casualty who has stopped breathing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-how-could-you-help-a-casualty-who-has-stopped-breathing/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Try to give them something to drink", "Keep their head tilted forwards as far as possible", "Follow the DR ABC code", "Raise their legs to help with circulation"], "answer": "Follow the DR ABC code"},
{"id": "44222", "question": "At an incident, a casualty isn’t breathing. What should you do while helping them to start breathing again?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-a-casualty-isnt-breathing-what-should-you-do-while-helping-them-to-start-breathing-again-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Shake them firmly", "Put their arms across their chest", "Roll them onto their side", "Open their airway"], "answer": "Open their airway"},
{"id": "44225", "question": "At an incident, a casualty is unconscious but breathing. When should you move them?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/at-an-incident-a-casualty-is-unconscious-but-breathing-when-should-you-move-them-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["When bystanders offer to help you", "When bystanders tell you to move them", "When there's a risk of further danger", "When an ambulance is on its way"], "answer": "When there's a risk of further danger"},
{"id": "44000", "question": "As you approach a pelican crossing, the lights change to green. What should you do if older people are still crossing?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/as-you-approach-a-pelican-crossing-the-lights-change-to-green-what-should-you-do-if-older-people-are-still-crossing/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["Wave them to cross as quickly as they can", "Flash your lights in case they haven't noticed you", "Wait patiently while they cross", "Rev your engine to make them hurry"], "answer": "Wait patiently while they cross"},
{"id": "44492", "question": "Are passengers allowed to ride in a caravan that’s being towed?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/are-passengers-allowed-to-ride-in-a-caravan-thats-being-towed-2/", "category": "Vehicle loading", "options": ["No, not at any time", "Only if a stabiliser is fitted", "Yes, if they're over 14", "Only if all the seats in the towing vehicle are full"], "answer": "No, not at any time"},
{"id": "44186", "question": "An injured person has been placed in the recovery position. They’re unconscious but breathing normally. What else should be done?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/an-injured-person-has-been-placed-in-the-recovery-position-theyre-unconscious-but-breathing-normally-what-else-should-be-done-3/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Place their arms by their side", "Check their airway remains open", "Give them a hot sweet drink", "Press firmly between their shoulders"], "answer": "Check their airway remains open"},
{"id": "44192", "question": "An injured motorcyclist is lying unconscious in the road. The traffic has stopped and there’s no further danger. What could you do to help?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/an-injured-motorcyclist-is-lying-unconscious-in-the-road-the-traffic-has-stopped-and-theres-no-further-danger-what-could-you-do-to-help/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Seek medical assistance", "Remove their safety helmet", "Remove their leather jacket", "Move the person off the road"], "answer": "Seek medical assistance"},
{"id": "44209", "question": "An adult casualty isn’t breathing. To maintain circulation, CPR should be given. What’s the correct depth to press down on their chest?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/an-adult-casualty-isnt-breathing-to-maintain-circulation-cpr-should-be-given-whats-the-correct-depth-to-press-down-on-their-chest/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["5 to 6 centimetres", "1 to 2 centimetres", "15 to 20 centimetres", "10 to 15 centimetres"], "answer": "5 to 6 centimetres"},
{"id": "44229", "question": "After a collision, someone is unconscious in their vehicle. When should you call the emergency services?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/after-a-collision-someone-is-unconscious-in-their-vehicle-when-should-you-call-the-emergency-services-4/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["After you've woken them up", "As soon as possible", "After checking for broken bones", "Only as a last resort"], "answer": "As soon as possible"},
{"id": "44312", "question": "A single carriageway road has this sign. What’s the maximum permitted speed for a car towing a trailer?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/BB1207.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-single-carriageway-road-has-this-sign-whats-the-maximum-permitted-speed-for-a-car-towing-a-trailer-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["60 mph", "40 mph", "30 mph", "50 mph"], "answer": "50 mph"},
{"id": "44207", "question": "A police officer asks to see your documents. You don’t have them with you. How many days do you have to produce them at a police station?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-police-officer-asks-to-see-your-documents-you-dont-have-them-with-you-how-many-days-do-you-have-to-produce-them-at-a-police-station/", "category": "Essential documents", "options": ["5 days", "7 days", "14 days", "21 days"], "answer": "7 days"},
{"id": "44128", "question": "A police car is following you. What should you do if the police officer flashes the headlights and points to the left?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-police-car-is-following-you-what-should-you-do-if-the-police-officer-flashes-the-headlights-and-points-to-the-left-2/", "category": "Road and traffic signs", "options": ["Move over to the left", "Turn left at the next junction", "Stop immediately", "Pull up on the left"], "answer": "Pull up on the left"},
{"id": "44034", "question": "A horse rider is in the left-hand lane approaching a roundabout. Where should you expect the rider to go?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-horse-rider-is-in-the-left-hand-lane-approaching-a-roundabout-where-should-you-expect-the-rider-to-go-3/", "category": "Vulnerable road users", "options": ["In any direction", "To the left", "To the right", "Straight ahead"], "answer": "In any direction"},
{"id": "44097", "question": "A driver’s behaviour has upset you. How can you get over this incident safely?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-drivers-behaviour-has-upset-you-how-can-you-get-over-this-incident-safely/", "category": "Hazard awareness", "options": ["Gesture to them with your hand", "Shout abusive language", "Stop and take a break", "Follow them, flashing your headlights"], "answer": "Stop and take a break"},
{"id": "44315", "question": "A cycle lane, marked by a solid white line, is in operation. What does this mean for car drivers?", "picture": "https://theorytest.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/BB1220.gif", "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-cycle-lane-marked-by-a-solid-white-line-is-in-operation-what-does-this-mean-for-car-drivers-2/", "category": "Rules of the road", "options": ["They may park in the lane", "They may drive in the lane at any time", "They may use the lane when necessary", "They mustn't drive along the lane"], "answer": "They mustn't drive along the lane"},
{"id": "44235", "question": "A collision has just happened. An injured person is lying in a busy road. What’s the first thing you should do?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-collision-has-just-happened-an-injured-person-is-lying-in-a-busy-road-whats-the-first-thing-you-should-do/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["Warn other traffic", "Make sure the injured person is kept warm", "Treat the person for shock", "Place them in the recovery position"], "answer": "Warn other traffic"},
{"id": "44184", "question": "A casualty isn’t breathing normally and needs CPR. At what rate should you press down and release on the centre of their chest?", "picture": null, "link": "https://theorytest.org.uk/a-casualty-isnt-breathing-normally-and-needs-cpr-at-what-rate-should-you-press-down-and-release-on-the-centre-of-their-chest/", "category": "Incidents, accidents and emergencies", "options": ["240 times per minute", "60 times per minute", "10 times per minute", "120 times per minute"], "answer": "120 times per minute"}
]